{"leaderboard":{"1024318491899199599":{"564667773779705856":{"correct":256,"incorrect":186}},"750111486919180308":{"756654284455542784":{"correct":54,"incorrect":38},"1159358523344437249":{"correct":62,"incorrect":34},"753372751070363760":{"correct":304,"incorrect":152},"756920746588111014":{"correct":55,"incorrect":17},"738900809810575390":{"correct":299,"incorrect":205},"1289789877076099102":{"correct":190,"incorrect":104},"598565783932633098":{"correct":36,"incorrect":12},"1218016447234572358":{"correct":1542,"incorrect":789},"1281379648789418025":{"correct":114,"incorrect":82},"655769451869765683":{"correct":130,"incorrect":151},"759121855759253574":{"correct":134,"incorrect":176},"908222284572008518":{"correct":3,"incorrect":4},"748599942821707818":{"correct":18,"incorrect":17},"1127990958580048052":{"correct":88,"incorrect":73},"945823042838351914":{"correct":13,"incorrect":22},"1157499161067917322":{"correct":0,"incorrect":1},"1261112054035648622":{"correct":50,"incorrect":61},"564667773779705856":{"correct":8,"incorrect":4},"1283292241812783107":{"correct":1,"incorrect":1},"724764983304650812":{"correct":21,"incorrect":28},"1089255337816760330":{"correct":9,"incorrect":7}},"1287237894720720917":{"738900809810575390":{"correct":6,"incorrect":12}},"1185469863972573184":{"1159358523344437249":{"correct":10,"incorrect":8}},"985627336370180116":{"712037176573034580":{"correct":342,"incorrect":243}}},"active":{"interactions":{"1290018120442052669":{"questionID":"LFIFTH005167","answers":["advenit"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *advenio* (to come to, reach, arrive at)?"},"1290018247093125151":{"questionID":"L1012757","answers":["accusavistis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *accuso* (to accuse, blame)?"},"1290029197594464286":{"questionID":"G001018","answers":["chance"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *fors fortis f.*."},"1290034684482555985":{"questionID":"I028784","answers":["conandis"],"genus":"inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural feminine gerundive** of *conor* (to attempt, try)?"},"1290034725276221543":{"questionID":"L1010893","answers":["occupavero"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *occupo* (to occupy, seize)?"},"1290034823829782549":{"questionID":"L1021299","answers":["aspexerit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *aspicio* (to look at, see)?"},"1290035726829748307":{"questionID":"I080765","answers":["afferendi"],"genus":"inflection","question":"What is the **vocative plural masculine gerundive** of *affero* (to bring to; to allege, assert)?"},"1290036880515137598":{"questionID":"I096719","answers":["vendendis"],"genus":"inflection","question":"What is the **dative plural masculine gerundive** of *vendo* (to sell)?"},"1290037335747989614":{"questionID":"I073150","answers":["decipiendis"],"genus":"inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural feminine gerundive** of *decipio* (to deceive, cheat)?"},"1290040713462939688":{"questionID":"D000198","answers":["cratis"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *grate* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1290041477623447603":{"questionID":"G002322","answers":["V3i"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the part of speech/Latin inflection category of the word *respicio respicere respexi respectum*.\n\nPlease use the following for your answer.\n**Adjective: 1st and 2nd Declension:** A12\n**Adjective: 3rd Declension:** A3\n**Adjective: Indeclinable:** AI\n**Adjective: Numeral:** AN\n**Adverb:** ADV\n**Conjunction:** CONJ\n**Noun: 1st Declension:** N1\n**Noun: 2nd Declension:** N2\n**Noun: 3rd Declension:** N3\n**Noun: 4th Declension:** N4\n**Noun: 5th Declension:** N5\n**Noun: Indeclinable:** NI\n**Preposition:** PREP\n**Pronoun:** PRO\n**Verb: 1st Conjugation:** V1\n**Verb: 2nd Conjugation:** V2\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -io:** V3i\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -o:** V3\n**Verb: 4th Conjugation:** V4\n**Verb: Deponent:** VD\n**Verb: Impersonal:** VIP\n**Verb: Irregular:** VIRR"},"1290044155426246811":{"questionID":"PW000055","answers":["431 BC"],"genus":"pw","question":"What year did the Peloponnesian War begin?"},"1290044529998565518":{"questionID":"PW000080","answers":["Devastating Athenian defeat"],"genus":"pw","question":"What was the outcome of the Athenian expedition to Sicily?"},"1290045102361677844_0":{"questionID":"PW000100","answers":["Defeat and dissolution of the alliance"],"genus":"pw","question":"What was the outcome of the Battle of Mantinea for the democratic alliance led by Argos?"},"1290045102361677844_1":{"questionID":"PW000033","answers":["Xenophon"],"genus":"pw","question":"What other Greek historian, who wrote the Hellenica, provided an account of the later years of the war and its aftermath?"},"1290045102361677844_2":{"questionID":"PW000041","answers":["Samos"],"genus":"pw","question":"What was the name of the island where the Athenian fleet was based after its revolt against the oligarchs in 411 BC?"},"1290045102361677844_3":{"questionID":"PW000121","answers":["404 BC"],"genus":"pw","question":"What year did the Second Peloponnesian War end?"},"1290045102361677844_4":{"questionID":"PW000012","answers":["Sparta"],"genus":"pw","question":"What city-state was Athens' main rival for power in Greece?"},"1290045102361677844_5":{"questionID":"PW000086","answers":["Dismantle walls, surrender fleet, and lose overseas possessions"],"genus":"pw","question":"What were the terms of Athens' surrender in 404 BC?"},"1290045102361677844_6":{"questionID":"PW000049","answers":["More brutal and less restrained warfare"],"genus":"pw","question":"What was the significance of the Peloponnesian War for the future of Greek warfare?"},"1290045102361677844_7":{"questionID":"PW000029","answers":["Long Walls"],"genus":"pw","question":"What were the fortifications called that connected Athens to its port of Piraeus?"},"1290045102361677844_8":{"questionID":"PW000101","answers":["Siege and subjugation of Melos"],"genus":"pw","question":"What event in 416 BC demonstrated Athenian aggression and alienated potential allies?"},"1290045102361677844_9":{"questionID":"PW000138","answers":["Alcibiades"],"genus":"pw","question":"Who persuaded the Athenians to launch the Sicilian Expedition?"},"1290045244057845791":{"questionID":"PW000063","answers":["Pericles"],"genus":"pw","question":"Who was the influential Athenian leader who advised a defensive strategy at the war's beginning?"},"1290046545235808287_0":{"questionID":"PW000132","answers":["The Battle of Amphipolis"],"genus":"pw","question":"Which battle resulted in the deaths of both Cleon and Brasidas?"},"1290046545235808287_2":{"questionID":"PW000015","answers":["Strong land army"],"genus":"pw","question":"What was Sparta's main military advantage?"},"1290046545235808287_3":{"questionID":"PW000008","answers":["Battle of Aegospotami"],"genus":"pw","question":"What was the name of the decisive naval battle where Sparta defeated Athens in 405 BC?"},"1290046545235808287_4":{"questionID":"PW000031","answers":["Thirty Tyrants"],"genus":"pw","question":"What group of Athenian citizens briefly held power after the war?"},"1290046545235808287_5":{"questionID":"PW000149","answers":["Thrasybulus"],"genus":"pw","question":"What Athenian leader helped restore democracy to Athens in 403 BC?"},"1290046545235808287_6":{"questionID":"PW000111","answers":["Cut off Athenian grain supply"],"genus":"pw","question":"Why did Lysander sail to the Dardanelles?"},"1290046545235808287_7":{"questionID":"PW000137","answers":["Syracuse"],"genus":"pw","question":"What main city in Sicily attacked an Athenian ally, prompting the Sicilian Expedition?"},"1290046545235808287_8":{"questionID":"PW000003","answers":["Plague"],"genus":"pw","question":"What event in 430 BC significantly weakened the Athenian military?"},"1290046545235808287_9":{"questionID":"PW000096","answers":["Speech honoring Athenian soldiers and values"],"genus":"pw","question":"What was Pericles' Funeral Oration?"},"1290046776165924956":{"questionID":"PW000002","answers":["Archidamus II"],"genus":"pw","question":"What was the name of the Spartan king who initially led invasions of Attica?"},"1290050011568275537":{"questionID":"A000557","answers":["sharp, keen... oxys (οξυς)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **peroxide**?"},"1290050042866176081":{"questionID":"PW000055","answers":["431 BC"],"genus":"pw","question":"What year did the Peloponnesian War begin?"},"1290056814049755199":{"questionID":"F002285","answers":["EURYSTHEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who terrified by the sight of the Nemean Lion hid in a bronze jar?"},"1290056838938755133":{"questionID":"F000261","answers":["QUAIL ISLAND"],"genus":"myth","question":"What does Ortygia mean?"},"1290056850573627566":{"questionID":"F001516","answers":["HIS DAUGHTER MEGARA AS WIFE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What prize did Creon, regent of Thebes, give to Heracles for helping the city?"},"1290058705173352500":{"questionID":"F001883","answers":["TIPHYS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Which helmsman of the Argo died during the visit to the Mariandyni?"},"1290077229476479027":{"questionID":"P000183","answers":["PERFECTION"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Ne plus ultra*?"},"1290077336812781599":{"questionID":"T001188","answers":["A MONASTERY WITHOUT BOOKS IS LIKE A CITY WITHOUT WEALTH"],"genus":"translation","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Monasterium sine libris est sicut civitas sine opibus*?"},"1290078380896555020":{"questionID":"P000173","answers":["IN ABSENCE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *In absentia*?"},"1290078941272604763":{"questionID":"H000056","answers":["BRENNUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What Sennonian chieftain reportedly said vae victis to the Romans when they complained of weighted scales?"},"1290079015046090753":{"questionID":"H000733","answers":["PERPERNA"],"genus":"history","question":"What subordinate of Sertorius assassinated him?"},"1290079522934231113":{"questionID":"P000075","answers":["FLUCTUAT NEC MERGITUR (\"IT IS TOSSED BY THE WAVES BUT DOES NOT SINK\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Paris*?"},"1290080855183851612":{"questionID":"H001246","answers":["IN HOC SIGNO VINCES"],"genus":"history","question":"What words did Constantine reportedly see in a cross before the battle of Milvian Bridge?"},"1290083328157814897":{"questionID":"A000417","answers":["to rule, control... krateo (κρατεω)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **bureaucracy**?"},"1290097021918642258":{"questionID":"H001298","answers":["RAVENNA"],"genus":"history","question":"Where did Honorius flee to when Alaric sacked Rome?"},"1290098052954067024":{"questionID":"H001272","answers":["378 AD"],"genus":"history","question":"In what year was Valens captured by the Goths at Adrianople?"},"1290116397241864263":{"questionID":"L1004765","answers":["albis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter ablative plural** of *albus* (white)?"},"1290116434080432258":{"questionID":"L1013577","answers":["paruerit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *pareo* (to appear; to obey)?"},"1290116633687232602":{"questionID":"L1018499","answers":["deduxistis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *deduco* (to lead away)?"},"1290117622909767680":{"questionID":"L1020325","answers":["recipiam"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future active indicative** of *recipio* (to take back; to receive)?"},"1290117889751515239":{"questionID":"L1009495","answers":["abes"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active imperative** of *absum* (to be away, to be absent)?"},"1290117904745889853":{"questionID":"L1000664","answers":["materias"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *materia, materiae* (wood, material)?"},"1290530544618045508":{"questionID":"LFIFTH003542","answers":["superamus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *supero* (to go over, exceed, remain)?"},"1290530582836809740":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004387","answers":["appellaverunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *appello* (to call, implore)?"},"1290530643511607317":{"questionID":"LFIFTH005262","answers":["revertistis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *reverto* (to come back, turn back, return)?"},"1290718853566828624":{"questionID":"LFIFTH000175","answers":["pugna"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *pugna, pugnae* (battle)?"},"1290718812588478474":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002730","answers":["omni"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine/feminine ablative singular** of *omnis* (all, every)?"},"1290718976258867293":{"questionID":"G002981","answers":["utor uti usus sum"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find all 4 principal parts of the verb that matches the definition *use, consume, employ (+ abl.)*. Do not include macrons."},"1290719140864196752":{"questionID":"LFIFTH003736","answers":["potant"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *poto* (to drink)?"},"1290729770019197008":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004656","answers":["pares"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *pareo* (to appear; to obey)?"},"1290730115767996458":{"questionID":"LFIFTH006578","answers":["agnoscis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *agnosco* (to recognize; to admit)?"},"1290730862035603569":{"questionID":"A000226","answers":["ge (γη), earth"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **geomorphic**?"},"1290758652902506569":{"questionID":"A000657","answers":["stretch out, strain... teino (τεινω)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **intonation**?"},"1290758681922764852":{"questionID":"A000460","answers":["logos (λογος), word, speech, reasoning"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **dialogue**?"},"1290759721053196298":{"questionID":"A000547","answers":["name... οnoma (ονομα)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **synonym**?"},"1290761412792287356":{"questionID":"A000534","answers":["one and the same, like"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What does the Greek word **homos (ὁμος)** mean?"},"1290786562618949733":{"questionID":"A000480","answers":["misos (μισος), hatred"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **misoneism**?"},"1290786542725627935":{"questionID":"A000171","answers":["throw... ballo (βαλλω)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **parole**?"},"1290786580398870528":{"questionID":"A000105","answers":["to lead, rule, be the first, begin... archo (αρχω)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **patriarch**?"},"1290814769850482769":{"questionID":"LFIFTH000064","answers":["sagitta"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *sagitta, sagittae* (arrow)?"},"1290814740280381450":{"questionID":"LFIFTH003571","answers":["speravistis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *spero* (to hope)?"},"1290831150553501726":{"questionID":"LFIFTH006798","answers":["percepisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *percipio* (to occupy; to perceive, observe)?"},"1290848406314680453":{"questionID":"LFIFTH001952","answers":["duri"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter genitive singular** of *durus* (hard)?"},"1290889609047314433":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002887","answers":["te"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *tu* (you, yourself)?"},"1290890481810804748":{"questionID":"LFIFTH000445","answers":["bellum"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative singular** of *bellum, belli* (war)?"},"1290891132556939337":{"questionID":"LFIFTH003713","answers":["praestatis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *praesto* (to stand before, surpass, warrant)?"},"1290891172012621926":{"questionID":"LFIFTH000088","answers":["experientia"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *experientia, experientiae* (experience)?"},"1291087784425164841":{"questionID":"LFIFTH006988","answers":["conspexi"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *conspicio* (to observe, to gaze upon)?"},"1291119243080896573":{"questionID":"A000205","answers":["word, speech, reasoning... logos (λογος)","race, offspring, kind... genos (γενος)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **genealogy**?"},"1291167071824121906":{"questionID":"LFIFTH000874","answers":["senectutes"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *senectus, senectutis* (old age)?"},"1291167523470839848":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002890","answers":["nobis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *nos* (we, us, ourselves; emph. I, me, myself)?"},"1291168631295574016":{"questionID":"LFIFTH005607","answers":["occidistis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *occido* (to kill)?"},"1291170257523708025":{"questionID":"LFIFTH000436","answers":["simulacrum"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative singular** of *simulacrum, simulacri* (image, portrait, phantom)?"},"1291184730842333185":{"questionID":"A000020","answers":["demos (δημος), the people","ago (αγω), to lead, bring"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **demagogue**?"},"1291189724081557524":{"questionID":"A000619","answers":["flesh... sarx (σαρξ)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **sarcasm**?"},"1291209330598744175":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004210","answers":["desperamus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *despero* (to despair of, to give up)?"},"1291209818647957515":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004814","answers":["intuent"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *intueor* (to look at, regard)?"},"1291209918543691838":{"questionID":"LFIFTH005237","answers":["ruisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *ruo* (to fall down; to cast down, prostrate)?"},"1291210712567513098":{"questionID":"LFIFTH000767","answers":["corpora"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *corpus, corporis* (body)?"},"1291210811884437514":{"questionID":"LFIFTH003299","answers":["tulisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *fero* (to bear, carry, bring)?"},"1291254424332795945":{"questionID":"H000721","answers":["LIVIUS DRUSUS THE YOUNGER"],"genus":"history","question":"What tribune of 91 BC was killed for trying to promote citizenship for the Latin allies?"},"1291258218043146290":{"questionID":"PW000107","answers":["ATHENIAN VICTORY AND PARTIAL RECOVERY"],"genus":"pw","question":"What was the significance of the Battle of Cyzicus?"},"1291263000854003812":{"questionID":"G001129","answers":["winter"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *hiems hiemis f.*."},"1291263367968854016":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002672","answers":["humiles"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine/feminine nominative plural** of *humilis* (small, humble)?"},"1291265530992267314":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002441","answers":["saeva"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter nominative plural** of *saevus* (furious, ferocious)?"},"1291267466978394142":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002823","answers":["celebris"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive singular** of *celeber* (crowded, renowned)?"},"1291268434176512112":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004753","answers":["meruistis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *mereo* (to deserve, merit, serve in the army)?"},"1291268463838629908":{"questionID":"LFIFTH006938","answers":["deiecerunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *deicio* (to throw or cast down)?"},"1291268688548204567":{"questionID":"LFIFTH003319","answers":["eunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *eo* (to go)?"},"1291269145685659691":{"questionID":"LFIFTH006803","answers":["patis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *patior* (to bear, suffer, endure, allow)?"},"1291269511688749056":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004810","answers":["intues"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *intueor* (to look at, regard)?"},"1291270141132406856":{"questionID":"L1013508","answers":["placuerint"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *placeo* (to please)?"},"1291270997294452746":{"questionID":"L1003911","answers":["auribus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative plural** of *auris, auris* (ear)?"},"1291271011504754748":{"questionID":"L1012455","answers":["clamaverat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *clamo* (to call, cry out, declare)?"},"1291271273380315236":{"questionID":"L1018361","answers":["deserueratis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *desero* (to leave, abandon)?"},"1291271281584640080":{"questionID":"L1020593","answers":["perceperatis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *percipio* (to occupy; to perceive, observe)?"},"1291271294415015957":{"questionID":"L1002146","answers":["barbarorum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural** of *barbarus, barbari* (barbarian)?"},"1291271533964038285":{"questionID":"L1000014","answers":["puellarum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural** of *puella, puellae* (girl)?"},"1291271546337235076":{"questionID":"L1008117","answers":["ipsius"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter genitive singular** of *ipse* (in person, himself, herself, itself)?"},"1291271627283370075":{"questionID":"L1008269","answers":["quacumque"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine ablative singular** of *quicumque* (whoever, whatever)?"},"1291272158391173120":{"questionID":"L1015668","answers":["rebunt"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future active indicative** of *reor* (to believe, think, imagine)?"},"1291272429985071128":{"questionID":"L1015293","answers":["sprevit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *sperno* (to despise, reject, spurn)?"},"1291272657593040918":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004867","answers":["fovetis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *foveo* (to keep warm; to caress, love)?"},"1291272795258490980":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002854","answers":["equestri"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter ablative singular** of *equester* (equestrian)?"},"1291273148339327037":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002538","answers":["adulescentis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive singular** of *adulescens* (young)?"},"1291274479732920372":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004637","answers":["placetis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *placeo* (to please)?"},"1291274772512116746":{"questionID":"L1017176","answers":["instrues"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future active indicative** of *instruo* (to set in order, equip; to teach, instruct)?"},"1291274913184874551":{"questionID":"LFIFTH006648","answers":["accedunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *accedo* (to go near to, approach; to agree with)?"},"1291275453398650892":{"questionID":"L1008466","answers":["transtuleris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *transfero* (to bear across, transport, transfer)?"},"1291275491751366750":{"questionID":"L1010551","answers":["postulabo"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future active indicative** of *postulo* (to ask, demand, summon)?"},"1291275552509923389":{"questionID":"L1015571","answers":["restitueratis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *restituo* (to give back, restore)?"},"1291275580364554260":{"questionID":"L1005393","answers":["commodi"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine genitive singular** of *commodus* (proper, suitable)?"},"1291275600358801428":{"questionID":"L1020770","answers":["inceperas"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *incipio* (to begin)?"},"1291276285259153420":{"questionID":"L1002699","answers":["tempore"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *tempus, temporis* (period of time)?"},"1291276352716144710":{"questionID":"L1017319","answers":["imponam"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future active indicative** of *impono* (to lay upon, impose)?"},"1291276460719476827":{"questionID":"L1010549","answers":["postulabatis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *postulo* (to ask, demand, summon)?"},"1291276511122296874":{"questionID":"L1004107","answers":["amnes"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *amnis, amnis* (stream, river)?"},"1291276704534233108":{"questionID":"L1016277","answers":["persequet"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future active indicative** of *persequor* (to follow, to pursue)?"},"1291276724373295155":{"questionID":"L1000236","answers":["littera"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **vocative singular** of *littera, litterae* (letter)?"},"1291276751262978119":{"questionID":"L1020038","answers":["accideris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *accido* (to fall upon; to happen)?"},"1291276762667417600":{"questionID":"L1017172","answers":["instruebamus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *instruo* (to set in order, equip; to teach, instruct)?"},"1291276836252160092":{"questionID":"L1014344","answers":["exercueras"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *exerceo* (to exercise, occupy, employ)?"},"1291276853184696381":{"questionID":"L1017901","answers":["erige"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active imperative** of *erigo* (to rise up, erect, build)?"},"1291276985825366068":{"questionID":"L1021062","answers":["deficiebant"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *deficio* (to withdraw, desert; to cease, disappear)?"},"1291277305402101760":{"questionID":"L1017589","answers":["floram"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future active indicative** of *floreo* (to bloom, blossom; to be prosperous)?"},"1291277394115690508":{"questionID":"L1020113","answers":["accesseritis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *accedo* (to go near to, approach; to agree with)?"},"1291277532842426432":{"questionID":"L1005051","answers":["asperorum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine genitive plural** of *asper* (rough, harsh)?"},"1291277750287597652":{"questionID":"P000205","answers":["ALL THE WAY UP TO"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Usque ad*?"},"1291278106492928052":{"questionID":"L1012049","answers":["dederitis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *do* (to give)?"},"1291278130123898932":{"questionID":"L1008275","answers":["quarumcumque"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive plural** of *quicumque* (whoever, whatever)?"},"1291278293668204596":{"questionID":"L1006801","answers":["pulchris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine ablative plural** of *pulcher* (beautiful, handsome)?"},"1291278303889457202":{"questionID":"L1010913","answers":["obstabit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future active indicative** of *obsto* (to stand against, oppose)?"},"1291278313339355158":{"questionID":"L1018030","answers":["edidimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *edo* (to bring forth, beget, publish)?"},"1291278363465482250":{"questionID":"L1004487","answers":["dierum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural** of *dies, diei* (day)?"},"1291278371745038406":{"questionID":"L1011190","answers":["moramus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *moror* (to delay, linger, hinder)?"},"1291278484441665641":{"questionID":"L1018397","answers":["descenderatis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *descendo* (to come down, descend)?"},"1291278869701070859":{"questionID":"L1010174","answers":["rogabis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future active indicative** of *rogo* (to ask, interrogate)?"},"1291278883223765063":{"questionID":"L1009936","answers":["steteramus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *sto* (to stand)?"},"1291278978619015219":{"questionID":"L1003979","answers":["manibus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative plural** of *manes, manium* (ghosts of the departed)?"},"1291278987816996924":{"questionID":"L1008750","answers":["praetuleramus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *praefero* (to bear before, prefer, display)?"},"1291279117907398748":{"questionID":"L1014765","answers":["vendet"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future active indicative** of *vendo* (to sell)?"},"1291279132428210276":{"questionID":"L1001387","answers":["tumule"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **vocative singular** of *tumulus, tumuli* (mound, hill)?"},"1291279197175550023":{"questionID":"L1003946","answers":["aestatum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural** of *aestas, aestatis* (summer)?"},"1291284951328751646":{"questionID":"A000203","answers":["race, offspring, kind... genos (γενος)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **cyanogen**?"},"1291397091893055560":{"questionID":"L1006209","answers":["iustum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine accusative singular** of *iustus* (lawful, right)?"},"1291397143940038718":{"questionID":"L1010036","answers":["simulavisti"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *simulo* (to imitate)?"},"1291397422676709489":{"questionID":"L1014458","answers":["docueris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *doceo* (to teach)?"},"1291397516780376144":{"questionID":"L1004996","answers":["aptis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter dative plural** of *aptus* (suitable)?"},"1291397536765972490":{"questionID":"L1002457","answers":["vasorum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural** of *vas, vasis* (vase)?"},"1291397836788727981":{"questionID":"L1001835","answers":["iuvenco"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *iuvencus, iuvenci* (young bullock)?"},"1291397924869247027":{"questionID":"L1011790","answers":["expectaveramus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *expecto* (to expect, to be waiting for)?"},"1291397936151793765":{"questionID":"L1003965","answers":["aequoribus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative plural** of *aequor, aequoris* (surface of the sea, sea)?"},"1291397946180370577":{"questionID":"L1018789","answers":["contempseram"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *contemno* (to despise, not to fear)?"},"1291398020323217499":{"questionID":"L1011791","answers":["expectaveratis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *expecto* (to expect, to be waiting for)?"},"1291398030200799305":{"questionID":"L1004698","answers":["aegris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine dative plural** of *aeger* (ill, troubled)?"},"1291398045946216489":{"questionID":"L1006204","answers":["iustae"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive singular** of *iustus* (lawful, right)?"},"1291398113801801800":{"questionID":"L1008275","answers":["quarumcumque"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive plural** of *quicumque* (whoever, whatever)?"},"1291398204507816028":{"questionID":"L1021863","answers":["evenit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *evenio* (to happen)?"},"1291398255183401080":{"questionID":"L1010398","answers":["probavimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *probo* (to test, approve)?"},"1291398701293506661":{"questionID":"L1019839","answers":["agam"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future active indicative** of *ago* (to lead, to drive, to do)?"},"1291398715244019753":{"questionID":"L1009267","answers":["detuleram"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *defero* (to bear or bring away; to report)?"},"1291398723317927988":{"questionID":"L1012822","answers":["videbimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future active indicative** of *video* (to see)?"},"1291398775729950770":{"questionID":"L1019254","answers":["coepit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *coepi* (to begin)?"},"1291398794805641306":{"questionID":"L1015011","answers":["sustulerat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *tollo* (to rise up, elevate, exhalt)?"},"1291398803836112918":{"questionID":"L1009789","answers":["vacaveram"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *vaco* (to be empty, vacant, free, idle)?"},"1291398809506676838":{"questionID":"L1010040","answers":["simulaverunt"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *simulo* (to imitate)?"},"1291398954336129074":{"questionID":"L1017593","answers":["floretis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future active indicative** of *floreo* (to bloom, blossom; to be prosperous)?"},"1291398964653985792":{"questionID":"L1006004","answers":["ignotum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter vocative singular** of *ignotus* (unknown)?"},"1291399109663785001":{"questionID":"L1001061","answers":["agno"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *agnus, agni* (lamb)?"},"1291399179184111698":{"questionID":"L1001875","answers":["initia"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *initium, initii* (beginning)?"},"1291399230577184902":{"questionID":"L1011468","answers":["iuraverant"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *iuro* (to swear, take an oath)?"},"1291399241994080377":{"questionID":"L1015070","answers":["tenebis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future active indicative** of *teneo* (to hold, keep, possess)?"},"1291399419853275196":{"questionID":"L1013246","answers":["riseras"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *rideo* (to laugh)?"},"1291399428300607539":{"questionID":"L1007583","answers":["omnium"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter genitive plural** of *omnis* (all, every)?"},"1291399436244881452":{"questionID":"L1012408","answers":["cogitabimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future active indicative** of *cogito* (to think, meditate, plan)?"},"1291399523549315174":{"questionID":"L1011109","answers":["negavero"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *nego* (to say no, to deny)?"},"1291399673193431040":{"questionID":"L1012755","answers":["accusavit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *accuso* (to accuse, blame)?"},"1291399694165213235":{"questionID":"L1018097","answers":["dividetis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future active indicative** of *divido* (to divide)?"},"1291399776947929119":{"questionID":"L1001570","answers":["proeliorum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural** of *proelium, proelii* (battle)?"},"1291399826973659229":{"questionID":"L1010805","answers":["optabit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future active indicative** of *opto* (to choose, to wish)?"},"1291399914638803025":{"questionID":"L1000548","answers":["potentiis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *potentia, potentiae* (power)?"},"1291399931860484096":{"questionID":"L1021480","answers":["sepeliverimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *sepelio* (to bury)?"},"1291399943487098910":{"questionID":"L1005235","answers":["caecis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine dative plural** of *caecus* (blind)?"},"1291399952509177907":{"questionID":"L1000308","answers":["pecunia"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **vocative singular** of *pecunia, pecuniae* (money, wealth)?"},"1291399960746524796":{"questionID":"L1014163","answers":["horrueram"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *horreo* (to be frightened at)?"},"1291399969114161185":{"questionID":"L1015419","answers":["scripsit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *scribo* (to write)?"},"1291399981747408960":{"questionID":"L1013428","answers":["praebueramus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *praebeo* (to give, offer)?"},"1291399987875414106":{"questionID":"L1010051","answers":["simulaveritis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *simulo* (to imitate)?"},"1291399994401882144":{"questionID":"L1018941","answers":["coniunget"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future active indicative** of *coniungo* (to join)?"},"1291400007747895370":{"questionID":"L1018043","answers":["edideritis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *edo* (to bring forth, beget, publish)?"},"1291400021492891689":{"questionID":"L1017934","answers":["emerimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *emo* (to buy)?"},"1291400114186752001":{"questionID":"L1000878","answers":["copiae"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *copia, copiae* (abundance)?"},"1291400132729896960":{"questionID":"L1021437","answers":["serviverat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *servio* (to be a servant or slave, to serve)?"},"1291400173528023143":{"questionID":"L1009783","answers":["vacavi"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *vaco* (to be empty, vacant, free, idle)?"},"1291400195384283268":{"questionID":"L1013218","answers":["sederimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *sedeo* (to sit)?"},"1291400207359279194":{"questionID":"L1017662","answers":["finges"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future active indicative** of *fingo* (to form, make, shape)?"},"1291400229039378473":{"questionID":"L1014900","answers":["tribuerunt"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *tribuo* (to assign, grant)?"},"1291400267631165521":{"questionID":"L1006472","answers":["nimiis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter ablative plural** of *nimius* (excessive)?"},"1291400282596573244":{"questionID":"L1002008","answers":["famule"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **vocative singular** of *famulus, famuli* (servant)?"},"1291400288250368051":{"questionID":"L1010535","answers":["potaverit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *poto* (to drink)?"},"1291400386007269491":{"questionID":"L1005427","answers":["contentae"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine dative singular** of *contentus* (tense, intent; satisfied)?"},"1291400395280879636":{"questionID":"L1013598","answers":["obtinebunt"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future active indicative** of *obtineo* (to hold, occupy, possess)?"},"1291400405992996947":{"questionID":"L1017703","answers":["favi"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *faveo* (to be favorable or inclined towards)?"},"1291400425744109689":{"questionID":"L1022010","answers":["compererunt"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *comperio* (to find out, ascertain)?"},"1291400442537971804":{"questionID":"L1021036","answers":["deiecimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *deicio* (to throw or cast down)?"},"1291400450880442398":{"questionID":"L1012100","answers":["desperaveris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *despero* (to despair of, to give up)?"},"1291400469742223452":{"questionID":"L1012645","answers":["appellavi"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *appello* (to call, implore)?"},"1291400480802738187":{"questionID":"L1016966","answers":["legisti"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *lego* (to gather, collect; to read)?"},"1291400636516143114":{"questionID":"L1021330","answers":["acceperamus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *accipio* (to receive)?"},"1291400669194092635":{"questionID":"L1011717","answers":["habitaverat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *habito* (to inhabit, dwell)?"},"1291400707551006741":{"questionID":"L1004504","answers":["speciei"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *species, speciei* (appearance)?"},"1291400863440699483":{"questionID":"L1005118","answers":["avidas"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine accusative plural** of *avidus* (eager, greedy)?"},"1291400917144436751":{"questionID":"L1003278","answers":["praetores"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *praetor, praetoris* (praetor, commander)?"},"1291401013768622163":{"questionID":"L1015934","answers":["quaesiveris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *quaero* (to seek, ask, inquire, desire)?"},"1291401027102441534":{"questionID":"L1016529","answers":["pepercerit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *parco* (to spare, have mercy upon)?"},"1291401035771940927":{"questionID":"L1007287","answers":["dulce"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter vocative singular** of *dulcis* (sweet, charming)?"},"1291401045381087293":{"questionID":"L1019158","answers":["colligemus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future active indicative** of *colligo* (to gather, draw or bring together)?"},"1291401110199865355":{"questionID":"L1002960","answers":["civitates"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *civitas, civitatis* (citizenship, state)?"},"1291401311345971280":{"questionID":"L1000887","answers":["comae"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *coma, comae* (hair)?"},"1291401319935901737":{"questionID":"L1006940","answers":["superba"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter nominative plural** of *superbus* (proud, arrogant)?"},"1291401331139149856":{"questionID":"L1008335","answers":["utrorum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine genitive plural** of *uter* (which of two?)?"},"1291401612241403954":{"questionID":"L1006554","answers":["novis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine dative plural** of *novus* (new)?"},"1291401620982206464":{"questionID":"L1018888","answers":["consuescemus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future active indicative** of *consuesco* (to be accustomed)?"},"1291401630557667449":{"questionID":"L1000737","answers":["horis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *hora, horae* (hour)?"},"1291401649771778160":{"questionID":"L1009041","answers":["inibit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future active indicative** of *ineo* (to go into, enter)?"},"1291406563294187622":{"questionID":"L1020342","answers":["receperant"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *recipio* (to take back; to receive)?"},"1291406929196875817":{"questionID":"L1002485","answers":["plebibus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative plural** of *plebs, plebis* (common people, the plebeians)?"},"1291406942782230672":{"questionID":"L1001869","answers":["iocos"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *iocus, ioci* (joke)?"},"1291406964630224906":{"questionID":"L1016852","answers":["metueris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *metuo* (to fear, to be afraid of)?"},"1291406990047711317":{"questionID":"L1008804","answers":["perferebatis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *perfero* (to bear through, endure to the end)?"},"1291407062839984179":{"questionID":"L1005326","answers":["certis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter dative plural** of *certus* (determined, settled)?"},"1291407100441919498":{"questionID":"L1009656","answers":["vitabunt"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future active indicative** of *vito* (to avoid)?"},"1291407319099379723":{"questionID":"L1006913","answers":["summorum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter genitive plural** of *summus* (highest, topmost)?"},"1291407439652061214":{"questionID":"L1002311","answers":["regiones"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *regio, regionis* (region)?"},"1291407452008353955":{"questionID":"L1001961","answers":["freto"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *fretum, freti* (strait, sea)?"},"1291407519524065375":{"questionID":"L1000151","answers":["victorias"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *victoria, victoriae* (victory)?"},"1291407633613455392":{"questionID":"L1016372","answers":["perdidisti"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *perdo* (to destroy, ruin; to lose)?"},"1291407645890183219":{"questionID":"L1012478","answers":["circumdabis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future active indicative** of *circumdo* (to surround, enclose)?"},"1291407665452290070":{"questionID":"L1000612","answers":["naturae"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *natura, naturae* (nature)?"},"1291407672012308694":{"questionID":"L1018176","answers":["discesserunt"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *discedo* (to go away from, to leave)?"},"1291407735190982737":{"questionID":"L1018504","answers":["deduxeramus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *deduco* (to lead away)?"},"1291407802446778493":{"questionID":"L1005807","answers":["firmos"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine accusative plural** of *firmus* (firm, strong)?"},"1291407815575076866":{"questionID":"L1007781","answers":["alacris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive singular** of *alacer* (brisk, eager, active)?"},"1291407821291913228":{"questionID":"L1019696","answers":["averteris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *averto* (to turn away from, to divert)?"},"1291407840904351815":{"questionID":"L1020211","answers":["suffeceram"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *sufficio* (to be sufficient)?"},"1291407877784731728":{"questionID":"L1015866","answers":["quiescent"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future active indicative** of *quiesco* (to rest, keep quiet)?"},"1291407905903476899":{"questionID":"L1002583","answers":["religionum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural** of *religio, religionis* (religion)?"},"1291407913411280907":{"questionID":"L1021847","answers":["evenitis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *evenio* (to happen)?"},"1291407922936545351":{"questionID":"L1002005","answers":["fatis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *fatum, fati* (fate)?"},"1291407930587091006":{"questionID":"L1013961","answers":["latuit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *lateo* (to be hidden, concealed, safe)?"},"1291407980830658615":{"questionID":"L1004686","answers":["aegra"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine vocative singular** of *aeger* (ill, troubled)?"},"1291407989202223285":{"questionID":"L1013399","answers":["prohibueritis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *prohibeo* (to forbid, prohibit)?"},"1291408021796421756":{"questionID":"L1007920","answers":["silvestrium"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter genitive plural** of *silvester* (belonging to a forest, woody)?"},"1291408031225090098":{"questionID":"L1017116","answers":["intenderas"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *intendo* (to bend, aim, stretch)?"},"1291408113504882708":{"questionID":"L1017335","answers":["imposueratis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *impono* (to lay upon, impose)?"},"1291408122828554301":{"questionID":"L1005432","answers":["contente"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine vocative singular** of *contentus* (tense, intent; satisfied)?"},"1291408176754856017":{"questionID":"L1009086","answers":["tulerunt"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *fero* (to bear, carry, bring)?"},"1291408187739869307":{"questionID":"L1001698","answers":["nuntia"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *nuntium, nuntii* (message)?"},"1291408281801068584":{"questionID":"L1000134","answers":["provinciis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *provincia, provinciae* (province)?"},"1291408289338228746":{"questionID":"L1011092","answers":["negabis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future active indicative** of *nego* (to say no, to deny)?"},"1291408298402381946":{"questionID":"L1003721","answers":["discrimini"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *discrimen, discriminis* (interval, difference; turning-point)?"},"1291408499108085760":{"questionID":"L1006599","answers":["pium"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine accusative singular** of *pius* (dutiful, pious, honest)?"},"1291408633225285776":{"questionID":"L1019400","answers":["cesserunt"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *cedo* (to move; to happen, result)?"},"1291408697565778003":{"questionID":"L1000756","answers":["formae"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *forma, formae* (form, figure, beauty)?"},"1291408704624660522":{"questionID":"L1008035","answers":["istius"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive singular** of *iste* (that)?"},"1291408710765117561":{"questionID":"L1002143","answers":["barbare"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **vocative singular** of *barbarus, barbari* (barbarian)?"},"1291408716570165352":{"questionID":"L1014662","answers":["vixisti"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *vivo* (to live)?"},"1291408723583172628":{"questionID":"L1000626","answers":["morarum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural** of *mora, morae* (delay)?"},"1291408728813473804":{"questionID":"L1017500","answers":["frues"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future active indicative** of *fruor* (to use, enjoy)?"},"1291408782676463616":{"questionID":"L1018948","answers":["coniunximus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *coniungo* (to join)?"},"1291408797553787004":{"questionID":"L1009622","answers":["vocavisti"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *voco* (to call, summon, invoke)?"},"1291408809553821696":{"questionID":"L1016622","answers":["omittent"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future active indicative** of *omitto* (to dismiss, neglect)?"},"1291408818693210165":{"questionID":"L1009795","answers":["vacavero"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *vaco* (to be empty, vacant, free, idle)?"},"1291408827396390933":{"questionID":"L1016813","answers":["miseratis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *mitto* (to send, throw)?"},"1291408844152635455":{"questionID":"L1016785","answers":["nasce"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active imperative** of *nascor* (to be born)?"},"1291408975711047804":{"questionID":"L1010426","answers":["precabis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future active indicative** of *precor* (to pray, request)?"},"1291408986649923695":{"questionID":"L1004297","answers":["genua"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *genu, genus* (knee)?"},"1291408993884966943":{"questionID":"L1010039","answers":["simulavistis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *simulo* (to imitate)?"},"1291409001677983917":{"questionID":"L1010805","answers":["optabit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future active indicative** of *opto* (to choose, to wish)?"},"1291409021395533856":{"questionID":"L1008104","answers":["earundem"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive plural** of *idem* (the same)?"},"1291409027603103744":{"questionID":"L1016658","answers":["occident"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future active indicative** of *occido* (to kill)?"},"1291409035932864512":{"questionID":"L1015563","answers":["restituit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *restituo* (to give back, restore)?"},"1291409043134349356":{"questionID":"L1000763","answers":["formas"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *forma, formae* (form, figure, beauty)?"},"1291409056010997780":{"questionID":"L1002776","answers":["imperatoribus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *imperator, imperatoris* (commander, emperor)?"},"1291409063330185319":{"questionID":"L1020524","answers":["perfeceris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *perficio* (to achieve, complete, accomplish)?"},"1291409072117252158":{"questionID":"L1014168","answers":["horruerant"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *horreo* (to be frightened at)?"},"1291409078995652651":{"questionID":"L1003039","answers":["vulnus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **vocative singular** of *vulnus, vulneris* (wound)?"},"1291409087032201226":{"questionID":"L1020484","answers":["perveneramus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *pervenio* (to arrive at, reach)?"},"1291409093386436620":{"questionID":"L1006243","answers":["laeta"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine vocative singular** of *laetus* (joyful)?"},"1291409099090694144":{"questionID":"L1019332","answers":["cinxeramus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *cingo* (to surround, encircle)?"},"1291409107428835398":{"questionID":"L1008597","answers":["redivi"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *redeo* (to go or come back)?"},"1291409116589461545":{"questionID":"L1021174","answers":["corripiemus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future active indicative** of *corripio* (to seize, snatch; to blame)?"},"1291409123111604254":{"questionID":"L1021706","answers":["muniveras"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *munio* (to fortify, defend)?"},"1291409129507782657":{"questionID":"L1006237","answers":["laetae"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine dative singular** of *laetus* (joyful)?"},"1291409136751476828":{"questionID":"L1017972","answers":["elegerint"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *eligo* (to choose, elect)?"},"1291409148214513776":{"questionID":"L1005590","answers":["divina"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter nominative plural** of *divinus* (divine)?"},"1291409157773197446":{"questionID":"L1019340","answers":["cinxerint"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *cingo* (to surround, encircle)?"},"1291409240250122250":{"questionID":"L1007867","answers":["salubribus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine ablative plural** of *saluber* (salutary, beneficial)?"},"1291409251138539531":{"questionID":"L1005482","answers":["crebris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter ablative plural** of *creber* (frequent, abounding in)?"},"1291409258100949023":{"questionID":"L1004505","answers":["speciem"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative singular** of *species, speciei* (appearance)?"},"1291409326233354262":{"questionID":"L1006797","answers":["pulchros"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine accusative plural** of *pulcher* (beautiful, handsome)?"},"1291409336102551683":{"questionID":"L1005709","answers":["extremae"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine nominative plural** of *extremus* (extreme, latest)?"},"1291409343832527009":{"questionID":"L1001403","answers":["telo"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *telum, teli* (dart, spear)?"},"1291409351348588565":{"questionID":"L1000968","answers":["tenebrae"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *tenebrae, tenebrarum* (darkness)?"},"1291409358885879951":{"questionID":"L1011575","answers":["indicaveratis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *indico* (to point out, indicate)?"},"1291409366829891718":{"questionID":"L1018423","answers":["deposui"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *depono* (to put down)?"},"1291409381644177408":{"questionID":"L1000997","answers":["deliciis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *deliciae, deliciarum* (delight, pleasure; beloved)?"},"1291409390150226111":{"questionID":"L1021246","answers":["capiemus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future active indicative** of *capio* (to take, seize, grasp)?"},"1291409417312538645":{"questionID":"L1013995","answers":["iussi"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *iubeo* (to command, order)?"},"1291409442776289301":{"questionID":"L1014358","answers":["egemus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *egeo* (to need, lack)?"},"1291409631297409125":{"questionID":"A000033","answers":["to lead, bring... ago (αγω)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **synagogue**?"},"1291411717665980426":{"questionID":"L1016383","answers":["perdidero"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *perdo* (to destroy, ruin; to lose)?"},"1291411735689039882":{"questionID":"L1016473","answers":["pascam"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future active indicative** of *pasco* (to pasture, feed, nourish)?"},"1291412170713731105":{"questionID":"L1018156","answers":["discedimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *discedo* (to go away from, to leave)?"},"1291412183590113405":{"questionID":"L1020216","answers":["suffecerant"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *sufficio* (to be sufficient)?"},"1291412196223352872":{"questionID":"L1008634","answers":["profuisti"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *prosum* (to be useful or of use, to benefit)?"},"1291428141520261211":{"questionID":"LADV105592","answers":["percussi estis"],"genus":"LADV_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect passive indicative** of *percutio* (to strike; to kill)?"},"1291446414349697105":{"questionID":"LFIFTH006560","answers":["alunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *alo* (to feed, nourish)?"},"1291446666150547517":{"questionID":"LFIFTH003027","answers":["quocumque"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine ablative singular** of *quicumque* (whoever, whatever)?"},"1291456728516526173":{"questionID":"A000483","answers":["monos (μονος)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What Greek word means **alone**?"},"1291456747621318686":{"questionID":"A000378","answers":["idein (ιδειν), to see"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **ideal**?"},"1291456765824864379":{"questionID":"A000197","answers":["wedding, marriage... gamos (γαμος)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **polygamy**?"},"1291511945089908736":{"questionID":"A000168","answers":["ballo (βαλλω), throw"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **parlor**?"},"1291520316216053780":{"questionID":"LFIFTH000476","answers":["studio"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *studium, studii* (desire, study)?"},"1291520671230328862":{"questionID":"LFIFTH005073","answers":["trahit"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *traho* (to draw, drag)?"},"1291528690500374639":{"questionID":"F001036","answers":["IDOMENEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What king of Crete came voluntarily rather as Agamemnon's bound ally?"},"1291528728803020810":{"questionID":"F000137","answers":["TRITON (DIFFERENT FROM CONCH MAN)"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who raised Athena shortly after her birth, according to some accounts?"},"1291528834172059710":{"questionID":"F001760","answers":["CHALCIOPE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What daughter of Aeetes married Phrixus?"},"1291528649610231868":{"questionID":"F002085","answers":["PUT LOG IN FIRE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What did Althaea upon learning Melaager killed her brothers?"},"1291528787871141928":{"questionID":"F000431","answers":["STOLE APOLLO'S CATTLE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What did Hermes accomplish the evening after his birth?"},"1291530322067849297":{"questionID":"F000264","answers":["NIOBE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What mother boasted that she was more deserving of honor than Leto?"},"1291529516543508651":{"questionID":"F001913","answers":["ALCINOUS AND ARETE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What Phaeacian king and queen agreed to protect Medea from the Colchians if she marry Jason?"},"1291529453188550747":{"questionID":"F001178","answers":["ACHILLES"],"genus":"myth","question":"To whom does Odysseus tell of the Trojan Horse in the underworld?"},"1291543258387845150":{"questionID":"F000512","answers":["ORION"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who does Odysseus see driving beasts through the fields of Asphodel?"},"1291543281070772254":{"questionID":"F000976","answers":["CASSANDRA"],"genus":"myth","question":"What daughter of Priam received the gift of prophecy from Apollo?"},"1291543225676333076":{"questionID":"F002061","answers":["TROPHONIUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the brother of Agamedes?"},"1291543606892695644":{"questionID":"F000304","answers":["SIRIUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the dog of Orion?"},"1291543690007023626":{"questionID":"F000124","answers":["PHEIDIAS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What sculptor and architect designed the Parthenon?"},"1291544860255322173":{"questionID":"LFIFTH003924","answers":["narravi"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *narro* (to tell, narrate)?"},"1291554037128495145":{"questionID":"LFIFTH001219","answers":["fulmen"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative singular** of *fulmen, fulminis* (lightning)?"},"1291554061493080104":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004756","answers":["manet"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *maneo* (to stay, remain)?"},"1291554182486032395":{"questionID":"F001432","answers":["MEGAPENTHES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who exchanged kingdoms with Perseus?"},"1291554254523207690":{"questionID":"F000458","answers":["P. OVIDIUS NASO"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who wrote the Metamorphoses?"},"1291554341844680714":{"questionID":"F000803","answers":["PISA"],"genus":"myth","question":"Where did the chariot race with Oenomaus begin?"},"1291554356910493776":{"questionID":"F001660","answers":["SYLEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What robber forced strangers to work in his vineyard?"},"1291554377580154901":{"questionID":"F001278","answers":["POSEIDON"],"genus":"myth","question":"What father of Polyphemus cursed Odysseus?"},"1291554399629475972":{"questionID":"F001907","answers":["PINDAR"],"genus":"myth","question":"What Greek poet wrote Odes, such as the Pythian Odes, to athletic champions?"},"1291554412443205675":{"questionID":"F001661","answers":["BY STRAITS OF EUBOEA"],"genus":"myth","question":"Where did Syleus live?"},"1291554459670941716":{"questionID":"F000187","answers":["CYPRUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What had the first prostitutes, as a result of a curse from Aphrodite?"},"1291554475894636584":{"questionID":"F001973","answers":["LAPITHS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Of what tribe was Pirithous the chieftain?"},"1291554775384457246":{"questionID":"F000508","answers":["ACHILLES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who said that he would rather be a slave on earth than king of dead souls?"},"1291554794519138354":{"questionID":"F000548","answers":["OTUS AND EPHIALTES"],"genus":"myth","question":"What twin giants tried to storm Olympus?"},"1291554808310009950":{"questionID":"F001225","answers":["NEREUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who told Menelaus how to return home safely?"},"1291554919261667408":{"questionID":"F002036","answers":["NELEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who demanded that Bias steal the cattle of Phylacus?"},"1291554934898299006":{"questionID":"F000616","answers":["AGENOR"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Cadmus?"},"1291555019413258311":{"questionID":"F000633","answers":["ARES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Harmonia?"},"1291555114271903794":{"questionID":"F000319","answers":["PHAEDRA"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who leaves a suicide note for Theseus, falsely incriminating Hippolytus?"},"1291555143669514241":{"questionID":"F001580","answers":["LAKE STYMPHALUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"To what lake in Arcadia did Heracles journey for his 6th labor?"},"1291555205833297951":{"questionID":"L1001888","answers":["ingeniis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *ingenium, ingenii* (temperament, talent)?"},"1291555233893449738":{"questionID":"L1011141","answers":["narraverat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *narro* (to tell, narrate)?"},"1291555322665893949":{"questionID":"L1008988","answers":["maluerit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *malo* (to prefer)?"},"1291555331205365861":{"questionID":"L1021425","answers":["serviet"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future active indicative** of *servio* (to be a servant or slave, to serve)?"},"1291555338742403082":{"questionID":"L1021218","answers":["conspexerunt"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *conspicio* (to observe, to gaze upon)?"},"1291558435539783732":{"questionID":"F000490","answers":["DIONYSUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What god was sometimes called Iacchus?"},"1291558469111119964":{"questionID":"F002132","answers":["TO KILL BELLEROPHON"],"genus":"myth","question":"What secret instructions to Iobates accompanied Bellerophon?"},"1291558494780129320":{"questionID":"G002813","answers":["velut"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find all 1 principal parts of the adverb that matches the definition *even as, just as*. Do not include macrons."},"1291559123321622558":{"questionID":"F002232","answers":["SEMIRAMIS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the queen of Babylon during Pyramus and Thisbe's lives?"},"1291559442399367288":{"questionID":"F000455","answers":["415 BC"],"genus":"myth","question":"In what year was Alcibiades charged with defiling Herms?"},"1291559670766506085":{"questionID":"F000816","answers":["ATREUS AND THYESTES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who were the sons of Pelops, called the Pelopidae?"},"1291559825062367324":{"questionID":"F002166","answers":["DELPHI"],"genus":"myth","question":"Where did Aepytus learn that Iamus would be the greatest of seers?"},"1291559856389488746":{"questionID":"F002046","answers":["STHENEBOEA"],"genus":"myth","question":"What wife of Proetus is prominent in the myth of Bellerophon?"},"1291559971221405748":{"questionID":"F001772","answers":["JASON"],"genus":"myth","question":"Whose mother is variously named as Polymede, Alcimede or Amphinome?"},"1291560185562792057":{"questionID":"F000703","answers":["COLONUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Where was Sophocles born?"},"1291560263119540234":{"questionID":"F002184","answers":["CYDIPPE"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who picked up an apple that read \"I swear to marry only Acontius\"?"},"1291560380354789438":{"questionID":"F001621","answers":["RAINED STONES"],"genus":"myth","question":"How did Zeus help Heracles when he ran out of arrows against the Ligurians?"},"1291560528375840820":{"questionID":"F001993","answers":["ASTYDAMIA"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the wife of Acastus?"},"1291560938453073960":{"questionID":"F000583","answers":["VERGIL"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who does Dante describe as his guide in the underworld?"},"1291562015550341290":{"questionID":"F002178","answers":["ESCAPE AGAMEMNON"],"genus":"myth","question":"Why did Dionysus turn Anius' daughters into white doves?"},"1291562308992241664":{"questionID":"F000276","answers":["STAG"],"genus":"myth","question":"Into what type of animal was Actaeon transformed?"},"1291562565603692625":{"questionID":"F001760","answers":["CHALCIOPE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What daughter of Aeetes married Phrixus?"},"1291562571299815435":{"questionID":"F000967","answers":["HELENUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Which of Priam's sons had the gift of prophecy?"},"1291562758847856681":{"questionID":"F000280","answers":["CADMUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Autonoe?"},"1291562885494870038":{"questionID":"F000058","answers":["NEREUS AND DORIS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who were the parents of the Nereid Galatea?"},"1291564424158777354":{"questionID":"F000766","answers":["FURIES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who pursued Alcmaeon after he killed his mother?"},"1291564451862155346":{"questionID":"F002234","answers":["TOMB OF NINUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Where did Pyramus and Thisbe plan to meet?"},"1291565117271445524":{"questionID":"F001490","answers":["IPHICLES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the son of Iolaus?"},"1291565195725901894":{"questionID":"F000305","answers":["THE DOG STAR"],"genus":"myth","question":"What did the dog of Orion become?"},"1291565736413761648":{"questionID":"F000046","answers":["CYRUS THE GREAT"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the king of Persia when Croesus attacked?"},"1291566632392593411":{"questionID":"F002166","answers":["DELPHI"],"genus":"myth","question":"Where did Aepytus learn that Iamus would be the greatest of seers?"},"1291566844305735702":{"questionID":"F001709","answers":["CEYX"],"genus":"myth","question":"With what king of Trachis did Deianira live while Heracles served Omphale?"},"1291567920002105354":{"questionID":"F001179","answers":["NEOPTOLEMUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who does Odysseus say was the one fellow warrior not afraid in the horse?"},"1291568167164055594":{"questionID":"F000626","answers":["ARES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of the serpent which guarded a spring Cadmus used?"},"1291568280242491443":{"questionID":"F002071","answers":["DEIANIRA"],"genus":"myth","question":"What daughter of Oeneus married Heracles?"},"1291571330721910874":{"questionID":"L1011368","answers":["laceras"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *lacero* (to tear to pieces, to lacerate)?"},"1291571397923045438":{"questionID":"L1010168","answers":["rogabas"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *rogo* (to ask, interrogate)?"},"1291571511894741012":{"questionID":"F000797","answers":["DEMETER"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who ate the shoulder of Pelops?"},"1291571524742025337":{"questionID":"F000015","answers":["DRYADS (OR HAMADRYADS)"],"genus":"myth","question":"What name was given to the nymphs of trees?"},"1291571533772226712":{"questionID":"F001179","answers":["NEOPTOLEMUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who does Odysseus say was the one fellow warrior not afraid in the horse?"},"1291571553477328949":{"questionID":"F000744","answers":["ZEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who hurled a thunderbolt to knock Capaneus from the walls of Thebes?"},"1291571633928146977":{"questionID":"F002097","answers":["MADE LOVE IN SACRED PLACE"],"genus":"myth","question":"Why were Atalanta and Melanion transformed into lions?"},"1291571645882040330":{"questionID":"F001102","answers":["TELEPHUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Whom did Achilles wound during an invasion of Mysia?"},"1291579874544193547":{"questionID":"A000285","answers":["to give... didomi (διδωμι)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **overdose**?"},"1291590131592990773":{"questionID":"D000195","answers":["costa"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *cutlet* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1291590434312945826":{"questionID":"H000548","answers":["MARCELLUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Who won the Spolia Opima by defeating Viridomarus in single combat at Clastidium in 222 BC?"},"1291590599165874187":{"questionID":"H000462","answers":["ELEPHANTS"],"genus":"history","question":"What military innovation was Pyrrhus the first to use against the Romans?"},"1291590653695758426":{"questionID":"T002160","answers":["FASTER THAN ASPARAGUS CAN BE COOKED"],"genus":"translation","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *velocius quam asparagi coquantur*?"},"1291590843458785280":{"questionID":"T001640","answers":["FOR SCIENCE AND NATION"],"genus":"translation","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *pro scientia et patria*?"},"1291591812967960688":{"questionID":"LFIFTH005859","answers":["frangis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *frango* (to break)?"},"1291591976784756766":{"questionID":"LFIFTH003116","answers":["transivi"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *transeo* (to go over or across)?"},"1291592156414349343":{"questionID":"P000110","answers":["(DECESSIT SINE PROLE) DEAD WITHOUT ISSUE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *d.s.p.*?"},"1291592332520456192":{"questionID":"L1012143","answers":["damnat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *damno* (to condemn)?"},"1291592438607253514":{"questionID":"LFIFTH006853","answers":["incepit"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *incipio* (to begin)?"},"1291592454369443893":{"questionID":"L1009448","answers":["adiveras"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *adeo* (to go to, approach)?"},"1291592462669709365":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004367","answers":["armavisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *armo* (to arm, equip)?"},"1291592473591808094":{"questionID":"LFIFTH007097","answers":["reperiunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *reperio* (to find)?"},"1291592476146143354":{"questionID":"L1018592","answers":["currebas"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *curro* (to run)?"},"1291592690995171369":{"questionID":"L1006749","answers":["publicum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine accusative singular** of *publicus* (public)?"},"1291592716148408442":{"questionID":"L1011791","answers":["expectaveratis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *expecto* (to expect, to be waiting for)?"},"1291592945459400804":{"questionID":"L1020059","answers":["accendetis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future active indicative** of *accendo* (to kindle, set on fire; to incite)?"},"1291592967798263840":{"questionID":"L1018106","answers":["diviseras"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *divido* (to divide)?"},"1291593211143520337":{"questionID":"L1017742","answers":["fefellimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *fallo* (to deceive, cheat, disappoint)?"},"1291593558083506268":{"questionID":"L1010470","answers":["praedicamus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *praedico* (to proclaim, declare)?"},"1291593578941775954":{"questionID":"L1012412","answers":["cogitavisti"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *cogito* (to think, meditate, plan)?"},"1291601325724930080":{"questionID":"A000537","answers":["one and the same, like... homos (ὁμος)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **anomalous**?"},"1291620017842032752":{"questionID":"L1005501","answers":["cunctorum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine genitive plural** of *cunctus* (all together, the whole)?"},"1291620039144898560":{"questionID":"L1014981","answers":["tradiderit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *trado* (to deliver, betray, report)?"},"1291620106652090419":{"questionID":"L1016547","answers":["ostendet"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future active indicative** of *ostendo* (to show, exhibit, display)?"},"1291620344397959178":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004324","answers":["clamavit"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *clamo* (to call, cry out, declare)?"},"1291620544499683339":{"questionID":"L1016314","answers":["permiserimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *permitto* (to allow, suffer, permit)?"},"1291620615081558039":{"questionID":"L1012813","answers":["videbam"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *video* (to see)?"},"1291620770354696243":{"questionID":"LFIFTH006391","answers":["coepi"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *coepi* (to begin)?"},"1291621083002306630":{"questionID":"LFIFTH005412","answers":["processisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *procedo* (to go forth, advance)?"},"1291621134764216392":{"questionID":"LFIFTH006027","answers":["ducitis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *duco* (to lead, conduct)?"},"1291621382861488138":{"questionID":"LFIFTH005882","answers":["florit"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *floreo* (to bloom, blossom; to be prosperous)?"},"1291621408732086283":{"questionID":"LFIFTH005042","answers":["veximus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *veho* (to bear, carry)?"},"1291621431066755072":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004545","answers":["siluerunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *sileo* (to keep silent, to be quiet)?"},"1291621797275500596":{"questionID":"LFIFTH001819","answers":["certae"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive singular** of *certus* (determined, settled)?"},"1291621935905767455":{"questionID":"LFIFTH003859","answers":["obstitisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *obsto* (to stand against, oppose)?"},"1291621972463190048":{"questionID":"LFIFTH006410","answers":["cingimus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *cingo* (to surround, encircle)?"},"1291622010375508060":{"questionID":"LFIFTH006161","answers":["deduxi"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *deduco* (to lead away)?"},"1291623565551992873":{"questionID":"LFIFTH007141","answers":["muniverunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *munio* (to fortify, defend)?"},"1291623697483825213":{"questionID":"LFIFTH005216","answers":["sequit"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *sequor* (to follow)?"},"1291623903495589959":{"questionID":"LFIFTH003535","answers":["temptavisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *tempto* (to handle, touch; to attempt)?"},"1291623915889758278":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004485","answers":["timuerunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *timeo* (to be afraid of)?"},"1291624427489984532":{"questionID":"LFIFTH005794","answers":["incessisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *incedo* (to go, step, march along)?"},"1291624764183674891":{"questionID":"LFIFTH006819","answers":["peperi"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *pario* (to bring forth, bear, produce)?"},"1291624782038831144":{"questionID":"LFIFTH005241","answers":["ruerunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *ruo* (to fall down; to cast down, prostrate)?"},"1291624798748672000":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002702","answers":["mitis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine/feminine genitive singular** of *mitis* (mild, gentle)?"},"1291624806592020534":{"questionID":"LFIFTH005157","answers":["surreximus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *surgo* (to rise, arise, get up, stand up)?"},"1291624813869273135":{"questionID":"LFIFTH003946","answers":["miras"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *miror* (to wonder, to be amazed, to admire)?"},"1291624842633805894":{"questionID":"LFIFTH003057","answers":["utram"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine accusative singular** of *uter* (which of two?)?"},"1291624856718409789":{"questionID":"LFIFTH003416","answers":["absumus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *absum* (to be away, to be absent)?"},"1291631708533424149":{"questionID":"G001143","answers":["N1"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the part of speech/Latin inflection category of the word *hora horae f.*.\n\nPlease use the following for your answer.\n**Adjective: 1st and 2nd Declension:** A12\n**Adjective: 3rd Declension:** A3\n**Adjective: Indeclinable:** AI\n**Adjective: Numeral:** AN\n**Adverb:** ADV\n**Conjunction:** CONJ\n**Noun: 1st Declension:** N1\n**Noun: 2nd Declension:** N2\n**Noun: 3rd Declension:** N3\n**Noun: 4th Declension:** N4\n**Noun: 5th Declension:** N5\n**Noun: Indeclinable:** NI\n**Preposition:** PREP\n**Pronoun:** PRO\n**Verb: 1st Conjugation:** V1\n**Verb: 2nd Conjugation:** V2\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -io:** V3i\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -o:** V3\n**Verb: 4th Conjugation:** V4\n**Verb: Deponent:** VD\n**Verb: Impersonal:** VIP\n**Verb: Irregular:** VIRR"},"1291632894703308821":{"questionID":"LFIFTH001470","answers":["fluctu"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *fluctus, fluctus* (wave)?"},"1291633782020902934":{"questionID":"LFIFTH005021","answers":["vertistis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *verto* (to turn, transform, translate)?"},"1291636025268895777":{"questionID":"LFIFTH000107","answers":["amicae"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *amica, amicae* (friend, lover)?"},"1291636097738080377":{"questionID":"LFIFTH000960","answers":["uxores"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *uxor, uxoris* (wife)?"},"1291639738427641948":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004939","answers":["debent"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *debeo* (to owe; to be bound)?"},"1291767046907887721":{"questionID":"LFIFTH006751","answers":["praecipitis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *praecipio* (to advise, instruct, teach)?"},"1291770764512464956":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002158","answers":["invitam"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine accusative singular** of *invitus* (unwilling)?"},"1291771878276464691":{"questionID":"LFIFTH006006","answers":["educunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *educo* (to lead forth, bring away)?"},"1291918867353960478":{"questionID":"LFIFTH005343","answers":["reddidimus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *reddo* (to give back)?"},"1291962870795604048":{"questionID":"G002704","answers":["back, rear","a tergo: from the rear"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *tergum tergi n.*."},"1291964135948550308":{"questionID":"G000462","answers":["V3"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the part of speech/Latin inflection category of the word *cogo cogere coegi coactum*.\n\nPlease use the following for your answer.\n**Adjective: 1st and 2nd Declension:** A12\n**Adjective: 3rd Declension:** A3\n**Adjective: Indeclinable:** AI\n**Adjective: Numeral:** AN\n**Adverb:** ADV\n**Conjunction:** CONJ\n**Noun: 1st Declension:** N1\n**Noun: 2nd Declension:** N2\n**Noun: 3rd Declension:** N3\n**Noun: 4th Declension:** N4\n**Noun: 5th Declension:** N5\n**Noun: Indeclinable:** NI\n**Preposition:** PREP\n**Pronoun:** PRO\n**Verb: 1st Conjugation:** V1\n**Verb: 2nd Conjugation:** V2\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -io:** V3i\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -o:** V3\n**Verb: 4th Conjugation:** V4\n**Verb: Deponent:** VD\n**Verb: Impersonal:** VIP\n**Verb: Irregular:** VIRR"},"1291964546768048171":{"questionID":"P000162","answers":["JUSTIFICATION FOR WAR"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Casus Belli*?"},"1291964579844456448":{"questionID":"P000024","answers":["CIVIUM IN MORIBUS REI PUBLIAE SALUS. (\"IN THE CHARACTER OF ITS CITIZENS LIES THE WELFARE OF THE STATE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Univ. Florida*?"},"1291966738887606312":{"questionID":"LFIFTH001736","answers":["avidi"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter genitive singular** of *avidus* (eager, greedy)?"},"1291966750711222344":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004274","answers":["conas"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *conor* (to attempt, try)?"},"1291968776387952680":{"questionID":"LFIFTH003503","answers":["venerat"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *veneror* (to worship, venerate)?"},"1291969110028324945":{"questionID":"L1004531","answers":["luxuriis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative plural** of *luxuria, luxuriae* (licentiousness, luxury, extravagance)?"},"1291969119700254720":{"questionID":"L1000205","answers":["scientias"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *scientia, scientiae* (knowledge)?"},"1291969385623191594":{"questionID":"LFIFTH003023","answers":["cuiuscumque"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter genitive singular** of *quicumque* (whoever, whatever)?"},"1291969720693555221":{"questionID":"L1000878","answers":["copiae"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *copia, copiae* (abundance)?"},"1291970957656850493":{"questionID":"P000215","answers":["CAESAR"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Veni, vidi, vici**?"},"1291970984512847932":{"questionID":"P000039","answers":["LUX SIT. (\"LET THERE BE LIGHT.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Washington*?"},"1291970993866149921":{"questionID":"P000032","answers":["LUX HOMINUM VITA. (\"LIGHT OF THE LIFE OF MEN.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of New Mexico*?"},"1291971278596472842":{"questionID":"P000000","answers":["TERRAS IRRADIENT. (\"LET THEM ILLUMINATE THE EARTH.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Amherst College*?"},"1291971770915622952":{"questionID":"P000134","answers":["(SENATUS CONSULTUM ULTIMUM) FINAL DECREE OF THE SENATE (MARITAL LAW)"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *S.C.U.*?"},"1291971786426028064":{"questionID":"P000146","answers":["SPEAK ONLY GOOD OF THE DEAD"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *De mortuis nil nisi bonum*?"},"1291971797910163546":{"questionID":"P000147","answers":["YOU HIT THE NAIL ON THE HEAD"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *rem acu tetigisti*?"},"1291971806235988049":{"questionID":"P000125","answers":["(MODUS OPERANDI) WAY OF OPERATING"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *m.o.*?"},"1291971818604855436":{"questionID":"P000078","answers":["PER ARDUA AD ASTRA (\"THROUGH STRUGGLE TO THE STARS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *The Royal Air Force*?"},"1291972269765033994":{"questionID":"P000247","answers":["OVID"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Rident stolidi verba Latina**?"},"1291972284344569981":{"questionID":"P000235","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **parturient montes, nasceture ridiculus mus**?"},"1291972294457163776":{"questionID":"P000022","answers":["NON SIBI, SED SUIS. (\"NOT FOR HERSELF, BUT FOR HER OWN.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Tulane University*?"},"1291972507875807293":{"questionID":"P000087","answers":["HIC IACET SEPULTUS (\"HERE LIES BURIED\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *H.J.S.*?"},"1291972520702119986":{"questionID":"P000247","answers":["OVID"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Rident stolidi verba Latina**?"},"1291972531900649515":{"questionID":"P000216","answers":["I CAME, I SAW, I CONQUERED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Veni, vidi, vici**."},"1291972544798134355":{"questionID":"P000207","answers":["WOE TO THE CONQUERED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *vae victis*?"},"1291973364839350336":{"questionID":"L1016493","answers":["paverit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *pasco* (to pasture, feed, nourish)?"},"1291973495844241429":{"questionID":"P000037","answers":["ECCE QUAM BONAM (\"BEHOLD HOW GOOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of the South (Sewanee)*?"},"1291973544716009482":{"questionID":"P000194","answers":["PROBABLE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Similis veri*?"},"1291973561015336960":{"questionID":"P000027","answers":["ET DOCERE ET RERUM EXQUIRERE CAUSAS (\"BOTH TO TEACH & TO INQUIRE INTO THE CAUSES OF THINGS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Georgia*?"},"1291973725461418034":{"questionID":"P000036","answers":["DISCIPLINA PRAESIDIUM CIVITATIS (\"INSTRUCTION IS THE SAFEGUARD OF THE STATE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Texas*?"},"1291974085374640138":{"questionID":"P000218","answers":["CAESAR"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Alea iacta est**?"},"1291974446260817930":{"questionID":"L1010376","answers":["properaverint"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *propero* (to hasten)?"},"1291974459619807252":{"questionID":"L1016915","answers":["lusistis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *ludo* (to play; to ridicule)?"},"1291974556914814976":{"questionID":"L1013665","answers":["nubebo"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future active indicative** of *nubo* (to marry)?"},"1291974650921746495":{"questionID":"L1010766","answers":["ornabant"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *orno* (to adorn, to equipe)?"},"1291974660426170499":{"questionID":"L1014059","answers":["intuebatis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *intueor* (to look at, regard)?"},"1291974669188206603":{"questionID":"L1021064","answers":["deficies"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future active indicative** of *deficio* (to withdraw, desert; to cease, disappear)?"},"1291975943807569951":{"questionID":"L1006978","answers":["suis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine ablative plural** of *suus* (his, her, its, their)?"},"1291980059669823520":{"questionID":"LFIFTH001760","answers":["benigni"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter genitive singular** of *benignus* (kind, friendly, favorable)?"},"1291980403485184082":{"questionID":"LFIFTH001818","answers":["certi"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine genitive singular** of *certus* (determined, settled)?"},"1291982768321986581":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002953","answers":["eodem"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter ablative singular** of *idem* (the same)?"},"1291983212976799795":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002117","answers":["immensa"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter nominative plural** of *immensus* (boundless, immense)?"},"1291983227950465077":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002489","answers":["sua"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter nominative plural** of *suus* (his, her, its, their)?"},"1291983974440239164":{"questionID":"P000224","answers":["IN THIS SIGN YOU WILL CONQUER"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **In hoc signo vinces**."},"1291984249716473856":{"questionID":"P000030","answers":["SALUS POPULI. (\"THE WELFARE OF THE PEOPLE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Missouri*?"},"1291984309535768586":{"questionID":"P000004","answers":["DEUS LUX MEA (\"GOD IS MY LIGHT\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Catholic University of America*?"},"1291984465610145892":{"questionID":"P000211","answers":["AUGUSTUS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Festina lente**?"},"1291984511470538752":{"questionID":"P000033","answers":["CIVI ET REI PUBLICAE (\"FOR THE CITIZEN AND THE STATE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Oklahoma*?"},"1291984682782818315":{"questionID":"P000232","answers":["ALAS, THE FLEETING YEARS GLIDE BY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Eheu fugaces labuntur anni**."},"1292004341783334942":{"questionID":"F001189","answers":["ASTYANAX"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who is the son of Hector?"},"1292007483639988346":{"questionID":"F001104","answers":["TELEPHUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was healed by scrapings from Achilles spear?"},"1292008071962431528":{"questionID":"F000954","answers":["ILUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Laomedon?"},"1292008402536501310":{"questionID":"F001683","answers":["OENEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Deianira?"},"1292009614401077268":{"questionID":"F002205","answers":["TELETHUSA"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the mother of Iphis and wife of Ligdus?"},"1292121204634685491":{"questionID":"LFIFTH007056","answers":["servivit"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *servio* (to be a servant or slave, to serve)?"},"1292122326317531257":{"questionID":"L1003847","answers":["clientium"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural** of *cliens, clientis* (client; follower)?"},"1292123178394583061":{"questionID":"L1004246","answers":["partus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **vocative singular** of *partus, partus* (bearing, birth)?"},"1292123387937820782":{"questionID":"L1011454","answers":["iurabimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future active indicative** of *iuro* (to swear, take an oath)?"},"1292124058632192122":{"questionID":"L1000131","answers":["provinciarum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural** of *provincia, provinciae* (province)?"},"1292124066626404453":{"questionID":"L1004982","answers":["apte"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine vocative singular** of *aptus* (suitable)?"},"1292124144460103815":{"questionID":"L1019947","answers":["adducam"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future active indicative** of *adduco* (to lead, to bring to)?"},"1292125114368000103":{"questionID":"L1000518","answers":["reginarum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural** of *regina, reginae* (queen)?"},"1292125783451631627":{"questionID":"L1020833","answers":["fugietis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future active indicative** of *fugio* (to flee, to run away)?"},"1292125809829482516":{"questionID":"L1004826","answers":["valido"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine dative singular** of *validus* (strong, powerful)?"},"1292125820990783540":{"questionID":"L1006112","answers":["improbis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter ablative plural** of *improbus* (bad, dishonest)?"},"1292125835016274012":{"questionID":"L1021844","answers":["evenis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *evenio* (to happen)?"},"1292157995572264991":{"questionID":"A000330","answers":["live"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What does the Greek word **zao (ζαω)** mean?"},"1292158013569765428":{"questionID":"A000393","answers":["to kindle, burn... kaio (καιω)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **cauterize**?"},"1292158031588622427":{"questionID":"A000089","answers":["to lead, rule, be the first, begin... archo (αρχω)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **archipelago**?"},"1292158058562326668":{"questionID":"A000022","answers":["pais (παις), child","ago (αγω), to lead, bring"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **pedagogue**?"},"1292159012657434807":{"questionID":"A000643","answers":["turn about, twist... strepho (στρεφω)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **apostrophe**?"},"1292181093700599818":{"questionID":"P000052","answers":["DEO GRATIAM HABEAMUS (\"LET US BE GRATEFUL TO GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Kentucky*?"},"1292181074138628357":{"questionID":"P000083","answers":["CITIUS, ALTIUS, FORTIUS (\"FASTER, HIGHER, STRONGER\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Olympics*?"},"1292182423802613762":{"questionID":"L1021787","answers":["finiveritis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *finio* (to limit, to bound, to terminate)?"},"1292183678356553768":{"questionID":"L1010877","answers":["occupabit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future active indicative** of *occupo* (to occupy, seize)?"},"1292184201931784387":{"questionID":"L1014318","answers":["fatebunt"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future active indicative** of *fateor* (to confess, acknowledge)?"},"1292184224505401424":{"questionID":"L1006949","answers":["superba"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter accusative plural** of *superbus* (proud, arrogant)?"},"1292187979816767559":{"questionID":"L1006841","answers":["saevum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter accusative singular** of *saevus* (furious, ferocious)?"},"1292191312904196127":{"questionID":"P000134","answers":["(SENATUS CONSULTUM ULTIMUM) FINAL DECREE OF THE SENATE (MARITAL LAW)"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *S.C.U.*?"},"1292191328998002799":{"questionID":"P000234","answers":["I HAVE RAISED A MONUMENT MORE LASTING THAN BRONZE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Exegi monumentum aere perennius**."},"1292191487450284053":{"questionID":"P000001","answers":["PRO ECCLESIA, PRO TEXANA (\"FOR CHURCH, FOR TEXAS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Baylor University*?"},"1292191499076898908":{"questionID":"P000020","answers":["AD MAIOREM DEI GLORIAM (\"FOR THE GREATER GLORY OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *The Jesuit*?"},"1292191566617640980":{"questionID":"P000039","answers":["LUX SIT. (\"LET THERE BE LIGHT.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Washington*?"},"1292191576914788372":{"questionID":"P000039","answers":["LUX SIT. (\"LET THERE BE LIGHT.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Washington*?"},"1292191697622536222":{"questionID":"P000038","answers":["STUDIIS ET REBUS HONESTIS (\"BY HONORABLE PURSUITS AND DEEDS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Vermont*?"},"1292191706166329367":{"questionID":"P000072","answers":["URBS IN HORTO (\"CITY IN A GARDEN\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Chicago*?"},"1292191718069899324":{"questionID":"P000004","answers":["DEUS LUX MEA (\"GOD IS MY LIGHT\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Catholic University of America*?"},"1292191724202098838":{"questionID":"P000246","answers":["WHAT IN ARTIST DIES IN ME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Qualis artifex pereo**."},"1292191736038293597":{"questionID":"P000097","answers":["(PER OS) THROUGH THE MOUTH, I.E., ORALLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *p.o.*?"},"1292192077341397043":{"questionID":"P000008","answers":["SAPIENTIA ET DOCTRINA. (\"WISDOM AND KNOWLEDGE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Fordham University*?"},"1292192137399763037":{"questionID":"P000246","answers":["WHAT IN ARTIST DIES IN ME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Qualis artifex pereo**."},"1292192150918004736":{"questionID":"P000104","answers":["(TER IN DIE) THREE TIMES A DAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *t.i.d.*?"},"1292192377540313170":{"questionID":"P000025","answers":["CRESCAT SCIENTIA, VITA EXCOLATUR (\"LET KNOWLEDGE INCREASE, LET LIFE BE PERFECTED\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Chicago*?"},"1292192569081462814":{"questionID":"P000020","answers":["AD MAIOREM DEI GLORIAM (\"FOR THE GREATER GLORY OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *The Jesuit*?"},"1292192709821599744":{"questionID":"P000034","answers":["MENS AGITAT MOLEM (\"MIND MOVES THE MASS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Oregon*?"},"1292192717962612837":{"questionID":"P000078","answers":["PER ARDUA AD ASTRA (\"THROUGH STRUGGLE TO THE STARS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *The Royal Air Force*?"},"1292192725847773205":{"questionID":"P000017","answers":["CRUX SPES UNICA (\"THE CROSS IS THE ONLY HOPE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Notre Dame University*?"},"1292192732869169205":{"questionID":"P000099","answers":["(QUANTUM SUFFICIAT) AS MUCH AS NEEDED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *q.s.*?"},"1292193093285580891":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004160","answers":["educat"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *educo* (to bring up, educate)?"},"1292600579419279391":{"questionID":"A000364","answers":["histemi (ἱστημι), to stand, to make to stand"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **apostasy**?"},"1292601172397658194":{"questionID":"A000476","answers":["misos (μισος), hatred"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **misogamy**?"},"1292622106156339242":{"questionID":"A000426","answers":["krypto (κρυπτω), to hide"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **crypt**?"},"1292622126691520604":{"questionID":"A000160","answers":["ballo (βαλλω), throw"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **parabola**?"},"1292622070315880508":{"questionID":"A000517","answers":["house, household... oikos (οικος)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **parish**?"},"1292622446637223957":{"questionID":"LFIFTH001567","answers":["aegrae"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive singular** of *aeger* (ill, troubled)?"},"1292623571352420482":{"questionID":"LFIFTH001341","answers":["oves"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *ovis, ovis* (sheep)?"},"1292626876895858688":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002861","answers":["silvestrem"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine accusative singular** of *silvester* (belonging to a forest, woody)?"},"1293050345039204395":{"questionID":"F000504","answers":["TELEMACHUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the son of Penelope and Odysseus?"},"1293050307776876574":{"questionID":"LFIFTH005166","answers":["advenisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *advenio* (to come to, reach, arrive at)?"},"1293050610412814407":{"questionID":"F000516","answers":["DELPHI"],"genus":"myth","question":"What city had the early name Pytho?"},"1293050769129476127":{"questionID":"F002108","answers":["SISYPHUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who instituted the Isthmian Games?"},"1293050780139388969":{"questionID":"F001278","answers":["POSEIDON"],"genus":"myth","question":"What father of Polyphemus cursed Odysseus?"},"1293050791824719964":{"questionID":"F001792","answers":["PHERES AND CLYMENE"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who were the parents of Admetus?"},"1293050800590819338":{"questionID":"F001737","answers":["TEMENUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Which of the Heraclids took over Argos?"},"1293050851245559808":{"questionID":"F002107","answers":["MELICERTES"],"genus":"myth","question":"In whose honor were the Isthmian Games instituted?"},"1293051043994931272":{"questionID":"L1002208","answers":["anni"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *annus, anni* (year)?"},"1293063370299277425":{"questionID":"L1002383","answers":["virtutes"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *virtus, virtutis* (courage, virtue)?"},"1293064844232228968":{"questionID":"L1003850","answers":["clientibus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *cliens, clientis* (client; follower)?"},"1293064863207395348":{"questionID":"L1020729","answers":["ingredit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *ingredior* (to go into, to enter)?"},"1293064914453401640":{"questionID":"P000224","answers":["IN THIS SIGN YOU WILL CONQUER"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **In hoc signo vinces**."},"1293064914927226931":{"questionID":"L1011220","answers":["mirabimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future active indicative** of *miror* (to wonder, to be amazed, to admire)?"},"1293065061971132436":{"questionID":"L1015218","answers":["advenient"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future active indicative** of *advenio* (to come to, reach, arrive at)?"},"1293065102186123325":{"questionID":"P000173","answers":["IN ABSENCE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *In absentia*?"},"1293065119701401620":{"questionID":"P000025","answers":["CRESCAT SCIENTIA, VITA EXCOLATUR (\"LET KNOWLEDGE INCREASE, LET LIFE BE PERFECTED\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Chicago*?"},"1293065159392366636":{"questionID":"P000245","answers":["NERO"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Qualis artifex pereo**?"},"1293065187699720204":{"questionID":"L1000572","answers":["patriarum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural** of *patria, patriae* (native country)?"},"1293065214400663693":{"questionID":"P000080","answers":["AD MAIOREM DEI GLORIAM (\"FOR THE GREATER GLORY OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Society of Jesuits*?"},"1293065644090064961":{"questionID":"F001712","answers":["LICHAS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What herald was hurled to his death into the sea after delivering a poisoned robe?"},"1293065717255634994":{"questionID":"L1007321","answers":["fallaci"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *fallax* (deceitful)?"},"1293066203366953122":{"questionID":"L1000413","answers":["viis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *via, viae* (way, path, street)?"},"1293066223491354746":{"questionID":"L1001224","answers":["soceris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative plural** of *socer, soceri* (father-in-law)?"},"1293066473119682600":{"questionID":"F000179","answers":["APHRODITE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What deity possessed a magic girdle with irresistible powers of enticement?"},"1293066495328387072":{"questionID":"F000943","answers":["PRIAM"],"genus":"myth","question":"By what better name is the Trojan Podarces known?"},"1293066705513353246":{"questionID":"F001481","answers":["IPHICLES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the son of Amphitryon and Alcmena, half-brother of Heracles?"},"1293066771552796726":{"questionID":"F001194","answers":["ODYSSEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who received Hecuba as part of the spoils of Troy?"},"1293066840108699711":{"questionID":"F001358","answers":["TIRESIAS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who had told Odysseus to carry an oar until people thought it was a winnowing fan?"},"1293066853404639315":{"questionID":"F000499","answers":["ELPENOR"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who first addresses Odysseus in the underworld before drinking the blood?"},"1293066923562500147":{"questionID":"F000454","answers":["ALCIBIADES"],"genus":"myth","question":"What Athenian leader supposedly desecrated the Herms?"},"1293066932999950428":{"questionID":"F001143","answers":["BATTLE BETWEEN GODS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What does the term 'theomachy' refer to?"},"1293067105654149191":{"questionID":"L1005247","answers":["candidae"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine dative singular** of *candidus* (white, clear)?"},"1293067115279945829":{"questionID":"L1005183","answers":["blandi"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine genitive singular** of *blandus* (agreeable)?"},"1293067182917287979":{"questionID":"F000755","answers":["ANTIGONE"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was engaged to marry Haemon?"},"1293067204891512863":{"questionID":"F000495","answers":["PHAEACIANS"],"genus":"myth","question":"To what island nation does Odysseus narrate his journey to the underworld?"},"1293067211631497278":{"questionID":"F000142","answers":["TROY"],"genus":"myth","question":"With what city's destiny was the Palladium tied?"},"1293067218740973578":{"questionID":"F001816","answers":["POLYDEUCES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the best boxer among the Argonauts?"},"1293067492931141692":{"questionID":"L1017469","answers":["gessi"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *gero* (to bear, carry)?"},"1293067549579284500":{"questionID":"F001087","answers":["MOPSUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Whom did Calchas challenge to a seer contest after the Trojan War?"},"1293067564800409661":{"questionID":"F002299","answers":["JASON"],"genus":"myth","question":"After forcing fire-breathing bulls into submission, who yoked them to a plow and used them to sow a field with dragon's teeth?"},"1293067669985296384":{"questionID":"F001817","answers":["IDAS AND LYNCEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What two brothers and later enemies of the Dioscuri (Castor & Polydeuces) joined them on the Argo?"},"1293067772124729435":{"questionID":"L1018881","answers":["consuescebat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *consuesco* (to be accustomed)?"},"1293067823048032307":{"questionID":"P000178","answers":["IN WINE, THE TRUTH"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *In vino veritas*?"},"1293070767201718272":{"questionID":"F000172","answers":["CYPRUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"On what island was the city of Paphos?"},"1293070813074948141":{"questionID":"F000791","answers":["TANTALUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Pelops?"},"1293071566728593488":{"questionID":"F002324","answers":["IOBATES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who received a letter instructing him to kill its messenger because he had allegedly seduced the wife of Proetus?"},"1293071595635609601":{"questionID":"F001335","answers":["EUMAEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What faithful swineherd of Odysseus first recognized him?"},"1293071638417375284":{"questionID":"F000013","answers":["NAIADS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What names was given to the nymphs of water, springs, lakes and rivers?"},"1293071663407169537":{"questionID":"F000928","answers":["HELEN AS HIS WIFE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What did Aphrodite offer Paris as a bribe?"},"1293071734425260053":{"questionID":"F000966","answers":["ASTYANAX"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the child of Hector and Andromache?"},"1293071803689865236":{"questionID":"F001218","answers":["AVENGING HIS SON PALAMEDES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Why did Nauplius lure Greek ships to their doom with a false beacon?"},"1293072087862218802":{"questionID":"F000920","answers":["AESACUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who foretold that Paris would lead to Troy's destruction?"},"1293072115561398335":{"questionID":"F000898","answers":["CASTOR AND POLYDEUCES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who were the Dioscuri?"},"1293072243383074818":{"questionID":"F000272","answers":["WEEPING STONE"],"genus":"myth","question":"Into what was Niobe transformed?"},"1293072255391236137":{"questionID":"F002333","answers":["CREON"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who had decreed that it was illegal to bury the body of Polyneices, the brother of Ismene?"},"1293072274441769023":{"questionID":"F001496","answers":["STHENELUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Whose child's birth was hastened by Hera to trick Zeus?"},"1293072473507627059":{"questionID":"F000988","answers":["LYCIANS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Of what Trojan ally were Glaucus and Sarpedon the leaders?"},"1293072519628324906":{"questionID":"F001029","answers":["PRIAM"],"genus":"myth","question":"To whom does Helen describe the Greeks as they fight in the plain?"},"1293072528230846464":{"questionID":"F001705","answers":["ZEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who threw a thunderbolt between Heracles and Apollo to stop their fighting?"},"1293072536174723102":{"questionID":"F002329","answers":["ETEOCLES"],"genus":"myth","question":"What king of Thebes refused to give up power when his year to rule was up?"},"1293072545662107658":{"questionID":"F000976","answers":["CASSANDRA"],"genus":"myth","question":"What daughter of Priam received the gift of prophecy from Apollo?"},"1293072557695565824":{"questionID":"F002126","answers":["TIRYNS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Where was Proetus, the purifier of Bellerophon, king?"},"1293072672724619306":{"questionID":"F000933","answers":["SEA MONSTER"],"genus":"myth","question":"What did Poseidon send to Troy to punish Laomedon?"},"1293072680307654748":{"questionID":"F001197","answers":["POLYMESTOR"],"genus":"myth","question":"To whom did Priam send his son Polydorus for safe refuge during the war?"},"1293072825602674688":{"questionID":"P000111","answers":["(DEO VOLENTE) GOD WILLING"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *D.V.*?"},"1293072876693487658":{"questionID":"P000204","answers":["TIME FLIES"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *tempus fugit*?"},"1293072935933710336":{"questionID":"P000080","answers":["AD MAIOREM DEI GLORIAM (\"FOR THE GREATER GLORY OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Society of Jesuits*?"},"1293072982188490773":{"questionID":"P000065","answers":["IMPERIUM IN IMPERIO (\"AN EMPIRE WITHIN AN EMPIRE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Ohio*?"},"1293073018536460399":{"questionID":"P000244","answers":["WHO WILL GUARD THE GUARDS THEMSELVES?"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Quis custodiet ipsos custodes?**."},"1293073191408762953":{"questionID":"P000138","answers":["(VIDE INFRA) SEE BELOW"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *v.i.*?"},"1293073200527183953":{"questionID":"P000040","answers":["PRO HUMANITATE (\"FOR HUMANITY\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Wake Forest Univesity*?"},"1293073208257544294":{"questionID":"P000136","answers":["(SI OPUS SIT) IF THERE IS NEED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *s.o.s.*?"},"1293073264037593088":{"questionID":"P000183","answers":["PERFECTION"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Ne plus ultra*?"},"1293073277987721277":{"questionID":"P000219","answers":["THE DIE IS CAST"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Alea iacta est**."},"1293073286065815583":{"questionID":"P000136","answers":["(SI OPUS SIT) IF THERE IS NEED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *s.o.s.*?"},"1293073751239557162":{"questionID":"P000098","answers":["(QUAQUE DIE) EVERYDAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *q.d.*?"},"1293073780092047413":{"questionID":"P000062","answers":["ESSE QUAM VIDERI (\"TO BE RATHER THAN TO SEEM\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *North Carolina*?"},"1293073818893549669":{"questionID":"P000111","answers":["(DEO VOLENTE) GOD WILLING"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *D.V.*?"},"1293073870269579354":{"questionID":"F002213","answers":["TEUCER"],"genus":"myth","question":"What son of Scamander was a king of the Troad?"},"1293073881619369985":{"questionID":"F001397","answers":["GRAEAE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What aged women were the sisters of the Gorgons?"},"1293073893724131368":{"questionID":"F001014","answers":["ODYSSEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who travelled with Diomedes to fetch Achilles from Scyros?"},"1293073902100287559":{"questionID":"F001833","answers":["HORSEMANSHIP"],"genus":"myth","question":"What was the talent of Castor?"},"1293073911679942676":{"questionID":"F000924","answers":["ZEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who decided that Paris should decide the golden apple judgment?"},"1293073918545891369":{"questionID":"F000936","answers":["LAOMEDON'S IMMORTAL HORSES"],"genus":"myth","question":"What payment did Heracles demand of Laomedon for saving Hesione?"},"1293076323274592287":{"questionID":"P000077","answers":["SEMPER PARATUS (\"ALWAYS READY\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Coast Guard*?"},"1293076336419803207":{"questionID":"P000077","answers":["SEMPER PARATUS (\"ALWAYS READY\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Coast Guard*?"},"1293076433006104606":{"questionID":"P000196","answers":["WITHOUT DELAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Sine mora*?"},"1293076529760305182":{"questionID":"F001790","answers":["AMYTHAON"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Melampus and Bias?"},"1293076537305858088":{"questionID":"F000405","answers":["MARSYAS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was flayed alive after losing a music contest to Apollo?"},"1293076563704807479":{"questionID":"F001197","answers":["POLYMESTOR"],"genus":"myth","question":"To whom did Priam send his son Polydorus for safe refuge during the war?"},"1293076596890271754":{"questionID":"F000926","answers":["ROYAL POWER"],"genus":"myth","question":"What did Hera offer Paris as a bribe?"},"1293076613034151966":{"questionID":"F001114","answers":["ILIAD"],"genus":"myth","question":"What poem is often described as 'the wrath of Achilles'?"},"1293076783360507926":{"questionID":"P000029","answers":["VIRTUTE ET ARMIS. (\"BY VALOR AND ARMS.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Mississippi*?"},"1293076828713385984":{"questionID":"F000833","answers":["ORESTES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the son of Agamemnon and Clytemnestra?"},"1293076883818418197":{"questionID":"F000585","answers":["THE FROGS"],"genus":"myth","question":"In what play does Aristophanes write 'brekekekex koax koax'?"},"1293076943490515018":{"questionID":"F002340","answers":["PENELOPE"],"genus":"myth","question":"Agenor, Leodes, Amphimedon, Eurymachus, and Antinous were all suitors of what Ithacan queen?"},"1293076958275436605":{"questionID":"F000964","answers":["EETION"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Andromache?"},"1293077001170845767":{"questionID":"F001103","answers":["HERACLES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Telephus, wounded by Achilles?"},"1293077043432394793":{"questionID":"P000247","answers":["OVID"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Rident stolidi verba Latina**?"},"1293077058242482206":{"questionID":"P000244","answers":["WHO WILL GUARD THE GUARDS THEMSELVES?"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Quis custodiet ipsos custodes?**."},"1293077143785574472":{"questionID":"F000325","answers":["SENECA THE YOUNGER"],"genus":"myth","question":"What Roman playwright wrote a tragedy called Phaedra?"},"1293077156510826528":{"questionID":"F001194","answers":["ODYSSEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who received Hecuba as part of the spoils of Troy?"},"1293077168582033458":{"questionID":"P000219","answers":["THE DIE IS CAST"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Alea iacta est**."},"1293077357661261906":{"questionID":"F001052","answers":["ZEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who rejected Thetis upon learning her son would be greater than his father?"},"1293077368428036117":{"questionID":"F001812","answers":["OILEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What father of Ajax the Lesser was among the Argonauts?"},"1293077461961015336":{"questionID":"F000428","answers":["PLEIADES"],"genus":"myth","question":"To what group did Maia belong?"},"1293077476213260348":{"questionID":"F000196","answers":["MYRRHA"],"genus":"myth","question":"What daughter of Cinyras fell desperately in love with her own father?"},"1293077485226950709":{"questionID":"F000647","answers":["SICYON"],"genus":"myth","question":"To what city did Antiope flee?"},"1293077555271831585":{"questionID":"F000631","answers":["ARES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Whom did Cadmus have to serve after killing a serpent?"},"1293077566336532530":{"questionID":"F002209","answers":["ISIS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who turned Iphis into a boy the day before her wedding to Ianthe?"},"1293077578956931123":{"questionID":"F000303","answers":["ORION"],"genus":"myth","question":"What giant pursued the Pleiades in life and afterwards as a constellation?"},"1293077589052755979":{"questionID":"F000941","answers":["HERACLES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who killed Laomedon?"},"1293077595499397161":{"questionID":"F002001","answers":["ACHILLES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the son of Peleus and Thetis?"},"1293077603531358279":{"questionID":"F002143","answers":["ARTEMIS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who killed Laodamia, daughter of Bellerophon?"},"1293077611488219169":{"questionID":"F001124","answers":["SARPEDON"],"genus":"myth","question":"What son of Zeus is killed by Patroclus?"},"1293078199709728809":{"questionID":"P000017","answers":["CRUX SPES UNICA (\"THE CROSS IS THE ONLY HOPE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Notre Dame University*?"},"1293078361169596456":{"questionID":"P000233","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Exegi monumentum aere perennius**?"},"1293078377770782780":{"questionID":"P000248","answers":["FOOLS LAUGH AT THE LATIN LANGUAGE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Rident stolidi verba Latina**."},"1293078440337080361":{"questionID":"P000225","answers":["DESCARTES"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous person said **Cogito ergo sum**?"},"1293078449052844032":{"questionID":"P000248","answers":["FOOLS LAUGH AT THE LATIN LANGUAGE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Rident stolidi verba Latina**."},"1293078461912453190":{"questionID":"P000133","answers":["(SCILICET) ACTUALLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *sc.*?"},"1293078472658522204":{"questionID":"P000147","answers":["YOU HIT THE NAIL ON THE HEAD"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *rem acu tetigisti*?"},"1293078649318281246":{"questionID":"P000199","answers":["EXISTING CONDITION"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Status quo*?"},"1293078724639588433":{"questionID":"P000221","answers":["CATO THE ELDER"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Delenda est Carthago**?"},"1293078732948639745":{"questionID":"P000036","answers":["DISCIPLINA PRAESIDIUM CIVITATIS (\"INSTRUCTION IS THE SAFEGUARD OF THE STATE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Texas*?"},"1293078886552436766":{"questionID":"P000023","answers":["PAX ET LUX (\"PEACE AND LIGHT\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Tufts University*?"},"1293078952134578296":{"questionID":"P000213","answers":["AUGUSTUS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Acta est fabula**?"},"1293078971419856896":{"questionID":"P000024","answers":["CIVIUM IN MORIBUS REI PUBLIAE SALUS. (\"IN THE CHARACTER OF ITS CITIZENS LIES THE WELFARE OF THE STATE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Univ. Florida*?"},"1293079180099059744":{"questionID":"P000015","answers":["PERSTARE ET PRAESTARE. (\"TO PRESERVE AND TO SURPASS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *New York University*?"},"1293079228941598812":{"questionID":"P000224","answers":["IN THIS SIGN YOU WILL CONQUER"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **In hoc signo vinces**."},"1293079504104849428":{"questionID":"P000133","answers":["(SCILICET) ACTUALLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *sc.*?"},"1293079575743430676":{"questionID":"P000194","answers":["PROBABLE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Similis veri*?"},"1293079588389519380":{"questionID":"P000220","answers":["CROSSING THE RUBICON"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Before what major event did Caesar say **Alea iacta est**?"},"1293079595041689692":{"questionID":"P000242","answers":["BREAD AND CIRCUS GAMES"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Panem et circenses**."},"1293079602117349469":{"questionID":"P000232","answers":["ALAS, THE FLEETING YEARS GLIDE BY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Eheu fugaces labuntur anni**."},"1293079617955172402":{"questionID":"P000041","answers":["PER VIRTUTEM VIS (\"STRENGTH THROUGH VIRTUE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Washington University*?"},"1293079628558106645":{"questionID":"P000015","answers":["PERSTARE ET PRAESTARE. (\"TO PRESERVE AND TO SURPASS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *New York University*?"},"1293079634346508319":{"questionID":"P000093","answers":["(HORA SOMNI) AT BEDTIME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *h.s.*?"},"1293083000636178515":{"questionID":"LFIFTH003953","answers":["memoramus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *memoro* (to remind of, to mention)?"},"1293212485582717009":{"questionID":"L1002894","answers":["virginem"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative singular** of *virgo, virginis* (maiden, virgin)?"},"1293212430763294741":{"questionID":"L1004490","answers":["diebus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *dies, diei* (day)?"},"1293212632324505671":{"questionID":"L1012056","answers":["dignant"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *dignor* (to deem worthy)?"},"1293260931245281360":{"questionID":"L1002119","answers":["capillorum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural** of *capillus, capilli* (hair)?"},"1293261030176329760":{"questionID":"L1008844","answers":["offeret"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future active indicative** of *offero* (to bring before, offer, show)?"},"1293261848682172459":{"questionID":"L1012251","answers":["constat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *consto* (to stand firm, endure; to be evident)?"},"1293261862749737082":{"questionID":"L1012764","answers":["accusaverant"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *accuso* (to accuse, blame)?"},"1293262548543475712":{"questionID":"L1009259","answers":["deferetis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future active indicative** of *defero* (to bear or bring away; to report)?"},"1293262559696261174":{"questionID":"L1017770","answers":["explebis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future active indicative** of *expleo* (to fill, complete)?"},"1293262572111527936":{"questionID":"L1018406","answers":["deponis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *depono* (to put down)?"},"1293262580395147366":{"questionID":"L1003361","answers":["pastori"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *pastor, pastoris* (shepherd)?"},"1293266360591323186":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002105","answers":["ignota"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter nominative plural** of *ignotus* (unknown)?"},"1293268289123913891":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002027","answers":["formosum"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter accusative singular** of *formosus* (beautiful, handsome)?"},"1293268355263762492":{"questionID":"LFIFTH006488","answers":["caeditis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *caedo* (to cut, cut off, strike, kill)?"},"1293323375359426701":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004527","answers":["studuimus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *studeo* (to be eager, to desire; to study)?"},"1293324840953970810":{"questionID":"L1009803","answers":["turbat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *turbo* (to disturb, agitate)?"},"1293326866505011260":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002888","answers":[" nostrum"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive singular** of *nos* (we, us, ourselves; emph. I, me, myself)?,nostri"},"1293343629150261340":{"questionID":"LFIFTH001233","answers":["errores"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *error, erroris* (wandering; mistake)?"},"1293343610539868253":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002026","answers":["formosam"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine accusative singular** of *formosus* (beautiful, handsome)?"},"1293343591279755285":{"questionID":"LFIFTH003370","answers":["aufers"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *aufero* (to take off, remove)?"},"1293344712110899251":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004415","answers":["accusavi"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *accuso* (to accuse, blame)?"},"1293361136678338643":{"questionID":"LFIFTH001092","answers":["potestates"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *potestas, potestatis* (power, authority)?"},"1293365566110699641":{"questionID":"LFIFTH003515","answers":["vacavimus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *vaco* (to be empty, vacant, free, idle)?"},"1293369930879733832":{"questionID":"L1003193","answers":["scelere"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *scelus, sceleris* (crime)?"},"1293369892761763904":{"questionID":"L1020661","answers":["pepereram"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *pario* (to bring forth, bear, produce)?"},"1293370666761977856":{"questionID":"L1019983","answers":["addam"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future active indicative** of *addo* (to add)?"},"1293370979124510783":{"questionID":"F000583","answers":["VERGIL"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who does Dante describe as his guide in the underworld?"},"1293370996706770987":{"questionID":"F000282","answers":["ARCADIA"],"genus":"myth","question":"Where did Callisto live?"},"1293371004684603422":{"questionID":"F001711","answers":["LICHAS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who carried the poisoned robe of Deianira to Heracles?"},"1293371411808915518":{"questionID":"LFIFTH001939","answers":["dubiae"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive singular** of *dubius* (uncertain)?"},"1293371521103822932":{"questionID":"LFIFTH005685","answers":["loquis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *loquor* (to speak, talk, say)?"},"1293432014040727572":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004442","answers":["viderunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *video* (to see)?"},"1293431995069759530":{"questionID":"LFIFTH005292","answers":["requisivisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *requiro* (to ask, demand, inquire)?"},"1293431975092158464":{"questionID":"LFIFTH006454","answers":["carpimus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *carpo* (to pick, pluck, crop)?"},"1293437275115360288":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002036","answers":["frigidi"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter genitive singular** of *frigidus* (cold)?"},"1293437292375179294":{"questionID":"LFIFTH001579","answers":["aequae"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive singular** of *aequus* (plain, favourable, fair)?"},"1293437872258416641":{"questionID":"P000203","answers":["A CLEAN SLATE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *tabula rasa*?"},"1293437897801728010":{"questionID":"P000134","answers":["(SENATUS CONSULTUM ULTIMUM) FINAL DECREE OF THE SENATE (MARITAL LAW)"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *S.C.U.*?"},"1293437910283976705":{"questionID":"P000088","answers":["SIT TIBI TERRA LEVIS (\"MAY THE EARTH REST LIGHTLY ON YOU\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *S.T.T.L.*?"},"1293437921004879873":{"questionID":"P000196","answers":["WITHOUT DELAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Sine mora*?"},"1293438007365468222":{"questionID":"LHALF011658","answers":["moriebatis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *morior* (to die)?"},"1293438125716144199":{"questionID":"LHALF001377","answers":["damno"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *damnum, damni* (damage, loss)?"},"1293438274198700062":{"questionID":"P000208","answers":["WORD FOR WORD"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *verbatim*?"},"1293438500619685910":{"questionID":"P000218","answers":["CAESAR"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Alea iacta est**?"},"1293438510295945226":{"questionID":"P000039","answers":["LUX SIT. (\"LET THERE BE LIGHT.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Washington*?"},"1293438562892779602":{"questionID":"P000004","answers":["DEUS LUX MEA (\"GOD IS MY LIGHT\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Catholic University of America*?"},"1293438572551999501":{"questionID":"P000150","answers":["FROM WHAT IS ALREADY KNOWN (LIT. \"FROM WHAT COMES BEFORE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *a priori*?"},"1293438629556781099":{"questionID":"P000245","answers":["NERO"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Qualis artifex pereo**?"},"1293438655612063776":{"questionID":"F001762","answers":["PHYXIUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What epithet was applied to Zeus as the god of escape?"},"1293438672737140758":{"questionID":"F001003","answers":["WHITE HORSES"],"genus":"myth","question":"What possession of Rhesus became a prize of Odysseus and Diomedes?"},"1293438754823995482":{"questionID":"F000197","answers":["MYRRH"],"genus":"myth","question":"Into what kind of tree was Myrrha transformed to escape the wrath of her father Cinyras?"},"1293438770284068865":{"questionID":"F000616","answers":["AGENOR"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Cadmus?"},"1293438776827183115":{"questionID":"F000290","answers":["ZEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who prevented Arcas from killing his mother, the bear, while hunting?"},"1293438794892054609":{"questionID":"F001465","answers":["PTERELAUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What king of the Teleboans fought Electryon of Mycenae?"},"1293438801951326278":{"questionID":"F000222","answers":["EOS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who abducted the Trojan prince Tithonus?"},"1293438808301502474":{"questionID":"F000758","answers":["EVADNE"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the wife of Capaneus?"},"1293438810390134824":{"questionID":"P000041","answers":["PER VIRTUTEM VIS (\"STRENGTH THROUGH VIRTUE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Washington University*?"},"1293438812562653267":{"questionID":"F000421","answers":["TITYUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was punished by Apollo for trying to rape Leto?"},"1293438818992656435":{"questionID":"P000230","answers":["THERE'S NO GREATER HONOR THAN TO DIE FOR ONE'S COUNTRY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Dulce et decorum est pro patria mori**."},"1293438820498538517":{"questionID":"F001487","answers":["LICYMNIUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What son of Electryon and Anaxo was the brother of Alcmena?"},"1293438827452432445":{"questionID":"F001176","answers":["DEMODOCUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What bard sings of Troy in the Odyssey?"},"1293438827494506567":{"questionID":"P000152","answers":["FROM THE EGG TO THE APPLE (\"FROM BEGINNING TO END\" OR \"FROM SOUP TO NUTS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *ab ovo usque ad mala*?"},"1293441036349210674":{"questionID":"A000600","answers":["pathos (παθος), feeling"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **sympathy**?"},"1293664474347081819":{"questionID":"LHALF002936","answers":["habitus"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *habitus, habitus* (appearance, dress)?"},"1293718040206381096":{"questionID":"LHALF006453","answers":["turbavit"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *turbo* (to disturb, agitate)?"},"1293718716575387678":{"questionID":"LHALF006068","answers":["interfuit"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *intersum* (to be between; to differ; to take part in)?"},"1293723584488804454":{"questionID":"LHALF011162","answers":["bibi"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *bibo* (to drink)?"},"1293778430424514600":{"questionID":"P000076","answers":["SEMPER FIDELIS (\"ALWAYS FAITHFUL\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Marine Corps*?"},"1293778852899848254":{"questionID":"P000246","answers":["WHAT IN ARTIST DIES IN ME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Qualis artifex pereo**."},"1293778940489498674":{"questionID":"P000244","answers":["WHO WILL GUARD THE GUARDS THEMSELVES?"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Quis custodiet ipsos custodes?**."},"1293778956792889345":{"questionID":"P000056","answers":["SI QUAERIS PENINSULAM AMOENAM, CIRCUMSPICE (\"IF YOU SEEK A PLEASANT PENINSULA, LOOK AROUND\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Michigan*?"},"1293779034873790534":{"questionID":"P000027","answers":["ET DOCERE ET RERUM EXQUIRERE CAUSAS (\"BOTH TO TEACH & TO INQUIRE INTO THE CAUSES OF THINGS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Georgia*?"},"1293780011790372904":{"questionID":"P000033","answers":["CIVI ET REI PUBLICAE (\"FOR THE CITIZEN AND THE STATE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Oklahoma*?"},"1293780051321552970":{"questionID":"P000033","answers":["CIVI ET REI PUBLICAE (\"FOR THE CITIZEN AND THE STATE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Oklahoma*?"},"1293780064307122207":{"questionID":"P000230","answers":["THERE'S NO GREATER HONOR THAN TO DIE FOR ONE'S COUNTRY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Dulce et decorum est pro patria mori**."},"1293780149497499671":{"questionID":"P000014","answers":["PRODESSE QUAM CONSPICI. (\"TO THE PRODUCTIVE, RATHER THAN TO BE ORNAMENTAL.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Miami University of Ohio*?"},"1293780163699544105":{"questionID":"P000000","answers":["TERRAS IRRADIENT. (\"LET THEM ILLUMINATE THE EARTH.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Amherst College*?"},"1293780169646932001":{"questionID":"P000206","answers":["A CONSTANT COMPANION (GO WITH ME)"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *vade mecum*?"},"1293780248739188777":{"questionID":"P000128","answers":["(PRO RE NATA) AS THE NEED ARISES"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *p.r.n.*?"},"1293784445043609672":{"questionID":"P000098","answers":["(QUAQUE DIE) EVERYDAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *q.d.*?"},"1293784487985025086":{"questionID":"P000020","answers":["AD MAIOREM DEI GLORIAM (\"FOR THE GREATER GLORY OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *The Jesuit*?"},"1293784470171681026":{"questionID":"P000154","answers":["FOR THIS PURPOSE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *ad hoc*?"},"1293784507325091881":{"questionID":"P000120","answers":["(FOLIO VERSO) ON THE LEFT HAND PAGE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *f.v.*?"},"1293784586320613528":{"questionID":"P000184","answers":["AN UNSOUND MAN"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Non compos mentis*?"},"1293784683825336431":{"questionID":"P000145","answers":["THERE IS NO ACCOUNTING FOR TASTE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *De gustibus non est disputandum*?"},"1293784845691912243":{"questionID":"P000020","answers":["AD MAIOREM DEI GLORIAM (\"FOR THE GREATER GLORY OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *The Jesuit*?"},"1293784869381341194":{"questionID":"P000130","answers":["(PINXIT) HE PAINTED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *pinx.*?"},"1293784879548338238":{"questionID":"P000206","answers":["A CONSTANT COMPANION (GO WITH ME)"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *vade mecum*?"},"1293784890516574208":{"questionID":"P000023","answers":["PAX ET LUX (\"PEACE AND LIGHT\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Tufts University*?"},"1293784896455577633":{"questionID":"P000181","answers":["A METHOD OF WORKING"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *modus operandi*?"},"1293784905695756321":{"questionID":"P000189","answers":["AN UNWELCOME PERSON"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Persona non grata*?"},"1293784943465336882":{"questionID":"P000055","answers":["ENSE PETIT PLACIDAM SUB LIBERTATE QUIETEM (\"WITH THE SWORD HE SEEKS PEACE UNDER LIBERTY\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Massachusettes*?"},"1293784994736635904":{"questionID":"P000047","answers":["NIL SINE NUMINE (\"NOTHING WITHOUT GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Colorado*?"},"1293785298643320844":{"questionID":"P000087","answers":["HIC IACET SEPULTUS (\"HERE LIES BURIED\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *H.J.S.*?"},"1293785310278320224":{"questionID":"P000144","answers":["WHERE THERE'S A WILL THERE'S A WAY (LIT. \"EITHER I'LL FIND A WAY OR MAKE ONE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *aut viam inveniam aut faciam*?"},"1293785323276337272":{"questionID":"P000118","answers":["(FLORUIT) PERIOD OF TIME DURING WHICH A PERSON OR THING FLOURISHED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *fl.*?"},"1293792904393003028":{"questionID":"P000250","answers":["TIME, THE DEVOURER OF ALL THINGS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Tempus edax rerum**."},"1293792922336231464":{"questionID":"P000154","answers":["FOR THIS PURPOSE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *ad hoc*?"},"1293793490395988048":{"questionID":"P000126","answers":["(MODIORUM) MEDIUM"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *mod.*?"},"1293793502592892980":{"questionID":"P000026","answers":["FIAT LUX (\"LET THERE BE LIGHT\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of California*?"},"1293793708013129758":{"questionID":"P000135","answers":["(SINE GRATIA) WITHOUT EXAMPLE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *s.g.*?"},"1293793718356410368":{"questionID":"P000248","answers":["FOOLS LAUGH AT THE LATIN LANGUAGE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Rident stolidi verba Latina**."},"1293793912858611723":{"questionID":"P000093","answers":["(HORA SOMNI) AT BEDTIME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *h.s.*?"},"1293793932269977694":{"questionID":"P000232","answers":["ALAS, THE FLEETING YEARS GLIDE BY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Eheu fugaces labuntur anni**."},"1293794072493953117":{"questionID":"P000189","answers":["AN UNWELCOME PERSON"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Persona non grata*?"},"1293794105213849601":{"questionID":"P000001","answers":["PRO ECCLESIA, PRO TEXANA (\"FOR CHURCH, FOR TEXAS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Baylor University*?"},"1293794112478384158":{"questionID":"P000137","answers":["(SENATUS POPULUSQUE ROMANUS) THE SENATE AND POPULACE OF ROME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *S.P.Q.R.*?"},"1293794198130266163":{"questionID":"P000040","answers":["PRO HUMANITATE (\"FOR HUMANITY\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Wake Forest Univesity*?"},"1293794209492369508":{"questionID":"P000074","answers":["DOMINE, DIRIGE NOS (\"LORD, GUIDE US\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *London*?"},"1293794220406214677":{"questionID":"P000122","answers":["(IBIDEM) IN THE SAME PLACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *ibid.*?"},"1293794229323038820":{"questionID":"P000220","answers":["CROSSING THE RUBICON"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Before what major event did Caesar say **Alea iacta est**?"},"1293794236738703494":{"questionID":"P000117","answers":["(FOLIIS) ON THE [FOLLOWING] PAGES"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *ff.*?"},"1293794244972249180":{"questionID":"P000094","answers":["(OCULUS DEXTER) RIGHT EYE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *o.d.*?"},"1293794282439966750":{"questionID":"P000148","answers":["ON THE RIGHT"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *a dextra*?"},"1293794558110597130":{"questionID":"P000029","answers":["VIRTUTE ET ARMIS. (\"BY VALOR AND ARMS.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Mississippi*?"},"1293794624611024987":{"questionID":"P000060","answers":["CRESCIT EUNDO (\"IT GROWS AS IT GOES\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *New Mexico*?"},"1293794787249360926":{"questionID":"P000020","answers":["AD MAIOREM DEI GLORIAM (\"FOR THE GREATER GLORY OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *The Jesuit*?"},"1293794846687105066":{"questionID":"P000242","answers":["BREAD AND CIRCUS GAMES"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Panem et circenses**."},"1293794854836375613":{"questionID":"P000009","answers":["DEUS NOBIS FIDUCIA (\"GOD IS OUR TRUST\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *George Washington University*?"},"1293795019777376337":{"questionID":"P000012","answers":["LUX ET VERITAS (\"LIGHT AND TRUTH\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Indiana University Bloomington*?"},"1293795418626588712":{"questionID":"P000171","answers":["THEREFORE, LET US REJOICE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Gaudeamus igitur*?"},"1293795430336823366":{"questionID":"P000072","answers":["URBS IN HORTO (\"CITY IN A GARDEN\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Chicago*?"},"1293795538835079188":{"questionID":"P000221","answers":["CATO THE ELDER"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Delenda est Carthago**?"},"1293796072744812564":{"questionID":"P000062","answers":["ESSE QUAM VIDERI (\"TO BE RATHER THAN TO SEEM\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *North Carolina*?"},"1293796149651832842":{"questionID":"P000174","answers":["FOREVER"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *In aeternum*?"},"1293796157235003474":{"questionID":"P000026","answers":["FIAT LUX (\"LET THERE BE LIGHT\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of California*?"},"1293796165321621504":{"questionID":"P000132","answers":["(QUOD ERAT DEMONSTRANDUM) THAT WHICH WAS TO BE BE SHOWN"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *Q.E.D.*?"},"1293796207629697034":{"questionID":"P000052","answers":["DEO GRATIAM HABEAMUS (\"LET US BE GRATEFUL TO GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Kentucky*?"},"1293796310045950033":{"questionID":"P000201","answers":["ONE OF A KIND"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *sui generis*?"},"1293796328798945382":{"questionID":"P000176","answers":["IN THE MIDDLE OF THINGS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *in medias res*?"},"1293796495018950736":{"questionID":"P000236","answers":["ALL THAT WORK AND NOTHING TO SHOW FOR IT"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **parturient montes, nasceture ridiculus mus**."},"1293796703274795018":{"questionID":"P000252","answers":["TO ERR IS HUMAN"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Errare humanum est**."},"1293796713466957845":{"questionID":"P000030","answers":["SALUS POPULI. (\"THE WELFARE OF THE PEOPLE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Missouri*?"},"1293796720836349972":{"questionID":"P000009","answers":["DEUS NOBIS FIDUCIA (\"GOD IS OUR TRUST\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *George Washington University*?"},"1293796725567258644":{"questionID":"P000090","answers":["(ANTE CIBOS) BEFORE MEALS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *a.c.*?"},"1293796732584329307":{"questionID":"P000000","answers":["TERRAS IRRADIENT. (\"LET THEM ILLUMINATE THE EARTH.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Amherst College*?"},"1293796798627840060":{"questionID":"P000108","answers":["(CETERIS PARIBUS) WITH OTHER THINGS BEING EQUAL"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *Cet. Par.*?"},"1293796807163510794":{"questionID":"P000180","answers":["A SLIP OF THE TONGUE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *lapsus linguae*?"},"1293796991800836106":{"questionID":"P000226","answers":["I THINK THEREFORE I AM"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Cogito ergo sum**."},"1293797084352479307":{"questionID":"P000224","answers":["IN THIS SIGN YOU WILL CONQUER"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **In hoc signo vinces**."},"1293797191130808362":{"questionID":"P000039","answers":["LUX SIT. (\"LET THERE BE LIGHT.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Washington*?"},"1293797202912608256":{"questionID":"P000162","answers":["JUSTIFICATION FOR WAR"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Casus Belli*?"},"1293797462372515850":{"questionID":"P000089","answers":["DIS MINIBUS (\"TO THE SPIRITS OF THE DEAD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *D.M.*?"},"1293797505468727306":{"questionID":"P000137","answers":["(SENATUS POPULUSQUE ROMANUS) THE SENATE AND POPULACE OF ROME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *S.P.Q.R.*?"},"1293797534912741526":{"questionID":"P000220","answers":["CROSSING THE RUBICON"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Before what major event did Caesar say **Alea iacta est**?"},"1293797544115310622":{"questionID":"P000031","answers":["LITTERIS DEDICATA ET OMNIBUS ARTIBUS (\"DEDICATED TO LETTERS AND ALL THE ARTS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Nebraska*?"},"1293797551815921694":{"questionID":"P000164","answers":["LET THE BUYER BEWARE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Caveat emptor*?"},"1293797559214805044":{"questionID":"P000207","answers":["WOE TO THE CONQUERED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *vae victis*?"},"1293797563572420709":{"questionID":"P000195","answers":["INDEFINITELY","WITHOUT SETTING A DAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *sine die*?"},"1293797568186286103":{"questionID":"P000253","answers":["CALIGULA (POSSIBLY TIBERIUS)"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Oderint dum metuant**?"},"1293797573789880360":{"questionID":"P000017","answers":["CRUX SPES UNICA (\"THE CROSS IS THE ONLY HOPE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Notre Dame University*?"},"1293797618174132224":{"questionID":"P000017","answers":["CRUX SPES UNICA (\"THE CROSS IS THE ONLY HOPE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Notre Dame University*?"},"1293797625803309147":{"questionID":"P000249","answers":["OVID"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Tempus edax rerum**?"},"1293797635798470746":{"questionID":"P000023","answers":["PAX ET LUX (\"PEACE AND LIGHT\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Tufts University*?"},"1293797640869380097":{"questionID":"P000029","answers":["VIRTUTE ET ARMIS. (\"BY VALOR AND ARMS.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Mississippi*?"},"1293797645269205002":{"questionID":"P000057","answers":["CIVILITAS SUCCESSIT BARBARUM (\"CIVILIZATION SUCCEEDS BARBARISM\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Minnesota*?"},"1293797737346760744":{"questionID":"P000000","answers":["TERRAS IRRADIENT. (\"LET THEM ILLUMINATE THE EARTH.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Amherst College*?"},"1293797743101349939":{"questionID":"P000128","answers":["(PRO RE NATA) AS THE NEED ARISES"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *p.r.n.*?"},"1293797757731213412":{"questionID":"P000252","answers":["TO ERR IS HUMAN"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Errare humanum est**."},"1293798052422881280":{"questionID":"P000213","answers":["AUGUSTUS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Acta est fabula**?"},"1293798062279626793":{"questionID":"P000045","answers":["REGNAT POPULUS (\"THE PEOPLE RULE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Arkansas*?"},"1293798366399959083":{"questionID":"P000175","answers":["IN THE PLACE OF A PARENT"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *in loco parentis*?"},"1293798393042173962":{"questionID":"P000041","answers":["PER VIRTUTEM VIS (\"STRENGTH THROUGH VIRTUE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Washington University*?"},"1293798398994026529":{"questionID":"P000072","answers":["URBS IN HORTO (\"CITY IN A GARDEN\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Chicago*?"},"1293798404765253632":{"questionID":"P000230","answers":["THERE'S NO GREATER HONOR THAN TO DIE FOR ONE'S COUNTRY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Dulce et decorum est pro patria mori**."},"1293798409081458740":{"questionID":"P000220","answers":["CROSSING THE RUBICON"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Before what major event did Caesar say **Alea iacta est**?"},"1293798415850803201":{"questionID":"P000151","answers":["FROM THE BEGINNING"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *ab initio*?"},"1293798427531939892":{"questionID":"P000209","answers":["BY WAY OF"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *via*?"},"1293798522851954698":{"questionID":"P000171","answers":["THEREFORE, LET US REJOICE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Gaudeamus igitur*?"},"1293798561015664691":{"questionID":"P000033","answers":["CIVI ET REI PUBLICAE (\"FOR THE CITIZEN AND THE STATE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Oklahoma*?"},"1293798576941563914":{"questionID":"P000099","answers":["(QUANTUM SUFFICIAT) AS MUCH AS NEEDED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *q.s.*?"},"1293798584268886046":{"questionID":"P000102","answers":["(SEMEL IN DIE) ONCE A DAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *s.i.d.*?"},"1293798588916305953":{"questionID":"P000148","answers":["ON THE RIGHT"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *a dextra*?"},"1293798948477337650":{"questionID":"P000238","answers":["IT IS NOT DIFFICULT TO WRITE SATIRE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Dificile est saturam non scribere**."},"1293798985068183563":{"questionID":"P000137","answers":["(SENATUS POPULUSQUE ROMANUS) THE SENATE AND POPULACE OF ROME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *S.P.Q.R.*?"},"1293799009177174036":{"questionID":"P000155","answers":["AGAINST THE MAN"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *ad hominem*?"},"1293799017603665982":{"questionID":"P000189","answers":["AN UNWELCOME PERSON"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Persona non grata*?"},"1293799024138256454":{"questionID":"P000182","answers":["WITH THE NECESSARY CHANGES HAVING BEEN MADE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *mutatis mutandis*?"},"1293799029704097823":{"questionID":"P000205","answers":["ALL THE WAY UP TO"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Usque ad*?"},"1293799033759858739":{"questionID":"P000039","answers":["LUX SIT. (\"LET THERE BE LIGHT.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Washington*?"},"1293799038306746410":{"questionID":"P000180","answers":["A SLIP OF THE TONGUE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *lapsus linguae*?"},"1293799044014936107":{"questionID":"P000217","answers":["THE BATTLE OF ZELA"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"After what battle did Caesar say **Veni, vidi, vici**?"},"1293799096724754513":{"questionID":"P000106","answers":["(ANTE MERIDIEM) BEFORE MIDDAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *A.M.*?"},"1293799107588128809":{"questionID":"P000118","answers":["(FLORUIT) PERIOD OF TIME DURING WHICH A PERSON OR THING FLOURISHED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *fl.*?"},"1293799115225956414":{"questionID":"P000189","answers":["AN UNWELCOME PERSON"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Persona non grata*?"},"1293799122893017184":{"questionID":"P000113","answers":["(ET ALIA) AND OTHERS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *et al.*?"},"1293799134373089291":{"questionID":"P000196","answers":["WITHOUT DELAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Sine mora*?"},"1293799173887623190":{"questionID":"P000251","answers":["SENECA"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Errare humanum est**?"},"1293799185270964316":{"questionID":"P000180","answers":["A SLIP OF THE TONGUE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *lapsus linguae*?"},"1293799193940328489":{"questionID":"P000028","answers":["ARTES, SCIENTIA, VERITAS. (\"THE ARTS, KNOWLEDGE, TRUTH.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Michigan*?"},"1293799209891397663":{"questionID":"P000168","answers":["BY RIGHT","LEGALLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *De jure*?"},"1293799217386487818":{"questionID":"P000094","answers":["(OCULUS DEXTER) RIGHT EYE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *o.d.*?"},"1293799414212853790":{"questionID":"P000006","answers":["IN LUMINE TUO VIDEBIMUS LUMEN. (\"IN THY LIGHT, WE SHALL SEE LIGHT.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Columbia University*?"},"1293799422429237331":{"questionID":"P000019","answers":["DEI SUB NUMINE VIGET (\"IT FLOURISHES UNDER THE WILL OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Princeton University*?"},"1293800136203309066":{"questionID":"P000236","answers":["ALL THAT WORK AND NOTHING TO SHOW FOR IT"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **parturient montes, nasceture ridiculus mus**."},"1293800144285859840":{"questionID":"P000049","answers":["IUSTITIA OMNIBUS (\"JUSTICE FOR ALL.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *District of Columbia*?"},"1293800558078988367":{"questionID":"P000221","answers":["CATO THE ELDER"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Delenda est Carthago**?"},"1293800587330322493":{"questionID":"F000613","answers":["THEBES"],"genus":"myth","question":"What was the leading city of Boeotia?"},"1293800599862902856":{"questionID":"F001376","answers":["IO"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the sister of Phoroneus?"},"1293800606363815977":{"questionID":"F001022","answers":["ANTILOCHUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What son of Nestor fought at Troy?"},"1293800616761622599":{"questionID":"F001167","answers":["SLAUGHTERED SHEEP"],"genus":"myth","question":"What did Ajax the Greater do in his madness?"},"1293800664291475486":{"questionID":"F000864","answers":["ATHENA"],"genus":"myth","question":"What goddess appears to help expedite Orestes and Iphigenia's escape from Tauris?"},"1293801290589143133":{"questionID":"F000844","answers":["BATH"],"genus":"myth","question":"Where was Agamemnon when he was killed, according to the usual account?"},"1293801302668738652":{"questionID":"F002308","answers":["LABYRINTH"],"genus":"myth","question":"The inhabitants of Delos, commemorating the visit of Theseus danced in intricate patterns in order to imitate the windings of what Cretan structure?"},"1293801438866178118":{"questionID":"F001441","answers":["ARGUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was sent to guard Io?"},"1293802345989279794":{"questionID":"F001357","answers":["ODYSSEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who carried an oar until people thought it was a winnowing fan?"},"1293802362636603464":{"questionID":"F001266","answers":["MARON"],"genus":"myth","question":"What priest of Apollo was spared in Odysseus' attack of Ismarus?"},"1293802377610264576":{"questionID":"F000142","answers":["TROY"],"genus":"myth","question":"With what city's destiny was the Palladium tied?"},"1293802410581688360":{"questionID":"F001058","answers":["ACHILLES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was fated to live long and die ingloriously, or die young and gloriously?"},"1293802430831661077":{"questionID":"F001996","answers":["ACASTUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who hid the sword of Peleus on Mt. Pelion?"},"1293802455880044545":{"questionID":"F000346","answers":["MT. PARNASSUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"On the slopes of what mountain was the Delphic sanctuary?"},"1293802462557507654":{"questionID":"F000781","answers":["TIRESIAS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Whom did Jupiter and Juno consult to find out whether women or men had more fun?"},"1293802501786828821":{"questionID":"F001903","answers":["HECATE"],"genus":"myth","question":"According to Ovid, at whose shrine did Jason meet Medea?"},"1293802511307771914":{"questionID":"P000057","answers":["CIVILITAS SUCCESSIT BARBARUM (\"CIVILIZATION SUCCEEDS BARBARISM\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Minnesota*?"},"1293802602844127273":{"questionID":"F000309","answers":["SISTERS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What was the relationship of Asterie to Leto?"},"1293802647559868426":{"questionID":"P000091","answers":["(BIS IN DIE) TWICE A DAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *b.i.d.*?"},"1293802657806422128":{"questionID":"P000250","answers":["TIME, THE DEVOURER OF ALL THINGS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Tempus edax rerum**."},"1293802665486061588":{"questionID":"P000020","answers":["AD MAIOREM DEI GLORIAM (\"FOR THE GREATER GLORY OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *The Jesuit*?"},"1293802671043645461":{"questionID":"P000152","answers":["FROM THE EGG TO THE APPLE (\"FROM BEGINNING TO END\" OR \"FROM SOUP TO NUTS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *ab ovo usque ad mala*?"},"1293802742518644756":{"questionID":"P000144","answers":["WHERE THERE'S A WILL THERE'S A WAY (LIT. \"EITHER I'LL FIND A WAY OR MAKE ONE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *aut viam inveniam aut faciam*?"},"1293802745287020587":{"questionID":"F001225","answers":["NEREUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who told Menelaus how to return home safely?"},"1293802817353678888":{"questionID":"P000221","answers":["CATO THE ELDER"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Delenda est Carthago**?"},"1293802844293697599":{"questionID":"P000035","answers":["LEGES SINE MORIBUS VANAE (\"LAWS WITHOUT MORALS ARE USELESS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Pennsylvania*?"},"1293802878120628245":{"questionID":"P000250","answers":["TIME, THE DEVOURER OF ALL THINGS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Tempus edax rerum**."},"1293802886215499816":{"questionID":"P000132","answers":["(QUOD ERAT DEMONSTRANDUM) THAT WHICH WAS TO BE BE SHOWN"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *Q.E.D.*?"},"1293802891806507058":{"questionID":"P000234","answers":["I HAVE RAISED A MONUMENT MORE LASTING THAN BRONZE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Exegi monumentum aere perennius**."},"1293802896864968766":{"questionID":"P000229","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Dulce et decorum est pro patria mori**?"},"1293802907602259988":{"questionID":"P000116","answers":["(FIDEI DEFENSOR) DEFENDER OF THE FAITH (A TITLE OF THE BRITISH MONARCHS)"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *F.D.*?"},"1293802912861917245":{"questionID":"F000080","answers":["PONTUS AND GE"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who were the parents of Charybdis?"},"1293802921380544523":{"questionID":"F001920","answers":["3","THREE"],"genus":"myth","question":"How many times did Talus walk around Crete each day?"},"1293802940079017994":{"questionID":"P000018","answers":["DOMINUS ILLUMINATIO MEA (\"THE LORD IS MY LIGHT\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Oxford University*?"},"1293802949214081219":{"questionID":"P000004","answers":["DEUS LUX MEA (\"GOD IS MY LIGHT\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Catholic University of America*?"},"1293802951026147409":{"questionID":"P000243","answers":["JUVENAL"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Quis custodiet ipsos custodes?**?"},"1293802955320983604":{"questionID":"P000218","answers":["CAESAR"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Alea iacta est**?"},"1293802962556031017":{"questionID":"P000218","answers":["CAESAR"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Alea iacta est**?"},"1293802969313185863":{"questionID":"P000091","answers":["(BIS IN DIE) TWICE A DAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *b.i.d.*?"},"1293802974317121566":{"questionID":"P000092","answers":["(GUTTAE) DROPS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *g.t.t.*?"},"1293802979127984191":{"questionID":"P000081","answers":["DUM VIVIMUS VIVAMUS (\"WHILE WE LIVE LET US LIVE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Epicureans*?"},"1293802984710340639":{"questionID":"P000009","answers":["DEUS NOBIS FIDUCIA (\"GOD IS OUR TRUST\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *George Washington University*?"},"1293802990662320138":{"questionID":"P000093","answers":["(HORA SOMNI) AT BEDTIME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *h.s.*?"},"1293803140679860255":{"questionID":"P000092","answers":["(GUTTAE) DROPS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *g.t.t.*?"},"1293803146572857395":{"questionID":"P000212","answers":["MAKE HASTE SLOWLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Festina lente**."},"1293803149156548659":{"questionID":"P000250","answers":["TIME, THE DEVOURER OF ALL THINGS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Tempus edax rerum**."},"1293803162624462902":{"questionID":"P000075","answers":["FLUCTUAT NEC MERGITUR (\"IT IS TOSSED BY THE WAVES BUT DOES NOT SINK\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Paris*?"},"1293803209974091807":{"questionID":"F000940","answers":["TEUCER"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the child of Hesione and Laomedon?"},"1293803262469865543":{"questionID":"P000018","answers":["DOMINUS ILLUMINATIO MEA (\"THE LORD IS MY LIGHT\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Oxford University*?"},"1293803270430658591":{"questionID":"P000007","answers":["VOX CLAMANTIS IN DESERTO. (\"A VOICE OF ONE CRYING IN THE WILDERNESS.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Dartmouth College*?"},"1293803389192503296":{"questionID":"F001163","answers":["ACHILLES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Whose ghost appears to the Greeks after Troy's fall to demand sacrifice?"},"1293803401573830733":{"questionID":"F000345","answers":["DELPHINIUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What epithet of Apollo associates him with dolphins?"},"1293803403637686272":{"questionID":"P000108","answers":["(CETERIS PARIBUS) WITH OTHER THINGS BEING EQUAL"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *Cet. Par.*?"},"1293803412156059698":{"questionID":"F001242","answers":["MEDA"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the wife of Idomeneus?"},"1293803419987083326":{"questionID":"F001268","answers":["LAND OF THE LOTUS-EATERS"],"genus":"myth","question":"To whose land did Odysseus go after the Cicones?"},"1293803427578777640":{"questionID":"F002061","answers":["TROPHONIUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the brother of Agamedes?"},"1293803465377710133":{"questionID":"P000039","answers":["LUX SIT. (\"LET THERE BE LIGHT.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Washington*?"},"1293803519391830076":{"questionID":"P000137","answers":["(SENATUS POPULUSQUE ROMANUS) THE SENATE AND POPULACE OF ROME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *S.P.Q.R.*?"},"1293803530141827094":{"questionID":"P000077","answers":["SEMPER PARATUS (\"ALWAYS READY\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Coast Guard*?"},"1293803639600709653":{"questionID":"F001465","answers":["PTERELAUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What king of the Teleboans fought Electryon of Mycenae?"},"1293803649205796954":{"questionID":"F000173","answers":["APHRODITE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What deity did the city of Paphos honor above all others?"},"1293803666062442506":{"questionID":"F000675","answers":["HAEMON"],"genus":"myth","question":"What son of Creon was engaged to Antigone?"},"1293803678733697034":{"questionID":"P000016","answers":["QUAECUM SUNT VERA (\"WHATEVER IS TRUE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Northwestern University*?"},"1293803688480997376":{"questionID":"P000020","answers":["AD MAIOREM DEI GLORIAM (\"FOR THE GREATER GLORY OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *The Jesuit*?"},"1293803695481425970":{"questionID":"P000016","answers":["QUAECUM SUNT VERA (\"WHATEVER IS TRUE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Northwestern University*?"},"1293803702540435538":{"questionID":"P000125","answers":["(MODUS OPERANDI) WAY OF OPERATING"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *m.o.*?"},"1293804140601933845":{"questionID":"P000037","answers":["ECCE QUAM BONAM (\"BEHOLD HOW GOOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of the South (Sewanee)*?"},"1293804150060224512":{"questionID":"P000234","answers":["I HAVE RAISED A MONUMENT MORE LASTING THAN BRONZE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Exegi monumentum aere perennius**."},"1293804319539204110":{"questionID":"P000203","answers":["A CLEAN SLATE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *tabula rasa*?"},"1293804452633120859":{"questionID":"P000137","answers":["(SENATUS POPULUSQUE ROMANUS) THE SENATE AND POPULACE OF ROME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *S.P.Q.R.*?"},"1293804493003165748":{"questionID":"P000029","answers":["VIRTUTE ET ARMIS. (\"BY VALOR AND ARMS.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Mississippi*?"},"1293804502494875689":{"questionID":"P000133","answers":["(SCILICET) ACTUALLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *sc.*?"},"1293804687749025863":{"questionID":"P000001","answers":["PRO ECCLESIA, PRO TEXANA (\"FOR CHURCH, FOR TEXAS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Baylor University*?"},"1293804697425018912":{"questionID":"P000028","answers":["ARTES, SCIENTIA, VERITAS. (\"THE ARTS, KNOWLEDGE, TRUTH.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Michigan*?"},"1293804918368370699":{"questionID":"P000239","answers":["JUVENAL"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Mens sana in corpore sano**?"},"1293805141333512262":{"questionID":"P000022","answers":["NON SIBI, SED SUIS. (\"NOT FOR HERSELF, BUT FOR HER OWN.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Tulane University*?"},"1293805160631373855":{"questionID":"P000207","answers":["WOE TO THE CONQUERED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *vae victis*?"},"1293805176708141076":{"questionID":"P000021","answers":["PRO ECCLESIA ET PATRIA. (\"FOR CHURCH AND COUNTRY.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Trinity College*?"},"1293805303040839680":{"questionID":"P000178","answers":["IN WINE, THE TRUTH"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *In vino veritas*?"},"1293805317376970786":{"questionID":"P000025","answers":["CRESCAT SCIENTIA, VITA EXCOLATUR (\"LET KNOWLEDGE INCREASE, LET LIFE BE PERFECTED\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Chicago*?"},"1293805323244666943":{"questionID":"P000195","answers":["INDEFINITELY","WITHOUT SETTING A DAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *sine die*?"},"1293805331046207519":{"questionID":"P000041","answers":["PER VIRTUTEM VIS (\"STRENGTH THROUGH VIRTUE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Washington University*?"},"1293805341179641950":{"questionID":"P000211","answers":["AUGUSTUS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Festina lente**?"},"1293805349278584925":{"questionID":"P000180","answers":["A SLIP OF THE TONGUE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *lapsus linguae*?"},"1293805357587632241":{"questionID":"P000140","answers":["(VIDELICET) NAMELY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *viz.*?"},"1293805455470100480":{"questionID":"P000230","answers":["THERE'S NO GREATER HONOR THAN TO DIE FOR ONE'S COUNTRY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Dulce et decorum est pro patria mori**."},"1293805464425070632":{"questionID":"P000040","answers":["PRO HUMANITATE (\"FOR HUMANITY\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Wake Forest Univesity*?"},"1293805493139279914":{"questionID":"P000110","answers":["(DECESSIT SINE PROLE) DEAD WITHOUT ISSUE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *d.s.p.*?"},"1293805677122158643":{"questionID":"P000032","answers":["LUX HOMINUM VITA. (\"LIGHT OF THE LIFE OF MEN.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of New Mexico*?"},"1293805685527547985":{"questionID":"P000254","answers":["LET THEM HATE ME PROVIDED THAT THEY FEAR ME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Oderint dum metuant**."},"1293805696936312883":{"questionID":"P000038","answers":["STUDIIS ET REBUS HONESTIS (\"BY HONORABLE PURSUITS AND DEEDS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Vermont*?"},"1293805703277842515":{"questionID":"P000223","answers":["CONSTANTINE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **In hoc signo vinces**?"},"1293805710932574260":{"questionID":"P000000","answers":["TERRAS IRRADIENT. (\"LET THEM ILLUMINATE THE EARTH.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Amherst College*?"},"1293805716301152289":{"questionID":"P000128","answers":["(PRO RE NATA) AS THE NEED ARISES"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *p.r.n.*?"},"1293805723565949019":{"questionID":"P000225","answers":["DESCARTES"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous person said **Cogito ergo sum**?"},"1293805731685990402":{"questionID":"P000248","answers":["FOOLS LAUGH AT THE LATIN LANGUAGE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Rident stolidi verba Latina**."},"1293805740204494889":{"questionID":"P000128","answers":["(PRO RE NATA) AS THE NEED ARISES"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *p.r.n.*?"},"1293805747309907993":{"questionID":"P000027","answers":["ET DOCERE ET RERUM EXQUIRERE CAUSAS (\"BOTH TO TEACH & TO INQUIRE INTO THE CAUSES OF THINGS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Georgia*?"},"1293805753143918674":{"questionID":"P000236","answers":["ALL THAT WORK AND NOTHING TO SHOW FOR IT"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **parturient montes, nasceture ridiculus mus**."},"1293805765437554718":{"questionID":"P000133","answers":["(SCILICET) ACTUALLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *sc.*?"},"1293805777018163231":{"questionID":"P000035","answers":["LEGES SINE MORIBUS VANAE (\"LAWS WITHOUT MORALS ARE USELESS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Pennsylvania*?"},"1293805895620231248":{"questionID":"P000150","answers":["FROM WHAT IS ALREADY KNOWN (LIT. \"FROM WHAT COMES BEFORE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *a priori*?"},"1293805905405546519":{"questionID":"P000019","answers":["DEI SUB NUMINE VIGET (\"IT FLOURISHES UNDER THE WILL OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Princeton University*?"},"1293805913366331392":{"questionID":"P000122","answers":["(IBIDEM) IN THE SAME PLACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *ibid.*?"},"1293805921532776478":{"questionID":"P000196","answers":["WITHOUT DELAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Sine mora*?"},"1293805927211991040":{"questionID":"F000662","answers":["THEBE"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the wife of Zethus?"},"1293805935709519946":{"questionID":"F001121","answers":["THROWN FROM WALLS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What happened to Astyanax when Troy was sacked?"},"1293805966873329734":{"questionID":"P000235","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **parturient montes, nasceture ridiculus mus**?"},"1293806004739506196":{"questionID":"LHALF005385","answers":["silvestris"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive singular** of *silvester* (belonging to a forest, woody)?"},"1293806034426794044":{"questionID":"LHALF003629","answers":["commodi"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter genitive singular** of *commodus* (proper, suitable)?"},"1293806196666531870":{"questionID":"LHALF005421","answers":["pedestres"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine accusative plural** of *pedester* (on foot, pedestrian)?"},"1293806283643686982":{"questionID":"P000124","answers":["(LOCO CITATO) IN A PREVIOUSLY CITED PLACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *loc. cit.*?"},"1293806298537918464":{"questionID":"P000243","answers":["JUVENAL"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Quis custodiet ipsos custodes?**?"},"1293806389554053181":{"questionID":"LHALF002854","answers":["magistratui"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *magistratus, magistratus* (magistracy)?"},"1293806410294890526":{"questionID":"P000075","answers":["FLUCTUAT NEC MERGITUR (\"IT IS TOSSED BY THE WAVES BUT DOES NOT SINK\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Paris*?"},"1293806411578343424":{"questionID":"LHALF005689","answers":["quodquam"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter accusative singular** of *quisquam* (any one, any thing)?"},"1293806425860083764":{"questionID":"LHALF004913","answers":["commune"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter accusative singular** of *communis* (common, public)?"},"1293806546001854575":{"questionID":"P000028","answers":["ARTES, SCIENTIA, VERITAS. (\"THE ARTS, KNOWLEDGE, TRUTH.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Michigan*?"},"1293806555027738684":{"questionID":"P000101","answers":["(RECIPE) TAKE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *Rx*?"},"1293806559587074080":{"questionID":"P000159","answers":["ANOTHER SELF"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *alter ego*?"},"1293806565014372405":{"questionID":"P000168","answers":["BY RIGHT","LEGALLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *De jure*?"},"1293806570202861608":{"questionID":"P000000","answers":["TERRAS IRRADIENT. (\"LET THEM ILLUMINATE THE EARTH.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Amherst College*?"},"1293806576380936204":{"questionID":"P000140","answers":["(VIDELICET) NAMELY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *viz.*?"},"1293806584127950898":{"questionID":"P000051","answers":["AD ASTRA PER ASPERA (\"TO THE STARS THROUGH DIFFICULTIES\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Kansas*?"},"1293806624217239552":{"questionID":"LHALF004491","answers":["pleno"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine dative singular** of *plenus* (full)?"},"1293806636795953195":{"questionID":"F000602","answers":["ARISTAEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was chasing Eurydice when she was killed?"},"1293807277958107157":{"questionID":"F002182","answers":["OVID"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who wrote the Heroides?"},"1293807288594727013":{"questionID":"F002110","answers":["SISYPHUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who, some say, seduced Anticleia before she married Laertes?"},"1293807296136347742":{"questionID":"F002124","answers":["ROLL BOULDER UPHILL"],"genus":"myth","question":"What was Sisyphus' punishment for telling on Zeus?"},"1293807587669704814":{"questionID":"F001048","answers":["ACHILLES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the greatest of the Greek warriors at Troy?"},"1293807650827407412":{"questionID":"F001066","answers":["TRUMPET BLAST"],"genus":"myth","question":"What led Achilles to take off his disguise as a girl and put on armor?"},"1293807662537900062":{"questionID":"F001076","answers":["AGAMEMNON KILLED SACRED STAG"],"genus":"myth","question":"Why did Artemis cause unfavorable winds for the Greeks at Aulis?"},"1293807669899038832":{"questionID":"F001347","answers":["PENELOPE"],"genus":"myth","question":"Whom does Homer describe as \"periphron\"?"},"1293807696658825290":{"questionID":"F001379","answers":["BELUS AND AGENOR"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who were the two sons of Libya?"},"1293807732771782748":{"questionID":"F002301","answers":["ARGUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What son of Arestor built the ship which allowed Jason to sail to Colchis?"},"1293807740514209876":{"questionID":"F001743","answers":["BLACK SEA"],"genus":"myth","question":"What is the Euxine Sea now called?"},"1293807746260406375":{"questionID":"F001045","answers":["ODYSSEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who vengefully contrived the death of Palamedes?"},"1293807755777540096":{"questionID":"F000416","answers":["DONKEY EARS"],"genus":"myth","question":"How did Apollo punish Midas for challenging his victory?"},"1293807890066571399":{"questionID":"F001111","answers":["CHRYSEIS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What priestess of Apollo was originally awarded to Agamemnon?"},"1293807901000859648":{"questionID":"F001366","answers":["INACHUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What river was the father of Phoroneus?"},"1293807913785098300":{"questionID":"F000729","answers":["NEMEAN GAMES"],"genus":"myth","question":"What games were celebrated in honor of the death of Opheltes?"},"1293807996551430174":{"questionID":"F001904","answers":["OVID"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who wrote the Metamorphoses?"},"1293808004327538688":{"questionID":"F001090","answers":["PHILOCTETES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who first guided the Greek fleet to the island of Chryse?"},"1293808010455552054":{"questionID":"F000636","answers":["ROBE"],"genus":"myth","question":"Besides a necklace, what other famous gift did Harmonia receive?"},"1293808045134184487":{"questionID":"F002231","answers":["BABYLON"],"genus":"myth","question":"In what city did Pyramus and Thisbe live?"},"1293808052406845500":{"questionID":"F002084","answers":["KILLED THEM IN QUARRELL"],"genus":"myth","question":"What did Meleager do to the uncles he offended by awarding Atalanta?"},"1293808079577808967":{"questionID":"F001069","answers":["STATIUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What Roman author wrote the Achilleid?"},"1293937711903801424":{"questionID":"F000210","answers":["CYBELE"],"genus":"myth","question":"From whose severed organ had the almond tree grown?"},"1293937691347652629":{"questionID":"F001281","answers":["GOLD/TREASURE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What did Odysseus' men believe was in the bag of Aeolus?"},"1293938166486798378":{"questionID":"F001410","answers":["CHRYSAOR"],"genus":"myth","question":"What creatures name meant \"he of the golden sword\"?"},"1293938182626349176":{"questionID":"F001997","answers":["CHIRON"],"genus":"myth","question":"What centaur protected Peleus when his sword was hidden?"},"1293938296740778087":{"questionID":"F001377","answers":["EPAPHUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the child of Io and Zeus?"},"1293938371021766669":{"questionID":"F001146","answers":["PENTHESILEA"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who led the Amazons at Troy?"},"1293938387677483069":{"questionID":"F000740","answers":["MENOECEUS II"],"genus":"myth","question":"Which of the Spartoi sacrificed himself to save Thebes?"},"1293938393591316590":{"questionID":"F002008","answers":["LUCIFER"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the Roman equivalent of Eosphoros?"},"1293938400776290405":{"questionID":"F001373","answers":["TIRYNS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What city was ruled by Proetus?"},"1293938411496800317":{"questionID":"F000900","answers":["APHAREUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Idas and Lynceus?"},"1293938418564337664":{"questionID":"F000677","answers":["EURYDICE (DIFFERENT FROM OPRHEUS')"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the wife of Creon?"},"1293938422594928711":{"questionID":"F000940","answers":["TEUCER"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the child of Hesione and Laomedon?"},"1293938428110573589":{"questionID":"F001103","answers":["HERACLES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Telephus, wounded by Achilles?"},"1293938433399717938":{"questionID":"F001439","answers":["IO"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was changed into a white cow by jealous Hera?"},"1293938486692413470":{"questionID":"F000081","answers":["ZEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who cast Charybdis into the sea with a thunderbolt?"},"1293945056641810533":{"questionID":"A000344","answers":["god"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What does the Greek word **theos (θεος)** mean?"},"1293950470183714948":{"questionID":"LHALF011567","answers":["perficitis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *perficio* (to achieve, complete, accomplish)?"},"1293955400902770729":{"questionID":"LFIFTH000734","answers":["aevo"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *aevum, aevi* (age, generation, period)?"},"1293955462613700670":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002801","answers":["utile"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter accusative singular** of *utilis* (useful)?"},"1293958302107041832":{"questionID":"LFIFTH006435","answers":["cessi"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *cedo* (to move; to happen, result)?"},"1293983196937064498":{"questionID":"LHALF001645","answers":["legem"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative singular** of *lex, legis* (law)?"},"1293983226536263894":{"questionID":"LHALF005284","answers":["utile"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter accusative singular** of *utilis* (useful)?"},"1293983161646186648":{"questionID":"LHALF011234","answers":["alunt"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *alo* (to feed, nourish)?"},"1293983360665784512":{"questionID":"LHALF000472","answers":["iuventas"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *iuventa, iuventae* (youth)?"},"1293993544687681648":{"questionID":"LHALF000616","answers":["aulam"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative singular** of *aula, aulae* (hall, palace)?"},"1293993506867642420":{"questionID":"LHALF002979","answers":["aestibus"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *aestus, aestus* (agitation, heat, tide)?"},"1293993525884620873":{"questionID":"LHALF009820","answers":["metuebant"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *metuo* (to fear, to be afraid of)?"},"1293993794718666824":{"questionID":"LFIFTH005802","answers":["imponitis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *impono* (to lay upon, impose)?"},"1294002062451015852":{"questionID":"LFIFTH003077","answers":["neutrius"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine genitive singular** of *neuter* (neither of two)?"},"1294002040611279010":{"questionID":"LFIFTH003678","answers":["pugnavisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *pugno* (to fight)?"},"1294002014358999091":{"questionID":"LFIFTH006845","answers":["ingrediunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *ingredior* (to go into, to enter)?"},"1294014419147423905":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004536","answers":["silet"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *sileo* (to keep silent, to be quiet)?"},"1294014469680136243":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004554","answers":["sedimus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *sedeo* (to sit)?"},"1294018777620549735":{"questionID":"LFIFTH001173","answers":["montes"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *mons, montis* (mountain)?"},"1294022431005999205":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002279","answers":["nimium"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter accusative singular** of *nimius* (excessive)?"},"1294022914844131379":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002339","answers":["pium"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter accusative singular** of *pius* (dutiful, pious, honest)?"},"1294056699979759726":{"questionID":"LHALF000627","answers":["animae"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *anima, animae* (breeze, breath, soul)?"},"1294056682011234420":{"questionID":"LHALF001083","answers":["otio"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *otium, otii* (leisure time)?"},"1294056726202683392":{"questionID":"LHALF006789","answers":["potavistis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *poto* (to drink)?"},"1294057378207236187":{"questionID":"LHALF009007","answers":["tetigi"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *tango* (to touch)?"},"1294057411912536125":{"questionID":"LHALF011262","answers":["egistis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *ago* (to lead, to drive, to do)?"},"1294057418065576057":{"questionID":"LHALF011425","answers":["sufficiebamus"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *sufficio* (to be sufficient)?"},"1294057721133273109":{"questionID":"LHALF005522","answers":["eae"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine nominative plural** of *is* (he, she, it; this, that)?"},"1294057913668862024":{"questionID":"LHALF011956","answers":["accipimus"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *accipio* (to receive)?"},"1294058073614192640":{"questionID":"P000182","answers":["WITH THE NECESSARY CHANGES HAVING BEEN MADE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *mutatis mutandis*?"},"1294058126890242048":{"questionID":"P000117","answers":["(FOLIIS) ON THE [FOLLOWING] PAGES"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *ff.*?"},"1294058179440939068":{"questionID":"P000205","answers":["ALL THE WAY UP TO"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Usque ad*?"},"1294058284440879134":{"questionID":"P000201","answers":["ONE OF A KIND"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *sui generis*?"},"1294058372609478696":{"questionID":"P000113","answers":["(ET ALIA) AND OTHERS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *et al.*?"},"1294058573474562149":{"questionID":"P000025","answers":["CRESCAT SCIENTIA, VITA EXCOLATUR (\"LET KNOWLEDGE INCREASE, LET LIFE BE PERFECTED\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Chicago*?"},"1294058585134858250":{"questionID":"P000192","answers":["HOW MUCH"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Quantum*?"},"1294058611147931678":{"questionID":"P000247","answers":["OVID"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Rident stolidi verba Latina**?"},"1294058847417274468":{"questionID":"P000098","answers":["(QUAQUE DIE) EVERYDAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *q.d.*?"},"1294058855218675795":{"questionID":"P000108","answers":["(CETERIS PARIBUS) WITH OTHER THINGS BEING EQUAL"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *Cet. Par.*?"},"1294088590254673961":{"questionID":"P000218","answers":["CAESAR"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Alea iacta est**?"},"1294091399494635541":{"questionID":"P000100","answers":["(QUOTIDIANUS) DAILY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *quot.*?"},"1294091410076602441":{"questionID":"P000039","answers":["LUX SIT. (\"LET THERE BE LIGHT.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Washington*?"},"1294091492071313449":{"questionID":"P000049","answers":["IUSTITIA OMNIBUS (\"JUSTICE FOR ALL.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *District of Columbia*?"},"1294091501495914496":{"questionID":"P000174","answers":["FOREVER"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *In aeternum*?"},"1294091623516602418":{"questionID":"P000080","answers":["AD MAIOREM DEI GLORIAM (\"FOR THE GREATER GLORY OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Society of Jesuits*?"},"1294091926135636019":{"questionID":"P000159","answers":["ANOTHER SELF"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *alter ego*?"},"1294091939481649172":{"questionID":"P000232","answers":["ALAS, THE FLEETING YEARS GLIDE BY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Eheu fugaces labuntur anni**."},"1294091946159112243":{"questionID":"P000254","answers":["LET THEM HATE ME PROVIDED THAT THEY FEAR ME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Oderint dum metuant**."},"1294091951687077920":{"questionID":"P000156","answers":["WITHOUT END"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Ad infinitum*?"},"1294091962336546848":{"questionID":"P000037","answers":["ECCE QUAM BONAM (\"BEHOLD HOW GOOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of the South (Sewanee)*?"},"1294091979772137482":{"questionID":"P000114","answers":["(ET SEQUENS) AND THE FOLLOWING"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *et seq.*?"},"1294091994741608529":{"questionID":"P000195","answers":["INDEFINITELY","WITHOUT SETTING A DAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *sine die*?"},"1294092307812978769":{"questionID":"P000223","answers":["CONSTANTINE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **In hoc signo vinces**?"},"1294092317023666286":{"questionID":"P000128","answers":["(PRO RE NATA) AS THE NEED ARISES"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *p.r.n.*?"},"1294092324455972956":{"questionID":"P000016","answers":["QUAECUM SUNT VERA (\"WHATEVER IS TRUE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Northwestern University*?"},"1294092330940235816":{"questionID":"P000016","answers":["QUAECUM SUNT VERA (\"WHATEVER IS TRUE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Northwestern University*?"},"1294092335705100328":{"questionID":"P000129","answers":["(PASSIM) EVERYWHERE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *pass.*?"},"1294092380009529397":{"questionID":"P000231","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Eheu fugaces labuntur anni**?"},"1294092387563475095":{"questionID":"P000202","answers":["SPONTANEOUSLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Suo motu*?"},"1294092473190318172":{"questionID":"P000038","answers":["STUDIIS ET REBUS HONESTIS (\"BY HONORABLE PURSUITS AND DEEDS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Vermont*?"},"1294092483399258202":{"questionID":"P000123","answers":["(INFRA DIGNITATEM) BENEATH ONE'S DIGNITY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *Infra. dig.*?"},"1294092491808833657":{"questionID":"P000002","answers":["NIL SINE MAGNO LABORE. (\"NOTHING WITHOUT GREAT EFFORT.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Brooklyn College*?"},"1294092498867847190":{"questionID":"P000106","answers":["(ANTE MERIDIEM) BEFORE MIDDAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *A.M.*?"},"1294092505608093898":{"questionID":"P000212","answers":["MAKE HASTE SLOWLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Festina lente**."},"1294092513656963142":{"questionID":"P000003","answers":["IN DEO SPERAMUS. (\"IN GOD WE TRUST.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Brown University*?"},"1294092520707330081":{"questionID":"P000025","answers":["CRESCAT SCIENTIA, VITA EXCOLATUR (\"LET KNOWLEDGE INCREASE, LET LIFE BE PERFECTED\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Chicago*?"},"1294092525732368465":{"questionID":"P000017","answers":["CRUX SPES UNICA (\"THE CROSS IS THE ONLY HOPE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Notre Dame University*?"},"1294092534989066440":{"questionID":"P000021","answers":["PRO ECCLESIA ET PATRIA. (\"FOR CHURCH AND COUNTRY.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Trinity College*?"},"1294092548444520488":{"questionID":"P000004","answers":["DEUS LUX MEA (\"GOD IS MY LIGHT\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Catholic University of America*?"},"1294092587959058493":{"questionID":"P000111","answers":["(DEO VOLENTE) GOD WILLING"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *D.V.*?"},"1294092594984390797":{"questionID":"P000101","answers":["(RECIPE) TAKE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *Rx*?"},"1294092602399785000":{"questionID":"P000108","answers":["(CETERIS PARIBUS) WITH OTHER THINGS BEING EQUAL"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *Cet. Par.*?"},"1294092609194561690":{"questionID":"P000152","answers":["FROM THE EGG TO THE APPLE (\"FROM BEGINNING TO END\" OR \"FROM SOUP TO NUTS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *ab ovo usque ad mala*?"},"1294092615104593930":{"questionID":"P000221","answers":["CATO THE ELDER"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Delenda est Carthago**?"},"1294092781928845342":{"questionID":"P000020","answers":["AD MAIOREM DEI GLORIAM (\"FOR THE GREATER GLORY OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *The Jesuit*?"},"1294092861926805527":{"questionID":"P000251","answers":["SENECA"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Errare humanum est**?"},"1294092996391735349":{"questionID":"P000030","answers":["SALUS POPULI. (\"THE WELFARE OF THE PEOPLE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Missouri*?"},"1294093003530440767":{"questionID":"P000203","answers":["A CLEAN SLATE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *tabula rasa*?"},"1294093009964503210":{"questionID":"P000213","answers":["AUGUSTUS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Acta est fabula**?"},"1294093015396122725":{"questionID":"P000181","answers":["A METHOD OF WORKING"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *modus operandi*?"},"1294093415926988861":{"questionID":"P000113","answers":["(ET ALIA) AND OTHERS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *et al.*?"},"1294093425779413043":{"questionID":"P000005","answers":["RESPICE, ADSPICE, PROSPICE. (\"LOOK BACK, LOOK TO THE PRESENT, LOOK TO THE FUTURE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *City College of NY*?"},"1294093432892952657":{"questionID":"P000154","answers":["FOR THIS PURPOSE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *ad hoc*?"},"1294093438534287472":{"questionID":"P000192","answers":["HOW MUCH"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Quantum*?"},"1294093444053995581":{"questionID":"P000145","answers":["THERE IS NO ACCOUNTING FOR TASTE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *De gustibus non est disputandum*?"},"1294093449779216485":{"questionID":"P000231","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Eheu fugaces labuntur anni**?"},"1294093455122763846":{"questionID":"P000174","answers":["FOREVER"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *In aeternum*?"},"1294093623511617587":{"questionID":"P000192","answers":["HOW MUCH"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Quantum*?"},"1294093633393393714":{"questionID":"P000183","answers":["PERFECTION"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Ne plus ultra*?"},"1294093638984269846":{"questionID":"P000251","answers":["SENECA"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Errare humanum est**?"},"1294093645669990471":{"questionID":"P000237","answers":["JUVENAL"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Dificile est saturam non scribere**?"},"1294093664838094929":{"questionID":"P000096","answers":["(POST CIBOS) AFTER MEALS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *p.c.*?"},"1294093676871422024":{"questionID":"P000212","answers":["MAKE HASTE SLOWLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Festina lente**."},"1294093684018774027":{"questionID":"P000203","answers":["A CLEAN SLATE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *tabula rasa*?"},"1294093900327293049":{"questionID":"P000120","answers":["(FOLIO VERSO) ON THE LEFT HAND PAGE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *f.v.*?"},"1294093909684912158":{"questionID":"P000104","answers":["(TER IN DIE) THREE TIMES A DAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *t.i.d.*?"},"1294093997169704960":{"questionID":"P000085","answers":["\"HE LOOKS WITH FAVOR ON OUR UNDERTAKINGS\""],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate \"Annuit Coeptis,\" a Latin motto of the US."},"1294094011417755679":{"questionID":"P000179","answers":["BY THE VERY FACT ITSELF"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *ipso facto*?"},"1294094018958856336":{"questionID":"P000075","answers":["FLUCTUAT NEC MERGITUR (\"IT IS TOSSED BY THE WAVES BUT DOES NOT SINK\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Paris*?"},"1294094026995142666":{"questionID":"P000218","answers":["CAESAR"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Alea iacta est**?"},"1294094032347205704":{"questionID":"P000138","answers":["(VIDE INFRA) SEE BELOW"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *v.i.*?"},"1294094043428425778":{"questionID":"P000081","answers":["DUM VIVIMUS VIVAMUS (\"WHILE WE LIVE LET US LIVE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Epicureans*?"},"1294095152486420500":{"questionID":"P000163","answers":["BEWARE THE DOG"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Cave canem*?"},"1294095171327365201":{"questionID":"P000036","answers":["DISCIPLINA PRAESIDIUM CIVITATIS (\"INSTRUCTION IS THE SAFEGUARD OF THE STATE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Texas*?"},"1294095177522348072":{"questionID":"P000113","answers":["(ET ALIA) AND OTHERS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *et al.*?"},"1294095185344598137":{"questionID":"P000020","answers":["AD MAIOREM DEI GLORIAM (\"FOR THE GREATER GLORY OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *The Jesuit*?"},"1294095194513342486":{"questionID":"P000137","answers":["(SENATUS POPULUSQUE ROMANUS) THE SENATE AND POPULACE OF ROME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *S.P.Q.R.*?"},"1294095232467599412":{"questionID":"P000230","answers":["THERE'S NO GREATER HONOR THAN TO DIE FOR ONE'S COUNTRY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Dulce et decorum est pro patria mori**."},"1294095339485401098":{"questionID":"P000201","answers":["ONE OF A KIND"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *sui generis*?"},"1294095347374751885":{"questionID":"P000104","answers":["(TER IN DIE) THREE TIMES A DAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *t.i.d.*?"},"1294096091628703755":{"questionID":"P000229","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Dulce et decorum est pro patria mori**?"},"1294096123446825038":{"questionID":"P000168","answers":["BY RIGHT","LEGALLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *De jure*?"},"1294096129482297387":{"questionID":"P000101","answers":["(RECIPE) TAKE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *Rx*?"},"1294096135559839844":{"questionID":"P000133","answers":["(SCILICET) ACTUALLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *sc.*?"},"1294096146008113253":{"questionID":"P000203","answers":["A CLEAN SLATE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *tabula rasa*?"},"1294096216426287124":{"questionID":"P000000","answers":["TERRAS IRRADIENT. (\"LET THEM ILLUMINATE THE EARTH.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Amherst College*?"},"1294096250450477057":{"questionID":"P000171","answers":["THEREFORE, LET US REJOICE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Gaudeamus igitur*?"},"1294096301457276948":{"questionID":"P000071","answers":["SICUT PATRIBUS, SIT DEUS NOBIS (\"AS TO OUR FATHERS, MAY GOD BE TO US\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Boston*?"},"1294096310563246101":{"questionID":"P000124","answers":["(LOCO CITATO) IN A PREVIOUSLY CITED PLACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *loc. cit.*?"},"1294096332256182363":{"questionID":"P000133","answers":["(SCILICET) ACTUALLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *sc.*?"},"1294096359678414868":{"questionID":"P000156","answers":["WITHOUT END"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Ad infinitum*?"},"1294096372198408192":{"questionID":"P000124","answers":["(LOCO CITATO) IN A PREVIOUSLY CITED PLACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *loc. cit.*?"},"1294096378691321876":{"questionID":"P000108","answers":["(CETERIS PARIBUS) WITH OTHER THINGS BEING EQUAL"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *Cet. Par.*?"},"1294096382923116644":{"questionID":"P000223","answers":["CONSTANTINE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **In hoc signo vinces**?"},"1294096388262461515":{"questionID":"P000147","answers":["YOU HIT THE NAIL ON THE HEAD"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *rem acu tetigisti*?"},"1294096397989318706":{"questionID":"P000094","answers":["(OCULUS DEXTER) RIGHT EYE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *o.d.*?"},"1294096426300870699":{"questionID":"P000213","answers":["AUGUSTUS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Acta est fabula**?"},"1294096432407511224":{"questionID":"P000231","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Eheu fugaces labuntur anni**?"},"1294096438258827366":{"questionID":"P000139","answers":["(VIDE SUPER) SEE ABOVE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *v.s.*?"},"1294096447972577312":{"questionID":"P000160","answers":["WHISKEY / ALCOHOL"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *aqua vitae*?"},"1294096578105049188":{"questionID":"P000090","answers":["(ANTE CIBOS) BEFORE MEALS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *a.c.*?"},"1294096589639516252":{"questionID":"P000071","answers":["SICUT PATRIBUS, SIT DEUS NOBIS (\"AS TO OUR FATHERS, MAY GOD BE TO US\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Boston*?"},"1294096595805143112":{"questionID":"P000206","answers":["A CONSTANT COMPANION (GO WITH ME)"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *vade mecum*?"},"1294096602125832234":{"questionID":"P000098","answers":["(QUAQUE DIE) EVERYDAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *q.d.*?"},"1294096611055636571":{"questionID":"P000168","answers":["BY RIGHT","LEGALLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *De jure*?"},"1294096652407148614":{"questionID":"P000212","answers":["MAKE HASTE SLOWLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Festina lente**."},"1294096659269156884":{"questionID":"P000112","answers":["(EXEMPLI GRATIA) FOR [THE SAKE OF AN] EXAMPLE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *e.g.*?"},"1294096663203418192":{"questionID":"P000012","answers":["LUX ET VERITAS (\"LIGHT AND TRUTH\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Indiana University Bloomington*?"},"1294096669448732795":{"questionID":"P000247","answers":["OVID"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Rident stolidi verba Latina**?"},"1294096675400450058":{"questionID":"P000241","answers":["JUVENAL"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Panem et circenses**?"},"1294096687555547237":{"questionID":"P000034","answers":["MENS AGITAT MOLEM (\"MIND MOVES THE MASS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Oregon*?"},"1294096741410275349":{"questionID":"P000223","answers":["CONSTANTINE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **In hoc signo vinces**?"},"1294096749438304359":{"questionID":"P000015","answers":["PERSTARE ET PRAESTARE. (\"TO PRESERVE AND TO SURPASS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *New York University*?"},"1294096755591479326":{"questionID":"P000004","answers":["DEUS LUX MEA (\"GOD IS MY LIGHT\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Catholic University of America*?"},"1294096760276521042":{"questionID":"P000155","answers":["AGAINST THE MAN"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *ad hominem*?"},"1294097835100344410":{"questionID":"F000882","answers":["CILISSA"],"genus":"myth","question":"What nurse of Orestes safely secured his escape after Agamemnon's murder?"},"1294097846823288916":{"questionID":"F002162","answers":["POSEIDON"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Evadne?"},"1294097879270428693":{"questionID":"F002202","answers":["IPHIS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who hanged himself in sorrow at the door of Anaxarete?"},"1294098101321072750":{"questionID":"F002337","answers":["EUMAEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What Ithacan swineherd remained faithful to Odysseus?"},"1294098251292868731":{"questionID":"F002114","answers":["HERMES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Autolycus?"},"1294098261518450769":{"questionID":"F001214","answers":["MYKONOS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Near what island did Athena cause many of Ajax the Lesser's ships to wreck?"},"1294098880186810429":{"questionID":"P000008","answers":["SAPIENTIA ET DOCTRINA. (\"WISDOM AND KNOWLEDGE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Fordham University*?"},"1294098889070215258":{"questionID":"P000192","answers":["HOW MUCH"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Quantum*?"},"1294098904694132797":{"questionID":"P000033","answers":["CIVI ET REI PUBLICAE (\"FOR THE CITIZEN AND THE STATE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Oklahoma*?"},"1294098912248074250":{"questionID":"P000104","answers":["(TER IN DIE) THREE TIMES A DAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *t.i.d.*?"},"1294098937158041721":{"questionID":"P000152","answers":["FROM THE EGG TO THE APPLE (\"FROM BEGINNING TO END\" OR \"FROM SOUP TO NUTS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *ab ovo usque ad mala*?"},"1294099199587123231":{"questionID":"P000197","answers":["AN INDISPENSABLE CONDITION","A NECESSITY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *sine qua non*?"},"1294099208973979749":{"questionID":"P000019","answers":["DEI SUB NUMINE VIGET (\"IT FLOURISHES UNDER THE WILL OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Princeton University*?"},"1294099250807967815":{"questionID":"P000226","answers":["I THINK THEREFORE I AM"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Cogito ergo sum**."},"1294099284937146450":{"questionID":"P000143","answers":["NEVER, OR WHEN HELL FREEZES OVER (LIT. \"AT THE GREEK CALENDS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *ad kalendas graecas*?"},"1294099296890781719":{"questionID":"P000168","answers":["BY RIGHT","LEGALLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *De jure*?"},"1294099357221650504":{"questionID":"P000033","answers":["CIVI ET REI PUBLICAE (\"FOR THE CITIZEN AND THE STATE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Oklahoma*?"},"1294099366256050176":{"questionID":"P000025","answers":["CRESCAT SCIENTIA, VITA EXCOLATUR (\"LET KNOWLEDGE INCREASE, LET LIFE BE PERFECTED\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Chicago*?"},"1294099372409098281":{"questionID":"P000021","answers":["PRO ECCLESIA ET PATRIA. (\"FOR CHURCH AND COUNTRY.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Trinity College*?"},"1294099377325084713":{"questionID":"P000071","answers":["SICUT PATRIBUS, SIT DEUS NOBIS (\"AS TO OUR FATHERS, MAY GOD BE TO US\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Boston*?"},"1294099382098067486":{"questionID":"P000037","answers":["ECCE QUAM BONAM (\"BEHOLD HOW GOOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of the South (Sewanee)*?"},"1294099387642937415":{"questionID":"P000137","answers":["(SENATUS POPULUSQUE ROMANUS) THE SENATE AND POPULACE OF ROME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *S.P.Q.R.*?"},"1294099452872753172":{"questionID":"P000172","answers":["A WRIT TO BRING A DETAINED PERSON BEFORE A JUDGE (LIT. \"YOU MUST HAVE THE BODY\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Habeas corpus*?"},"1294099566999638129":{"questionID":"P000197","answers":["AN INDISPENSABLE CONDITION","A NECESSITY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *sine qua non*?"},"1294099695794257982":{"questionID":"P000132","answers":["(QUOD ERAT DEMONSTRANDUM) THAT WHICH WAS TO BE BE SHOWN"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *Q.E.D.*?"},"1294099714584744057":{"questionID":"P000129","answers":["(PASSIM) EVERYWHERE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *pass.*?"},"1294099748961259520":{"questionID":"P000231","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Eheu fugaces labuntur anni**?"},"1294099755810684991":{"questionID":"P000089","answers":["DIS MINIBUS (\"TO THE SPIRITS OF THE DEAD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *D.M.*?"},"1294099947058233364":{"questionID":"F001252","answers":["ANDROMACHE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What Trojan widow accompanied Neoptolemus home from Troy?"},"1294099957426684026":{"questionID":"F000455","answers":["415 BC"],"genus":"myth","question":"In what year was Alcibiades charged with defiling Herms?"},"1294099965479747614":{"questionID":"F001561","answers":["NETS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What did Heracles use to catch the Erymanthian Boar?"},"1294118181559865384":{"questionID":"A000272","answers":["demos (δημος), the people"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **epidemic**?"},"1294118215236190299":{"questionID":"A000612","answers":["phagein (φαγειν), to eat"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **esophagus**?"},"1294125485533691937":{"questionID":"A000140","answers":["baino (βαινω), to walk, step"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **basement**?"},"1294128392697937920":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002977","answers":["quo"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter ablative singular** of *qui* (who, which, what; who? which? what?)?"},"1294156484325937163":{"questionID":"LHALF009108","answers":["serebant"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *sero* (to sow, plant)?"},"1294157105594499156":{"questionID":"LHALF006863","answers":["parant"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *paro* (to prepare, provide)?"},"1294157218832322560":{"questionID":"LHALF009402","answers":["proposuerunt"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *propono* (to put forth, declare, propose)?"},"1294157431785525248":{"questionID":"LHALF008019","answers":["sustinuit"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *sustineo* (to support, sustain)?"},"1294157632604733452":{"questionID":"LHALF007991","answers":["tacemus"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *taceo* (to be silent)?"},"1294157650979979274":{"questionID":"LHALF007830","answers":["amaverunt"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *amo* (to love)?"},"1294157659234107403":{"questionID":"LHALF006807","answers":["postulaverunt"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *postulo* (to ask, demand, summon)?"},"1294157843804459009":{"questionID":"LHALF009389","answers":["proponitis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *propono* (to put forth, declare, propose)?"},"1294157857503318157":{"questionID":"LHALF011255","answers":["agebamus"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *ago* (to lead, to drive, to do)?"},"1294157878642475088":{"questionID":"LHALF010241","answers":["favit"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *faveo* (to be favorable or inclined towards)?"},"1294157892118908978":{"questionID":"LHALF009806","answers":["misit"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *mitto* (to send, throw)?"},"1294157932623171584":{"questionID":"LHALF009903","answers":["laesimus"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *laedo* (to hurt, wound, annoy)?"},"1294157948905459743":{"questionID":"LHALF006321","answers":["vulgavi"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *vulgo* (to spread, to make known)?"},"1294158051590275182":{"questionID":"LHALF011273","answers":["agnoscebatis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *agnosco* (to recognize; to admit)?"},"1294158108154921040":{"questionID":"LHALF007793","answers":["arbitrabat"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *arbitror* (to believe, to make a decision)?"},"1294158117713612800":{"questionID":"LHALF011506","answers":["rapiebant"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *rapio* (to seize, rob, snatch)?"},"1294158180393160766":{"questionID":"LHALF008871","answers":["ussi"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *uro* (to burn)?"},"1294158344948289536":{"questionID":"LHALF007378","answers":["firmaverunt"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *firmo* (to make firm, strengthen fortify)?"},"1294158716777795634":{"questionID":"LHALF008703","answers":["censebat"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *censeo* (to assess, estimate; to propose, vote)?"},"1294158765481918475":{"questionID":"LHALF009985","answers":["instruebas"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *instruo* (to set in order, equip; to teach, instruct)?"},"1294158773669068892":{"questionID":"LHALF006235","answers":["afferebant"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *affero* (to bring to; to allege, assert)?"},"1294158781915074571":{"questionID":"LHALF007573","answers":["damnavit"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *damno* (to condemn)?"},"1294158869689536562":{"questionID":"LHALF008128","answers":["respondebatis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *respondeo* (to answer)?"},"1294158879667654716":{"questionID":"LHALF011071","answers":["carpebam"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *carpo* (to pick, pluck, crop)?"},"1294158887938691165":{"questionID":"LHALF006575","answers":["significaverunt"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *significo* (to show; to mean, signify)?"},"1294159002418020382":{"questionID":"LHALF006630","answers":["revocatis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *revoco* (to call back)?"},"1294159011792293939":{"questionID":"LHALF010256","answers":["fefelli"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *fallo* (to deceive, cheat, disappoint)?"},"1294159023507247135":{"questionID":"LHALF010402","answers":["ducunt"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *duco* (to lead, conduct)?"},"1294159065747951696":{"questionID":"LHALF011225","answers":["amisisti"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *amitto* (to lose)?"},"1294159074279030815":{"questionID":"LHALF007296","answers":["imperabat"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *impero* (to command, order)?"},"1294159657748922474":{"questionID":"LHALF006307","answers":["abivimus"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *abeo* (to go away, depart)?"},"1294159774069559389":{"questionID":"LHALF008896","answers":["trahimus"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *traho* (to draw, drag)?"},"1294159787784667168":{"questionID":"LHALF006262","answers":["aditis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *adeo* (to go to, approach)?"},"1294160015149498390":{"questionID":"LHALF006911","answers":["optat"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *opto* (to choose, to wish)?"},"1294160030475485194":{"questionID":"LHALF007953","answers":["torsistis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *torqueo* (to twist, turn, torture)?"},"1294160121521377382":{"questionID":"LHALF008456","answers":["iussimus"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *iubeo* (to command, order)?"},"1294160159387422771":{"questionID":"LHALF011516","answers":["proficitis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *proficio* (to go on, to make progress)?"},"1294160324835934240":{"questionID":"LHALF008634","answers":["egebas"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *egeo* (to need, lack)?"},"1294160333870596137":{"questionID":"LHALF005094","answers":["ingentes"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *ingens* (huge)?"},"1294345845659009054":{"questionID":"A000705","answers":["water... hydor (ὑδωρ)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **formaldehyde**?"},"1294346822499700838":{"questionID":"LHALF008186","answers":["praebuerunt"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *praebeo* (to give, offer)?"},"1294347413414346845":{"questionID":"LHALF007795","answers":["arbitrabatis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *arbitror* (to believe, to make a decision)?"},"1294347449971904572":{"questionID":"LHALF011880","answers":["cupivi"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *cupio* (to desire, to wish)?"},"1294347849907179541":{"questionID":"LHALF008594","answers":["flevi"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *fleo* (to weep, cry)?"},"1294348003364306965":{"questionID":"LHALF001261","answers":["incendia"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *incendium, incendii* (fire)?"},"1294348365282414653":{"questionID":"LHALF006469","answers":["temptavisti"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *tempto* (to handle, touch; to attempt)?"},"1294349672529399868":{"questionID":"A000158","answers":["ballo (βαλλω), throw"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **parable**?"},"1294352939552477185":{"questionID":"A000210","answers":["homos (ὁμος), one and the same, like","genos (γενος), race, offspring, kind"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **homogeneous**?"},"1294352958116335678":{"questionID":"A000198","answers":["monos (μονος), alone","gamos (γαμος), wedding, marriage"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **monogamous**?"},"1294352975904379011":{"questionID":"A000249","answers":["to draw, write, describe... grapho (γραφω)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **epigram**?"},"1294352996100214824":{"questionID":"A000088","answers":["archo (αρχω), to lead, rule, be the first, begin"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **archipelago**?"},"1294355748997824533":{"questionID":"A000107","answers":["aster (αστηρ)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What Greek word means **star**?"},"1294376113136734401":{"questionID":"A000177","answers":["biblos (βιβλος)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What Greek word means **book**?"},"1294376405710405652":{"questionID":"A000473","answers":["little, small... micros (μικρος)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **microcosm**?"},"1294400731633156096":{"questionID":"A000268","answers":["grapho (γραφω), to draw, write, describe"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **telegram**?"},"1294400773253234820":{"questionID":"A000423","answers":["krypto (κρυπτω)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What Greek word means **to hide**?"},"1294400753992994825":{"questionID":"A000661","answers":["stretch out, strain... teino (τεινω)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **tendon**?"},"1294400866182496287":{"questionID":"A000055","answers":["another... allos (αλλος)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **parallel**?"},"1294422438968561755":{"questionID":"P000222","answers":["CARTHAGE MUST BE DESTROYED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Delenda est Carthago**."},"1294422497416183969":{"questionID":"P000251","answers":["SENECA"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Errare humanum est**?"},"1294427323508064317":{"questionID":"A000206","answers":["genos (γενος), race, offspring, kind"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **genesis**?"},"1294427288279973908":{"questionID":"A000673","answers":["cut, divide... temno (τεμνω)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **atom**?"},"1294427400376946780":{"questionID":"A000626","answers":["micros (μικρος), little, small","skopeo (σκοπεω), behold, examine, inspect, consider, see"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **microscope**?"},"1294451718263930911":{"questionID":"LHALF011596","answers":["percussistis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *percutio* (to strike; to kill)?"},"1294452375796322336":{"questionID":"P000036","answers":["DISCIPLINA PRAESIDIUM CIVITATIS (\"INSTRUCTION IS THE SAFEGUARD OF THE STATE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Texas*?"},"1294452391017578556":{"questionID":"P000183","answers":["PERFECTION"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Ne plus ultra*?"},"1294452418720960512":{"questionID":"P000146","answers":["SPEAK ONLY GOOD OF THE DEAD"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *De mortuis nil nisi bonum*?"},"1294452445136814122":{"questionID":"P000239","answers":["JUVENAL"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Mens sana in corpore sano**?"},"1294452452028055562":{"questionID":"P000221","answers":["CATO THE ELDER"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Delenda est Carthago**?"},"1294452458059468840":{"questionID":"P000223","answers":["CONSTANTINE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **In hoc signo vinces**?"},"1294452468700282912":{"questionID":"P000172","answers":["A WRIT TO BRING A DETAINED PERSON BEFORE A JUDGE (LIT. \"YOU MUST HAVE THE BODY\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Habeas corpus*?"},"1294452555325374607":{"questionID":"P000073","answers":["SPERAMUS MELIORA, RESURGET CINERIBUS (\"WE HOPE FOR BETTER THINGS, IT WILL RISE FROM THE ASHES\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Detroit*?"},"1294452573872590868":{"questionID":"P000231","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Eheu fugaces labuntur anni**?"},"1294452647683690506":{"questionID":"P000032","answers":["LUX HOMINUM VITA. (\"LIGHT OF THE LIFE OF MEN.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of New Mexico*?"},"1294452658450595890":{"questionID":"P000160","answers":["WHISKEY / ALCOHOL"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *aqua vitae*?"},"1294452668533575761":{"questionID":"P000011","answers":["MIHI CURA FUTURI. (\"MY ANXIETY IS FOR THE FUTURE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Hunter College*?"},"1294452688058191955":{"questionID":"P000195","answers":["INDEFINITELY","WITHOUT SETTING A DAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *sine die*?"},"1294453274895978519":{"questionID":"P000020","answers":["AD MAIOREM DEI GLORIAM (\"FOR THE GREATER GLORY OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *The Jesuit*?"},"1294453283196371076":{"questionID":"P000072","answers":["URBS IN HORTO (\"CITY IN A GARDEN\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Chicago*?"},"1294453290507177995":{"questionID":"P000143","answers":["NEVER, OR WHEN HELL FREEZES OVER (LIT. \"AT THE GREEK CALENDS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *ad kalendas graecas*?"},"1294453302527791214":{"questionID":"P000030","answers":["SALUS POPULI. (\"THE WELFARE OF THE PEOPLE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Missouri*?"},"1294453309142339685":{"questionID":"P000116","answers":["(FIDEI DEFENSOR) DEFENDER OF THE FAITH (A TITLE OF THE BRITISH MONARCHS)"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *F.D.*?"},"1294454853749444750":{"questionID":"P000039","answers":["LUX SIT. (\"LET THERE BE LIGHT.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Washington*?"},"1294454865614868502":{"questionID":"P000058","answers":["VIRTUTE ET ARMIS (\"BY COURAGE AND ARMS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Mississippi*?"},"1294465624898273280":{"questionID":"A000457","answers":["word, speech, reasoning... logos (λογος)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **analogy**?"},"1294465644858703892":{"questionID":"A000723","answers":["time... chronos (χρονος)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **chronic**?"},"1294465681617850419":{"questionID":"A000660","answers":["teino (τεινω), stretch out, strain"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **tendon**?"},"1294466501851484170":{"questionID":"A000048","answers":["algos (αλγος), pain"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **nostalgia**?"},"1294466951338524723":{"questionID":"P000221","answers":["CATO THE ELDER"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Delenda est Carthago**?"},"1294467033634705490":{"questionID":"P000091","answers":["(BIS IN DIE) TWICE A DAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *b.i.d.*?"},"1294467042887467119":{"questionID":"P000124","answers":["(LOCO CITATO) IN A PREVIOUSLY CITED PLACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *loc. cit.*?"},"1294467050923884575":{"questionID":"P000205","answers":["ALL THE WAY UP TO"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Usque ad*?"},"1294467059693916266":{"questionID":"P000165","answers":["WITH A GRAIN OF SALT (I.E. USE CAUTION)"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Cum grano salis*?"},"1294467065679446178":{"questionID":"P000201","answers":["ONE OF A KIND"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *sui generis*?"},"1294467078824136745":{"questionID":"P000133","answers":["(SCILICET) ACTUALLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *sc.*?"},"1294467423520559164":{"questionID":"P000226","answers":["I THINK THEREFORE I AM"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Cogito ergo sum**."},"1294467506995597402":{"questionID":"P000034","answers":["MENS AGITAT MOLEM (\"MIND MOVES THE MASS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Oregon*?"},"1294467515971534869":{"questionID":"P000185","answers":["BY THE YEAR"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Per annum*?"},"1294467567846428714":{"questionID":"P000169","answers":["AN UNLIKELY AND PROVIDENTIAL INTERVENTION"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *deus ex machina*?"},"1294467574725214228":{"questionID":"P000226","answers":["I THINK THEREFORE I AM"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Cogito ergo sum**."},"1294467704845238385":{"questionID":"P000003","answers":["IN DEO SPERAMUS. (\"IN GOD WE TRUST.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Brown University*?"},"1294467823619543111":{"questionID":"P000219","answers":["THE DIE IS CAST"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Alea iacta est**."},"1294467835220856853":{"questionID":"P000161","answers":["IN GOOD FAITH"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Bona fide*?"},"1294468028146258002":{"questionID":"LHALF003872","answers":["fera"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter nominative plural** of *ferus* (wild)?"},"1294490302786043956":{"questionID":"P000150","answers":["FROM WHAT IS ALREADY KNOWN (LIT. \"FROM WHAT COMES BEFORE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *a priori*?"},"1294490283668668417":{"questionID":"P000065","answers":["IMPERIUM IN IMPERIO (\"AN EMPIRE WITHIN AN EMPIRE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Ohio*?"},"1294491590928105484":{"questionID":"P000076","answers":["SEMPER FIDELIS (\"ALWAYS FAITHFUL\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Marine Corps*?"},"1294491967052320799":{"questionID":"P000237","answers":["JUVENAL"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Dificile est saturam non scribere**?"},"1294491976858603601":{"questionID":"P000223","answers":["CONSTANTINE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **In hoc signo vinces**?"},"1294491982768635927":{"questionID":"P000147","answers":["YOU HIT THE NAIL ON THE HEAD"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *rem acu tetigisti*?"},"1294491994588053534":{"questionID":"P000137","answers":["(SENATUS POPULUSQUE ROMANUS) THE SENATE AND POPULACE OF ROME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *S.P.Q.R.*?"},"1294492103732105267":{"questionID":"P000057","answers":["CIVILITAS SUCCESSIT BARBARUM (\"CIVILIZATION SUCCEEDS BARBARISM\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Minnesota*?"},"1294498538234839050":{"questionID":"P000216","answers":["I CAME, I SAW, I CONQUERED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Veni, vidi, vici**."},"1294498560183898173":{"questionID":"P000018","answers":["DOMINUS ILLUMINATIO MEA (\"THE LORD IS MY LIGHT\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Oxford University*?"},"1294498582505852973":{"questionID":"P000093","answers":["(HORA SOMNI) AT BEDTIME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *h.s.*?"},"1294498601367506996":{"questionID":"P000029","answers":["VIRTUTE ET ARMIS. (\"BY VALOR AND ARMS.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Mississippi*?"},"1294498817051459604":{"questionID":"P000117","answers":["(FOLIIS) ON THE [FOLLOWING] PAGES"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *ff.*?"},"1294498824710262794":{"questionID":"P000236","answers":["ALL THAT WORK AND NOTHING TO SHOW FOR IT"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **parturient montes, nasceture ridiculus mus**."},"1294498937885163531":{"questionID":"P000120","answers":["(FOLIO VERSO) ON THE LEFT HAND PAGE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *f.v.*?"},"1294498946227503155":{"questionID":"P000224","answers":["IN THIS SIGN YOU WILL CONQUER"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **In hoc signo vinces**."},"1294498950702956587":{"questionID":"P000031","answers":["LITTERIS DEDICATA ET OMNIBUS ARTIBUS (\"DEDICATED TO LETTERS AND ALL THE ARTS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Nebraska*?"},"1294498961415077920":{"questionID":"P000016","answers":["QUAECUM SUNT VERA (\"WHATEVER IS TRUE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Northwestern University*?"},"1294499030809706527":{"questionID":"P000116","answers":["(FIDEI DEFENSOR) DEFENDER OF THE FAITH (A TITLE OF THE BRITISH MONARCHS)"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *F.D.*?"},"1294522659861827647":{"questionID":"LHALF010959","answers":["cognoscit"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *cognosco* (to examine, to know)?"},"1294743905312706641":{"questionID":"LFIFTH001601","answers":["alba"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter nominative plural** of *albus* (white)?"},"1294743876589850645":{"questionID":"LFIFTH003917","answers":["negavistis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *nego* (to say no, to deny)?"},"1294743930537246740":{"questionID":"LFIFTH006108","answers":["desiit"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *desino* (to cease, desist)?"},"1294750175054532759":{"questionID":"LFIFTH007167","answers":["feritis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *ferio* (to strike; to kill)?"},"1294791771649474612":{"questionID":"LHALF001904","answers":["iudici"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *iudex, iudicis* (judge)?"},"1294810003965739018":{"questionID":"P000250","answers":["TIME, THE DEVOURER OF ALL THINGS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Tempus edax rerum**."},"1294810054888919130":{"questionID":"LHALF001243","answers":["iocos"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *iocus, ioci* (joke)?"},"1294811886017056845":{"questionID":"LHALF001250","answers":["initiis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *initium, initii* (beginning)?"},"1294835798230695987":{"questionID":"LFIFTH000086","answers":["fortunae"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *fortuna, fortunae* (luck)?"},"1294855080008482856":{"questionID":"P000098","answers":["(QUAQUE DIE) EVERYDAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *q.d.*?"},"1294855122869944331":{"questionID":"P000143","answers":["NEVER, OR WHEN HELL FREEZES OVER (LIT. \"AT THE GREEK CALENDS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *ad kalendas graecas*?"},"1294855060878266430":{"questionID":"LHALF006434","answers":["vacavi"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *vaco* (to be empty, vacant, free, idle)?"},"1294855133829660732":{"questionID":"LHALF012018","answers":["servivit"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *servio* (to be a servant or slave, to serve)?"},"1294855160480403568":{"questionID":"P000144","answers":["WHERE THERE'S A WILL THERE'S A WAY (LIT. \"EITHER I'LL FIND A WAY OR MAKE ONE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *aut viam inveniam aut faciam*?"},"1294855234178252882":{"questionID":"P000151","answers":["FROM THE BEGINNING"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *ab initio*?"},"1294855244324536350":{"questionID":"P000021","answers":["PRO ECCLESIA ET PATRIA. (\"FOR CHURCH AND COUNTRY.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Trinity College*?"},"1294855250095902721":{"questionID":"P000164","answers":["LET THE BUYER BEWARE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Caveat emptor*?"},"1294855255728853042":{"questionID":"P000143","answers":["NEVER, OR WHEN HELL FREEZES OVER (LIT. \"AT THE GREEK CALENDS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *ad kalendas graecas*?"},"1294855264880562277":{"questionID":"P000095","answers":["(OCULUS SINISTER) LEFT EYE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *o.s.*?"},"1294855415841947698":{"questionID":"P000049","answers":["IUSTITIA OMNIBUS (\"JUSTICE FOR ALL.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *District of Columbia*?"},"1294855424511840379":{"questionID":"P000108","answers":["(CETERIS PARIBUS) WITH OTHER THINGS BEING EQUAL"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *Cet. Par.*?"},"1294855430480330752":{"questionID":"P000238","answers":["IT IS NOT DIFFICULT TO WRITE SATIRE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Dificile est saturam non scribere**."},"1294855436201230346":{"questionID":"P000187","answers":["BY THE DAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Per diem*?"},"1294855441389453354":{"questionID":"P000064","answers":["JOANNES EST NOMAN EIUS (\"JOHN IS HIS NAME.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Puerto Rico*?"},"1294855449048383529":{"questionID":"P000088","answers":["SIT TIBI TERRA LEVIS (\"MAY THE EARTH REST LIGHTLY ON YOU\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *S.T.T.L.*?"},"1294855477854863380":{"questionID":"P000241","answers":["JUVENAL"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Panem et circenses**?"},"1294855485375254629":{"questionID":"P000102","answers":["(SEMEL IN DIE) ONCE A DAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *s.i.d.*?"},"1294855489791987772":{"questionID":"P000135","answers":["(SINE GRATIA) WITHOUT EXAMPLE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *s.g.*?"},"1294855495588380722":{"questionID":"P000180","answers":["A SLIP OF THE TONGUE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *lapsus linguae*?"},"1294855500797710388":{"questionID":"P000150","answers":["FROM WHAT IS ALREADY KNOWN (LIT. \"FROM WHAT COMES BEFORE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *a priori*?"},"1294855551645122681":{"questionID":"P000030","answers":["SALUS POPULI. (\"THE WELFARE OF THE PEOPLE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Missouri*?"},"1294855558435704922":{"questionID":"P000114","answers":["(ET SEQUENS) AND THE FOLLOWING"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *et seq.*?"},"1294855727684255786":{"questionID":"P000004","answers":["DEUS LUX MEA (\"GOD IS MY LIGHT\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Catholic University of America*?"},"1294855736102227968":{"questionID":"P000082","answers":["E PLURIBUS UNUM (\"FROM MANY, ONE\", \"OUT OF MANY, ONE\", ETC.)"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *United States of America*?"},"1294855757442973696":{"questionID":"P000021","answers":["PRO ECCLESIA ET PATRIA. (\"FOR CHURCH AND COUNTRY.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Trinity College*?"},"1294855762778132541":{"questionID":"P000099","answers":["(QUANTUM SUFFICIAT) AS MUCH AS NEEDED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *q.s.*?"},"1294855767022899274":{"questionID":"P000150","answers":["FROM WHAT IS ALREADY KNOWN (LIT. \"FROM WHAT COMES BEFORE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *a priori*?"},"1294855772718632981":{"questionID":"P000017","answers":["CRUX SPES UNICA (\"THE CROSS IS THE ONLY HOPE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Notre Dame University*?"},"1294855779148369950":{"questionID":"P000138","answers":["(VIDE INFRA) SEE BELOW"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *v.i.*?"},"1294855785389756507":{"questionID":"P000108","answers":["(CETERIS PARIBUS) WITH OTHER THINGS BEING EQUAL"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *Cet. Par.*?"},"1294855790728970304":{"questionID":"P000107","answers":["(AB URBE CONDITA, ANNO URBIS CONDITAE) FROM THE FOUNDING OF THE CITY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *a.u.c.*?"},"1294855823624896622":{"questionID":"P000237","answers":["JUVENAL"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Dificile est saturam non scribere**?"},"1294855828817444918":{"questionID":"P000165","answers":["WITH A GRAIN OF SALT (I.E. USE CAUTION)"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Cum grano salis*?"},"1294855833993220166":{"questionID":"P000137","answers":["(SENATUS POPULUSQUE ROMANUS) THE SENATE AND POPULACE OF ROME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *S.P.Q.R.*?"},"1294855839072653403":{"questionID":"P000097","answers":["(PER OS) THROUGH THE MOUTH, I.E., ORALLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *p.o.*?"},"1295125427152748564":{"questionID":"LHALF008454","answers":["iussisti"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *iubeo* (to command, order)?"},"1295130252850499585":{"questionID":"LFIFTH000238","answers":["invidia"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *invidia, invidiae* (envy, hostility)?"},"1295130275206004776":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002773","answers":["simplices"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *simplex* (simple, ingenuous)?"},"1295130294113796127":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004514","answers":["sustinuisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *sustineo* (to support, sustain)?"},"1295130636641767525":{"questionID":"LFIFTH001050","answers":["solitudines"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *solitudo, solitudinis* (loneliness, lonely place)?"},"1295139372752044133":{"questionID":"LHALF011513","answers":["proficis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *proficio* (to go on, to make progress)?"},"1295153282947481691":{"questionID":"LFIFTH000097","answers":["magistra"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *magistra, magistrae* (instructress)?"},"1295159228415348757":{"questionID":"LFIFTH001094","answers":["ponte"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *pons, pontis* (bridge)?"},"1295169137617801299":{"questionID":"A000660","answers":["teino (τεινω), stretch out, strain"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **tendon**?"},"1295174307974221924":{"questionID":"LHALF010051","answers":["imponunt"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *impono* (to lay upon, impose)?"},"1295174359622877284":{"questionID":"LHALF007629","answers":["conat"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *conor* (to attempt, try)?"},"1295174372822351903":{"questionID":"LHALF010474","answers":["dimittebamus"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *dimitto* (to send out, dismiss)?"},"1295177545452617781":{"questionID":"F001345","answers":["ODYSSEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who is described by Homer as \"polytropos\"?"},"1295196544542310571":{"questionID":"A000179","answers":["book... biblos (βιβλος)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **Bible**?"},"1295196524782813212":{"questionID":"A000718","answers":["cheir (χειρ), hand"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **surgery**?"},"1295201673274331157":{"questionID":"A000106","answers":["star"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What does the Greek word **aster (αστηρ)** mean?"},"1295217563499888734":{"questionID":"F000193","answers":["ASTARTE"],"genus":"myth","question":"With what Phoenician goddess is Aphrodite sometimes confused in the myth of Adonis?"},"1295217609532248125":{"questionID":"F001577","answers":["PHYLEUS (AUGEAS' SON)"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who did Heracles put on the throne of Elis to replace king Augeas?"},"1295219703588851752":{"questionID":"G002851","answers":["old"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *vetus veteris*."},"1295219798896148480":{"questionID":"G000908","answers":["facies faciei f."],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find all 3 principal parts of the noun that matches the definition *form, appearance*. Do not include macrons."},"1295219879259148300":{"questionID":"G002823","answers":["ADV"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the part of speech/Latin inflection category of the word *vere*.\n\nPlease use the following for your answer.\n**Adjective: 1st and 2nd Declension:** A12\n**Adjective: 3rd Declension:** A3\n**Adjective: Indeclinable:** AI\n**Adjective: Numeral:** AN\n**Adverb:** ADV\n**Conjunction:** CONJ\n**Noun: 1st Declension:** N1\n**Noun: 2nd Declension:** N2\n**Noun: 3rd Declension:** N3\n**Noun: 4th Declension:** N4\n**Noun: 5th Declension:** N5\n**Noun: Indeclinable:** NI\n**Preposition:** PREP\n**Pronoun:** PRO\n**Verb: 1st Conjugation:** V1\n**Verb: 2nd Conjugation:** V2\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -io:** V3i\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -o:** V3\n**Verb: 4th Conjugation:** V4\n**Verb: Deponent:** VD\n**Verb: Impersonal:** VIP\n**Verb: Irregular:** VIRR"},"1295220356424142919":{"questionID":"G000009","answers":["CONJ"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the part of speech/Latin inflection category of the word *ac*.\n\nPlease use the following for your answer.\n**Adjective: 1st and 2nd Declension:** A12\n**Adjective: 3rd Declension:** A3\n**Adjective: Indeclinable:** AI\n**Adjective: Numeral:** AN\n**Adverb:** ADV\n**Conjunction:** CONJ\n**Noun: 1st Declension:** N1\n**Noun: 2nd Declension:** N2\n**Noun: 3rd Declension:** N3\n**Noun: 4th Declension:** N4\n**Noun: 5th Declension:** N5\n**Noun: Indeclinable:** NI\n**Preposition:** PREP\n**Pronoun:** PRO\n**Verb: 1st Conjugation:** V1\n**Verb: 2nd Conjugation:** V2\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -io:** V3i\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -o:** V3\n**Verb: 4th Conjugation:** V4\n**Verb: Deponent:** VD\n**Verb: Impersonal:** VIP\n**Verb: Irregular:** VIRR"},"1295254371273019412":{"questionID":"P000063","answers":["LABOR OMNIA VINCIT (\"WORK CONQUERS ALL\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Oklahoma*?"},"1295254410875637790":{"questionID":"P000188","answers":["BY ITSELF","ESSENTIALLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Per se*?"},"1295254453481639996":{"questionID":"P000015","answers":["PERSTARE ET PRAESTARE. (\"TO PRESERVE AND TO SURPASS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *New York University*?"},"1295255860087488522":{"questionID":"P000184","answers":["AN UNSOUND MAN"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Non compos mentis*?"},"1295261446573391944":{"questionID":"F000349","answers":["DORIC, IONIC, CORINTHIAN"],"genus":"myth","question":"What were the three major orders of Greek architecture?"},"1295261470140928031":{"questionID":"F000682","answers":["CHRYSIPPUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What son of Pelops was kidnapped by Laius?"},"1295261489556619294":{"questionID":"F000302","answers":["ATLAS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of the Pleiades?"},"1295263464297725954":{"questionID":"F000040","answers":["LITYERSES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the son of Midas?"},"1295483752935329924":{"questionID":"F000445","answers":["PETASUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What was a traveling hat called?"},"1295483733042008106":{"questionID":"F001793","answers":["ACASTUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the son of Pelias?"},"1295483703723819029":{"questionID":"F001055","answers":["STYX"],"genus":"myth","question":"Into what river did Thetis dip Achilles to make him immortal?"},"1295484301370069052":{"questionID":"F002038","answers":["WORMS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who warned Melampus that his jail cell was about to cave in?"},"1295557749538557962":{"questionID":"I003114","answers":["legioni"],"genus":"inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *legio, legionis* (army, legion)?"},"1295557702319214722":{"questionID":"I021244","answers":["occupantis"],"genus":"inflection","question":"What is the **genitive singular masculine present participle** of *occupo* (to occupy, seize)?"},"1295557724398157894":{"questionID":"I072883","answers":["deiecturum"],"genus":"inflection","question":"What is the **nominative singular neuter future participle** of *deicio* (to throw or cast down)?"},"1295560780540022880":{"questionID":"LADV104598","answers":["additus sum"],"genus":"LADV_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect passive indicative** of *addo* (to add)?"},"1295570375786364999":{"questionID":"F000400","answers":["MOIRAI (FATES)"],"genus":"myth","question":"Whom did Apollo convince with wine to allow Admetus to live?"},"1295570433885606012":{"questionID":"F000682","answers":["CHRYSIPPUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What son of Pelops was kidnapped by Laius?"},"1295570413631438988":{"questionID":"F002279","answers":["MEGARA"],"genus":"myth","question":"What daughter of Creon did Heracles inadvertently kill in a fit of madness enduced by Hera?"},"1295571419815739402":{"questionID":"F001013","answers":["ARES AND APHRODITE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What two deities were wounded by Diomedes?"},"1295588463927627847":{"questionID":"P000247","answers":["OVID"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Rident stolidi verba Latina**?"},"1295588559536918649":{"questionID":"P000168","answers":["BY RIGHT","LEGALLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *De jure*?"},"1295622853219192852":{"questionID":"F001455","answers":["DANAUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the uncle of Lynceus, husband of Hypermnestra?"},"1295622928825843824":{"questionID":"P000170","answers":["WITHOUT PREPARATION"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Ex tempore*?"},"1295625256521830482":{"questionID":"F002042","answers":["10TH (CATTLE OF GERYON)"],"genus":"myth","question":"To which of Heracles' labor can Melampus adventure be likened?"},"1295932872435175475":{"questionID":"LFIFTH000409","answers":["vitio"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *vitium, vitii* (fault, error, vice)?"},"1295932931684040704":{"questionID":"LFIFTH001338","answers":["pisces"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *piscis, piscis* (fish)?"},"1295932892001730570":{"questionID":"LFIFTH003598","answers":["significatis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *significo* (to show; to mean, signify)?"},"1295943094642016296":{"questionID":"P000224","answers":["IN THIS SIGN YOU WILL CONQUER"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **In hoc signo vinces**."},"1295943102116270120":{"questionID":"P000009","answers":["DEUS NOBIS FIDUCIA (\"GOD IS OUR TRUST\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *George Washington University*?"},"1295943108839739444":{"questionID":"P000174","answers":["FOREVER"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *In aeternum*?"},"1295943114661433354":{"questionID":"P000194","answers":["PROBABLE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Similis veri*?"},"1295943149931466812":{"questionID":"P000168","answers":["BY RIGHT","LEGALLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *De jure*?"},"1295943157443199028":{"questionID":"P000019","answers":["DEI SUB NUMINE VIGET (\"IT FLOURISHES UNDER THE WILL OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Princeton University*?"},"1295943162212122636":{"questionID":"P000181","answers":["A METHOD OF WORKING"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *modus operandi*?"},"1295943166725455982":{"questionID":"P000088","answers":["SIT TIBI TERRA LEVIS (\"MAY THE EARTH REST LIGHTLY ON YOU\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *S.T.T.L.*?"},"1295943171406168086":{"questionID":"P000224","answers":["IN THIS SIGN YOU WILL CONQUER"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **In hoc signo vinces**."},"1295943176711962654":{"questionID":"P000242","answers":["BREAD AND CIRCUS GAMES"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Panem et circenses**."},"1295943320337387530":{"questionID":"P000248","answers":["FOOLS LAUGH AT THE LATIN LANGUAGE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Rident stolidi verba Latina**."},"1295943327270572072":{"questionID":"P000192","answers":["HOW MUCH"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Quantum*?"},"1295943344853356645":{"questionID":"P000201","answers":["ONE OF A KIND"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *sui generis*?"},"1295943353724178494":{"questionID":"P000163","answers":["BEWARE THE DOG"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Cave canem*?"},"1295943361781432330":{"questionID":"P000199","answers":["EXISTING CONDITION"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Status quo*?"},"1295943368022556743":{"questionID":"P000206","answers":["A CONSTANT COMPANION (GO WITH ME)"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *vade mecum*?"},"1295944410135265310":{"questionID":"P000011","answers":["MIHI CURA FUTURI. (\"MY ANXIETY IS FOR THE FUTURE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Hunter College*?"},"1295944463037894696":{"questionID":"P000007","answers":["VOX CLAMANTIS IN DESERTO. (\"A VOICE OF ONE CRYING IN THE WILDERNESS.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Dartmouth College*?"},"1295944474471432232":{"questionID":"P000143","answers":["NEVER, OR WHEN HELL FREEZES OVER (LIT. \"AT THE GREEK CALENDS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *ad kalendas graecas*?"},"1295944617283289170":{"questionID":"P000176","answers":["IN THE MIDDLE OF THINGS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *in medias res*?"},"1295944666067243088":{"questionID":"P000124","answers":["(LOCO CITATO) IN A PREVIOUSLY CITED PLACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *loc. cit.*?"},"1295944672593842217":{"questionID":"P000146","answers":["SPEAK ONLY GOOD OF THE DEAD"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *De mortuis nil nisi bonum*?"},"1295944680395243530":{"questionID":"P000176","answers":["IN THE MIDDLE OF THINGS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *in medias res*?"},"1295944763802914888":{"questionID":"P000033","answers":["CIVI ET REI PUBLICAE (\"FOR THE CITIZEN AND THE STATE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Oklahoma*?"},"1295944771977609256":{"questionID":"P000187","answers":["BY THE DAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Per diem*?"},"1295944869428203562":{"questionID":"P000073","answers":["SPERAMUS MELIORA, RESURGET CINERIBUS (\"WE HOPE FOR BETTER THINGS, IT WILL RISE FROM THE ASHES\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Detroit*?"},"1295944874951970826":{"questionID":"P000220","answers":["CROSSING THE RUBICON"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Before what major event did Caesar say **Alea iacta est**?"},"1295944881587490876":{"questionID":"P000099","answers":["(QUANTUM SUFFICIAT) AS MUCH AS NEEDED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *q.s.*?"},"1295944885819674717":{"questionID":"P000127","answers":["(POST MERIDIEM) AFTER MIDDAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *P.M.*?"},"1295944891096105000":{"questionID":"P000025","answers":["CRESCAT SCIENTIA, VITA EXCOLATUR (\"LET KNOWLEDGE INCREASE, LET LIFE BE PERFECTED\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Chicago*?"},"1295944896200310794":{"questionID":"P000162","answers":["JUSTIFICATION FOR WAR"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Casus Belli*?"},"1295944949744795658":{"questionID":"P000072","answers":["URBS IN HORTO (\"CITY IN A GARDEN\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Chicago*?"},"1295944958376804403":{"questionID":"P000111","answers":["(DEO VOLENTE) GOD WILLING"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *D.V.*?"},"1295944965729550336":{"questionID":"P000100","answers":["(QUOTIDIANUS) DAILY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *quot.*?"},"1295944979348459612":{"questionID":"P000190","answers":["AUTOPSY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *post mortem*?"},"1295945024797933610":{"questionID":"P000189","answers":["AN UNWELCOME PERSON"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Persona non grata*?"},"1295945031794032660":{"questionID":"P000121","answers":["(ID EST) THAT IS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *i.e.*?"},"1295945036713689129":{"questionID":"P000176","answers":["IN THE MIDDLE OF THINGS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *in medias res*?"},"1295945076718964736":{"questionID":"P000074","answers":["DOMINE, DIRIGE NOS (\"LORD, GUIDE US\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *London*?"},"1295945083509669889":{"questionID":"P000247","answers":["OVID"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Rident stolidi verba Latina**?"},"1295945092334489682":{"questionID":"P000224","answers":["IN THIS SIGN YOU WILL CONQUER"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **In hoc signo vinces**."},"1295945098424750162":{"questionID":"P000104","answers":["(TER IN DIE) THREE TIMES A DAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *t.i.d.*?"},"1295945107362807908":{"questionID":"P000227","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Carpe diem, quam minimum credula postero**?"},"1295945114136608788":{"questionID":"P000084","answers":["\"A NEW ORDER OF THE AGES\""],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate \"Novus Ordo Seclorum,\" a Latin motto on the US $1 bill."},"1295947477182185512":{"questionID":"LHALF010606","answers":["deducunt"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *deduco* (to lead away)?"},"1295960580016046145":{"questionID":"P000212","answers":["MAKE HASTE SLOWLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Festina lente**."},"1295961306888929333":{"questionID":"P000083","answers":["CITIUS, ALTIUS, FORTIUS (\"FASTER, HIGHER, STRONGER\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Olympics*?"},"1295961320478347355":{"questionID":"P000235","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **parturient montes, nasceture ridiculus mus**?"},"1295961326820266054":{"questionID":"P000233","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Exegi monumentum aere perennius**?"},"1295961331815419955":{"questionID":"P000243","answers":["JUVENAL"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Quis custodiet ipsos custodes?**?"},"1295961376275304520":{"questionID":"P000005","answers":["RESPICE, ADSPICE, PROSPICE. (\"LOOK BACK, LOOK TO THE PRESENT, LOOK TO THE FUTURE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *City College of NY*?"},"1295961396223414364":{"questionID":"P000168","answers":["BY RIGHT","LEGALLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *De jure*?"},"1295961402259017739":{"questionID":"P000174","answers":["FOREVER"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *In aeternum*?"},"1295961408261062749":{"questionID":"P000133","answers":["(SCILICET) ACTUALLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *sc.*?"},"1295961415282065469":{"questionID":"P000095","answers":["(OCULUS SINISTER) LEFT EYE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *o.s.*?"},"1295961423008104500":{"questionID":"P000016","answers":["QUAECUM SUNT VERA (\"WHATEVER IS TRUE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Northwestern University*?"},"1295961494609072149":{"questionID":"P000253","answers":["CALIGULA (POSSIBLY TIBERIUS)"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Oderint dum metuant**?"},"1295961534228463626":{"questionID":"P000031","answers":["LITTERIS DEDICATA ET OMNIBUS ARTIBUS (\"DEDICATED TO LETTERS AND ALL THE ARTS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Nebraska*?"},"1295961547016896584":{"questionID":"P000240","answers":["A SOUND MIND IN A SOUND BODY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Mens sana in corpore sano**."},"1295961552108912781":{"questionID":"P000230","answers":["THERE'S NO GREATER HONOR THAN TO DIE FOR ONE'S COUNTRY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Dulce et decorum est pro patria mori**."},"1295961556986888304":{"questionID":"P000162","answers":["JUSTIFICATION FOR WAR"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Casus Belli*?"},"1295961566042394624":{"questionID":"P000221","answers":["CATO THE ELDER"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Delenda est Carthago**?"},"1295961570832023593":{"questionID":"P000212","answers":["MAKE HASTE SLOWLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Festina lente**."},"1295961576599322677":{"questionID":"P000016","answers":["QUAECUM SUNT VERA (\"WHATEVER IS TRUE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Northwestern University*?"},"1295961727212585002":{"questionID":"P000190","answers":["AUTOPSY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *post mortem*?"},"1295961738407055464":{"questionID":"P000196","answers":["WITHOUT DELAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Sine mora*?"},"1295961745495691366":{"questionID":"P000009","answers":["DEUS NOBIS FIDUCIA (\"GOD IS OUR TRUST\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *George Washington University*?"},"1295961757155721247":{"questionID":"P000085","answers":["\"HE LOOKS WITH FAVOR ON OUR UNDERTAKINGS\""],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate \"Annuit Coeptis,\" a Latin motto of the US."},"1295961800600453162":{"questionID":"P000185","answers":["BY THE YEAR"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Per annum*?"},"1295961814571548716":{"questionID":"P000031","answers":["LITTERIS DEDICATA ET OMNIBUS ARTIBUS (\"DEDICATED TO LETTERS AND ALL THE ARTS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Nebraska*?"},"1295961821479698543":{"questionID":"P000090","answers":["(ANTE CIBOS) BEFORE MEALS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *a.c.*?"},"1295961826638561321":{"questionID":"P000002","answers":["NIL SINE MAGNO LABORE. (\"NOTHING WITHOUT GREAT EFFORT.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Brooklyn College*?"},"1295961831919059025":{"questionID":"P000118","answers":["(FLORUIT) PERIOD OF TIME DURING WHICH A PERSON OR THING FLOURISHED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *fl.*?"},"1295961838592458906":{"questionID":"P000099","answers":["(QUANTUM SUFFICIAT) AS MUCH AS NEEDED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *q.s.*?"},"1295961845143830549":{"questionID":"P000233","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Exegi monumentum aere perennius**?"},"1295961850902609972":{"questionID":"P000100","answers":["(QUOTIDIANUS) DAILY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *quot.*?"},"1295961935967420427":{"questionID":"P000205","answers":["ALL THE WAY UP TO"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Usque ad*?"},"1295961948692676639":{"questionID":"P000075","answers":["FLUCTUAT NEC MERGITUR (\"IT IS TOSSED BY THE WAVES BUT DOES NOT SINK\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Paris*?"},"1295961957429674004":{"questionID":"P000042","answers":["LUX ET VERITAS. (\"LIGHT AND TRUTH.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Yale University*?"},"1295961963611816046":{"questionID":"P000004","answers":["DEUS LUX MEA (\"GOD IS MY LIGHT\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Catholic University of America*?"},"1295961969249091595":{"questionID":"P000179","answers":["BY THE VERY FACT ITSELF"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *ipso facto*?"},"1295961975796531320":{"questionID":"P000128","answers":["(PRO RE NATA) AS THE NEED ARISES"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *p.r.n.*?"},"1295961982993956884":{"questionID":"P000088","answers":["SIT TIBI TERRA LEVIS (\"MAY THE EARTH REST LIGHTLY ON YOU\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *S.T.T.L.*?"},"1295961988878434324":{"questionID":"P000069","answers":["MONTANI SEMPER LIBERI. (\" MOUNTAINERS ARE ALWAYS FREE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *West Virginia*?"},"1295961998672138250":{"questionID":"P000141","answers":["(VERSUS) AGAINST"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *vs.*?"},"1295965969285386261":{"questionID":"LHALF006161","answers":["desunt"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *desum* (to be away, to be absent; to fail)?"},"1295966350795079700":{"questionID":"LHALF010851","answers":["condebas"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *condo* (to found, establish)?"},"1295968046380220458":{"questionID":"G001905","answers":["N1"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the part of speech/Latin inflection category of the word *pecunia pecuniae f.*.\n\nPlease use the following for your answer.\n**Adjective: 1st and 2nd Declension:** A12\n**Adjective: 3rd Declension:** A3\n**Adjective: Indeclinable:** AI\n**Adjective: Numeral:** AN\n**Adverb:** ADV\n**Conjunction:** CONJ\n**Noun: 1st Declension:** N1\n**Noun: 2nd Declension:** N2\n**Noun: 3rd Declension:** N3\n**Noun: 4th Declension:** N4\n**Noun: 5th Declension:** N5\n**Noun: Indeclinable:** NI\n**Preposition:** PREP\n**Pronoun:** PRO\n**Verb: 1st Conjugation:** V1\n**Verb: 2nd Conjugation:** V2\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -io:** V3i\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -o:** V3\n**Verb: 4th Conjugation:** V4\n**Verb: Deponent:** VD\n**Verb: Impersonal:** VIP\n**Verb: Irregular:** VIRR"},"1295969584611987487":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002443","answers":["stultae"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive singular** of *stultus* (silly)?"},"1295973807907143753":{"questionID":"LHALF005713","answers":["unoquoque"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter ablative singular** of *unusquisque* (every one)?"},"1295973842623135805":{"questionID":"LHALF010774","answers":["consulimus"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *consulo* (to consider, advise, deliberate)?"},"1295974054448070747":{"questionID":"LHALF011834","answers":["deiecerunt"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *deicio* (to throw or cast down)?"},"1295977557900132362":{"questionID":"LHALF011360","answers":["accendi"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *accendo* (to kindle, set on fire; to incite)?"},"1295977608470859798":{"questionID":"LFIFTH005551","answers":["pavimus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *pasco* (to pasture, feed, nourish)?"},"1295977640733179906":{"questionID":"LFIFTH006697","answers":["subiecistis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *subicio* (to place under)?"},"1295977671943258194":{"questionID":"LFIFTH000354","answers":["templa"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *templum, templi* (temple)?"},"1295978028350046219":{"questionID":"LFIFTH003782","answers":["peccavisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *pecco* (to commit a fault, to sin)?"},"1295978223766601759":{"questionID":"C000268","answers":["lanista"],"genus":"culture_daily_life","question":"Find a Latin term that matches the following description: **trainer of gladiators**"},"1295978327584014367":{"questionID":"T000266","answers":["CAESAR HAS NO AUTHORITY OVER THE GRAMMARIANS"],"genus":"translation","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Caesar non supra grammaticos*?"},"1295978425290592266":{"questionID":"F001441","answers":["ARGUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was sent to guard Io?"},"1295978498330071091":{"questionID":"D000105","answers":["campus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *champion* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1295978560510758943":{"questionID":"L000535","answers":["SUETONIUS"],"genus":"literature","question":"What authorr's father fought on the losing side at the Battle of Bedriacum in 69 AD?"},"1295978921459978250":{"questionID":"C000364","answers":["Salii Collini"],"genus":"culture_daily_life","question":"Find a Latin term that matches the following description: **dancing priests of Quirinus**"},"1295978987503222837":{"questionID":"C000007","answers":["people who were related by marriage only"],"genus":"culture_daily_life","question":"Write a description for the Latin term **adfines**."},"1295979010194407485":{"questionID":"C000053","answers":["ribbons which held six locks of carefully braided hair divided by a spear"],"genus":"culture_daily_life","question":"Write a description for the Latin term **vittae**."},"1295979016250982422":{"questionID":"C000243","answers":["four tali all with different numbers"],"genus":"culture_daily_life","question":"Write a description for the Latin term **Vulture throw**."},"1295979025000435732":{"questionID":"C000496","answers":["Publius"],"genus":"culture_daily_life","question":"What Roman praenomen has the abbreviation of **P**?"},"1295979065299435621":{"questionID":"G000645","answers":["V3"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the part of speech/Latin inflection category of the word *decerno decernere decrevi decretum*.\n\nPlease use the following for your answer.\n**Adjective: 1st and 2nd Declension:** A12\n**Adjective: 3rd Declension:** A3\n**Adjective: Indeclinable:** AI\n**Adjective: Numeral:** AN\n**Adverb:** ADV\n**Conjunction:** CONJ\n**Noun: 1st Declension:** N1\n**Noun: 2nd Declension:** N2\n**Noun: 3rd Declension:** N3\n**Noun: 4th Declension:** N4\n**Noun: 5th Declension:** N5\n**Noun: Indeclinable:** NI\n**Preposition:** PREP\n**Pronoun:** PRO\n**Verb: 1st Conjugation:** V1\n**Verb: 2nd Conjugation:** V2\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -io:** V3i\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -o:** V3\n**Verb: 4th Conjugation:** V4\n**Verb: Deponent:** VD\n**Verb: Impersonal:** VIP\n**Verb: Irregular:** VIRR"},"1295979933553918042":{"questionID":"G001237","answers":["bring upon, against","bellum inferre: make war on"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *infero inferre intuli illatum*."},"1295979989384302672":{"questionID":"G002081","answers":["prior prius"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find all 2 principal parts of the adjective that matches the definition *earlier, preceding*. Do not include macrons."},"1295980131881324604":{"questionID":"G000995","answers":["flos floris m."],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find all 3 principal parts of the noun that matches the definition *flower, bloom*. Do not include macrons."},"1295980155210043443":{"questionID":"G000199","answers":["fit, suitable"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *aptus apta aptum*."},"1295980165041623093":{"questionID":"G000532","answers":["agree","constat, it is established that (+ acc. and infin.)"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *consto constare constiti*."},"1295980182749970464":{"questionID":"G002395","answers":["enough, sufficient, sufficiently"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *satis sat*."},"1295980204971528194":{"questionID":"G002279","answers":["recipio recipere recepi receptum"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find all 4 principal parts of the verb that matches the definition *take back, receive; se recipere, betake oneself, go*. Do not include macrons."},"1295980252886994975":{"questionID":"G000641","answers":["debeo debere debui debitum"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find all 4 principal parts of the verb that matches the definition *owe, be obliged*. Do not include macrons."},"1295980484546924574":{"questionID":"G002905","answers":["any, anyone"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *ullus ulla ullum*."},"1295980503329013760":{"questionID":"G000191","answers":["aperio aperire aperui apertum"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find all 4 principal parts of the verb that matches the definition *open*. Do not include macrons."},"1295980513278038098":{"questionID":"G002464","answers":["save, watch over"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *servo servare*."},"1295980787199381514":{"questionID":"G002713","answers":["third"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *tertius tertia tertium*."},"1295981298883493981":{"questionID":"G000883","answers":["army"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *exercitus exercitus m.*."},"1295981322744893450":{"questionID":"G000304","answers":["war"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *bellum belli n.*."},"1295981407755309067":{"questionID":"G001102","answers":["glory, fame"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *gloria gloriae f.*."},"1295982304715477002":{"questionID":"L1013602","answers":["obtinuimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *obtineo* (to hold, occupy, possess)?"},"1296885627018547222":{"questionID":"LFIFTH005228","answers":["scripsimus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *scribo* (to write)?"},"1296886886417039441":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002774","answers":["tenuis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine/feminine genitive singular** of *tenuis* (thin, fine, slender, weak)?"},"1297374049432899656":{"questionID":"LHALF000797","answers":["viris"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *virus, viri* (poison)?"},"1297381598983094314":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002201","answers":["laeta"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter nominative plural** of *laetus* (joyful)?"},"1297381631283433603":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004136","answers":["existimaverunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *existimo* (to value, estimate, consider, think)?"},"1297381571304886344":{"questionID":"LFIFTH006978","answers":["corripuisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *corripio* (to seize, snatch; to blame)?"},"1298517802285662208":{"questionID":"D000137","answers":["carrus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *charge * derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1298517866131357766":{"questionID":"D000085","answers":["calo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *nomenclature* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1298517885400121396":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002986","answers":["quo"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter ablative singular** of *quis* (who? which? what?; somebody)?"},"1298518606212239371":{"questionID":"D000440","answers":["longus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *lunge* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1298648367131262988":{"questionID":"P000215","answers":["CAESAR"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Veni, vidi, vici**?"},"1298648421724590161":{"questionID":"P000193","answers":["SOMETHING FOR SOMETHING"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *quid pro quo*?"},"1298648582445994006":{"questionID":"P000211","answers":["AUGUSTUS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Festina lente**?"},"1298648705548943371":{"questionID":"P000001","answers":["PRO ECCLESIA, PRO TEXANA (\"FOR CHURCH, FOR TEXAS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Baylor University*?"},"1298648889368510494":{"questionID":"P000110","answers":["(DECESSIT SINE PROLE) DEAD WITHOUT ISSUE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *d.s.p.*?"},"1298648896591102022":{"questionID":"P000042","answers":["LUX ET VERITAS. (\"LIGHT AND TRUTH.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Yale University*?"},"1298802569422049301":{"questionID":"LHALF007048","answers":["negamus"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *nego* (to say no, to deny)?"},"1298884090296274985":{"questionID":"D000327","answers":["frango"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *frail* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1298884115571019776":{"questionID":"D000168","answers":["clamo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *chiaroscuro* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1298884066879340574":{"questionID":"D000715","answers":["rota"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *rowel* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1298884886748467281":{"questionID":"D000263","answers":["emo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *prompt* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1298884930700574753":{"questionID":"LHALF001178","answers":["magistris"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *magister, magistri* (teacher, master)?"},"1298884952318021713":{"questionID":"LHALF004189","answers":["iucundas"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine accusative plural** of *iucundus* (delightful)?"},"1298898230595162183":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004837","answers":["horres"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *horreo* (to be frightened at)?"},"1298898464419086417":{"questionID":"LFIFTH007045","answers":["venit"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *venio* (to come)?"},"1299006549133496440":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002209","answers":["longa"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine ablative singular** of *longus* (long)?"},"1299006491033862215":{"questionID":"LFIFTH005083","answers":["tradis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *trado* (to deliver, betray, report)?"},"1299006527599804479":{"questionID":"LFIFTH005511","answers":["perdit"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *perdo* (to destroy, ruin; to lose)?"},"1299006509732200508":{"questionID":"LFIFTH006773","answers":["perficitis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *perficio* (to achieve, complete, accomplish)?"},"1299006936372613150":{"questionID":"LFIFTH003117","answers":["transivisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *transeo* (to go over or across)?"},"1299197360458694656":{"questionID":"D000249","answers":["domus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *damsel* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1299197301675524106":{"questionID":"D000644","answers":["praeda"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *prey* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1299197334911062048":{"questionID":"LFIFTH001843","answers":["clarae"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive singular** of *clarus* (clear, famous)?"},"1299516050710200347":{"questionID":"A000031","answers":["to lead, bring... ago (αγω)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **strategic**?"},"1299516524108713996":{"questionID":"A000611","answers":["phagein (φαγειν)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What Greek word means **to eat**?"},"1299540222064721992":{"questionID":"LADV060001","answers":["coniuncturum"],"genus":"LADV_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative singular neuter future participle** of *coniungo* (to join)?"},"1299540150774136912":{"questionID":"LADV065789","answers":["traiecerit"],"genus":"LADV_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *traicio* (to throw across, transport across, cross )?"},"1299540499849543790":{"questionID":"LADV095488","answers":["pulsorum"],"genus":"LADV_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural masculine perfect participle** of *pello* (to push, expel)?"},"1299572119532994583":{"questionID":"LFIFTH007134","answers":["munitis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *munio* (to fortify, defend)?"},"1299766485727580201":{"questionID":"D000350","answers":["glacies"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *glance* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1299766554875138190":{"questionID":"D000210","answers":["culina"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *kiln* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1299944871246827632":{"questionID":"D000579","answers":["pars"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *parcel* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1299945391411691562":{"questionID":"D000854","answers":["utor"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *utensil* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1301030893854658593":{"questionID":"D000573","answers":["pario"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *repertoire* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1301030913244659795":{"questionID":"D000782","answers":["sto"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *rest* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1301030943993368638":{"questionID":"D000798","answers":["taceo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *reticent* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1301045657158549564":{"questionID":"LHALF010951","answers":["cogebant"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *cogo* (to urge, force, compel)?"},"1301255996496416818":{"questionID":"LADV090292","answers":["fassuris"],"genus":"LADV_inflection","question":"What is the **dative plural masculine future participle** of *fateor* (to confess, acknowledge)?"},"1301256820576227399":{"questionID":"LADV042858","answers":["restitueratis"],"genus":"LADV_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *restituo* (to give back, restore)?"},"1301261233491673088":{"questionID":"D000620","answers":["plango"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *plaintiff* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1301261288869073028":{"questionID":"D000530","answers":["odi"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *annoy* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1301261526203633716":{"questionID":"D000653","answers":["premo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *print* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1301305279740121088":{"questionID":"F000570","answers":["HERMES"],"genus":"myth","question":"What god had the epithet Psychopompus?"},"1301305404998815744":{"questionID":"F002195","answers":["CANACE"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the sister of Macareus, with whom he fell in love?"},"1301306042524893195":{"questionID":"F001850","answers":["JASON AND HYPSIPYLE"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who were the parents of Euneus and Nebrophonus?"},"1301306462777249924":{"questionID":"F001870","answers":["SNATCHERS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What does the name of the Harpies mean?"},"1301359308356849744":{"questionID":"D000258","answers":["ebur"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *ivory* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1301359354238206086":{"questionID":"D000438","answers":["locus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *lieu* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1301359335305252895":{"questionID":"D000815","answers":["texo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *subtle* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1301359800717934593":{"questionID":"D000064","answers":["bulla"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *boil* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1301363963107475456":{"questionID":"D000060","answers":["bos"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *beef* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1301363982116065343":{"questionID":"D000179","answers":["collum"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *collar* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1301364000121950208":{"questionID":"D000623","answers":["planus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *plan* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1301363943721406464":{"questionID":"D000668","answers":["puto"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *count* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1301369560246779974":{"questionID":"D000513","answers":["noceo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *nuisance* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1301763223585816626":{"questionID":"L1002304","answers":["regioni"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *regio, regionis* (region)?"},"1301769969624940577":{"questionID":"L1003243","answers":["radicibus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *radix, radicis* (root)?"},"1301957715756716052":{"questionID":"L1017330","answers":["imposuerunt"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *impono* (to lay upon, impose)?"},"1301959108844589097":{"questionID":"L1011753","answers":["firmaverat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *firmo* (to make firm, strengthen fortify)?"},"1302062703937847327":{"questionID":"A000229","answers":["gignosko (γιγνωσκω)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What Greek word means **to come to know, recognize**?"},"1302062743591063563":{"questionID":"A000043","answers":["algos (αλγος)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What Greek word means **pain**?"},"1302063561107050506":{"questionID":"D000308","answers":["fleo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *foible * derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1302063842729394258":{"questionID":"D000212","answers":["cuneus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *coin* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1302066869980762143":{"questionID":"D000378","answers":["iocus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *jewel* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1302066881364234270":{"questionID":"A000728","answers":["chronos (χρονος), time"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **crony**?"},"1302289768167641108":{"questionID":"D000719","answers":["ruga"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *arroyo* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1302290500539252807":{"questionID":"D000627","answers":["plecto"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *pleat* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1302299971223293964":{"questionID":"L1021517","answers":["senseritis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *sentio* (to perceive, notice, feel; to think)?"},"1302302802382688266":{"questionID":"L1015895","answers":["querebatis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *queror* (to complain, lament)?"},"1302337798505893990":{"questionID":"L1003965","answers":["aequoribus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative plural** of *aequor, aequoris* (surface of the sea, sea)?"},"1302337780399210666":{"questionID":"L1012349","answers":["comparabatis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *comparo* (to prepare, provide)?"},"1302337817007099945":{"questionID":"L1012894","answers":["valuerimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *valeo* (to be strong, powerful, capable of)?"},"1302337850838356039":{"questionID":"L1010409","answers":["probaverit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *probo* (to test, approve)?"},"1302342072061137017":{"questionID":"D000662","answers":["pulvis"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *powder* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1302442599516471336":{"questionID":"A000574","answers":["every, entire, all"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What does the Greek word **pas (πας)** mean?"},"1302693101948895286":{"questionID":"H001264","answers":["TRIED TO RESTORE PAGAN WORSHIP"],"genus":"history","question":"Why was Julian known as the \"apostate\"?"},"1302693546855501854":{"questionID":"H000427","answers":["BLIND"],"genus":"history","question":"What does the cognomen \"Caecus\" mean?"},"1302847699485327471":{"questionID":"LFIFTH000787","answers":["virtute"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *virtus, virtutis* (courage, virtue)?"},"1302847798294872064":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004161","answers":["educamus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *educo* (to bring up, educate)?"},"1303826834877579375":{"questionID":"D000289","answers":["facio"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *feat* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1303827358125658112":{"questionID":"L1019512","answers":["carueramus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *careo* (to be without)?"},"1303910600295976990":{"questionID":"H000229","answers":["ROMULUS & REMUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What infants were saved by a she-wolf when they were exposed in the wilderness by Amulius?"},"1303910641844748348":{"questionID":"H001215","answers":["AURELIAN"],"genus":"history","question":"Who defeated Tetricus the ruler of the Gallic Empire?"},"1303916300720017499":{"questionID":"H000200","answers":["DIDIUS JULIANUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What senator purchased the empire at an auction for 25,000 sesterces?"},"1303920904987873330":{"questionID":"H001171","answers":["238–244 AD"],"genus":"history","question":"What were the years of Gordian III's reign?"},"1303920941650411692":{"questionID":"H000744","answers":["POMPEY"],"genus":"history","question":"Who crucified 6000 slaves along the Via Appia after the rebellion of Spartacus?"},"1303925275758690304":{"questionID":"H001017","answers":["AUGUSTUS, TIBERIUS, CALIGULA, CLAUDIUS, NERO"],"genus":"history","question":"Name the five Julio-Claudian emperors."},"1303933839500116059":{"questionID":"H001024","answers":["BEDRIACUM"],"genus":"history","question":"What is another name for the battle of Cremona?"},"1303945634302394409":{"questionID":"L1021026","answers":["deiciebant"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *deicio* (to throw or cast down)?"},"1303950462768255037":{"questionID":"L1000030","answers":["nauta"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *nauta, nautae* (sailor)?"},"1303976737079820328":{"questionID":"D000765","answers":["sibilus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *persiflage* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1304678393903714325_0":{"questionID":"D000358","answers":["herba"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *arbor* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1304678393903714325_1":{"questionID":"D000600","answers":["penes"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *penetrate* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1304678393903714325_2":{"questionID":"D000793","answers":["sum"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *entity* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1304678393903714325_3":{"questionID":"D000357","answers":["habeo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *provender* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1304678393903714325_4":{"questionID":"D000052","answers":["bellum"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *rebel* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1304678393903714325_5":{"questionID":"D000792","answers":["suavis"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *suave* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1304678393903714325_6":{"questionID":"D000676","answers":["quattor"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *quarantine* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1304678393903714325_7":{"questionID":"D000350","answers":["glacies"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *glance* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1304678393903714325_8":{"questionID":"D000606","answers":["pes"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *vamp* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1304678393903714325_9":{"questionID":"D000721","answers":["sacer"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *execration* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1304678510610223125_0":{"questionID":"D000602","answers":["pes"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *pawn* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1304678510610223125_1":{"questionID":"D000083","answers":["calo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *calendar* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1304678510610223125_2":{"questionID":"D000573","answers":["pario"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *repertoire* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1304678510610223125_3":{"questionID":"D000803","answers":["tango"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *taste* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1304678510610223125_4":{"questionID":"D000451","answers":["maneo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *menial* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1304678510610223125_5":{"questionID":"D000691","answers":["rapio"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *usurp* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1304678510610223125_6":{"questionID":"D000575","answers":["paro"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *emperor* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1304678510610223125_7":{"questionID":"D000411","answers":["latus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *elate* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1304678510610223125_8":{"questionID":"D000245","answers":["do"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *traitor* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1304678510610223125_9":{"questionID":"D000621","answers":["planus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *explain* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1304938846378655804":{"questionID":"L1010652","answers":["peccant"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *pecco* (to commit a fault, to sin)?"},"1304938823519834159":{"questionID":"L1020573","answers":["percipiebat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *percipio* (to occupy; to perceive, observe)?"},"1304938908240318464":{"questionID":"L1011264","answers":["mandant"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *mando* (to order, command)?"},"1305612181236351037":{"questionID":"H000933","answers":["MARCELLUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What nephew of Augustus did his daughter Julia marry?"},"1305612147794903092":{"questionID":"H000876","answers":["BONONIA"],"genus":"history","question":"Where did Marc Antony, Octavian, and Lepidus meet in 43 BC to form the Second Triumvirate?"},"1305612274811011153":{"questionID":"H000656","answers":["133 BC"],"genus":"history","question":"In what year did Attalus III bequeathe Pergamum to the Romans in his will?"},"1305617057500495983":{"questionID":"H000561","answers":["HASDRUBAL"],"genus":"history","question":"What brother of Hannibal defended Spain while Hannibal invaded Italy?"},"1305617098940092426":{"questionID":"H000318","answers":["TEMPLE OF JUPITER CAPITOLINUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What is the alternate name of the Temple of Jupiter Optimus Maximus?"},"1305622269229404191":{"questionID":"H000057","answers":["APPIUS CLAUDIUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What man, the only member of both decemviri councils, is infamous for his tyrannical actions?"},"1305625257423536270":{"questionID":"H000511","answers":["HAMILCAR BARCA"],"genus":"history","question":"What Carthaginian made his young son Hannibal swear eternal hatred for Rome in return for the opportunity to join his father's military exploits?"},"1305627826199855164":{"questionID":"F000778","answers":["TIRESIAS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was summoned by Amphitryon to interpret the miracle of the two snakes sent to Heracles?"},"1305628427310596167":{"questionID":"H000526","answers":["TREBIA RIVER"],"genus":"history","question":"After his victory at the Ticinus River, where did Hannibal defeat the forces of Sempronius Longus?"},"1305670717433450527":{"questionID":"H000243","answers":["753–509 BC"],"genus":"history","question":"What were the beginning and ending years of the Monarchy?"},"1305670760857206894":{"questionID":"H001027","answers":["VITELLIUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Which emperor was defeated at the Second Battle of Bedriacum in 69 AD"},"1305673586916331561":{"questionID":"H000633","answers":["MASSINISSA"],"genus":"history","question":"Who caused Third Punic War by making raids into Carthaginian territory which forced them to retaliate and violate their treaty with the Romans?"},"1305681153327628368":{"questionID":"H000425","answers":["FABIUS RULLIANUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What Roman commander was defeated by the Samnites at Lautulae in 315 BC?"},"1305681122834776116":{"questionID":"H001167","answers":["MAXIMINUS THRAX, GORDIAN I, GORDIAN II, BALBINUS, PUPIENUS, GORDIAN III"],"genus":"history","question":"Name the 6 emperors of 238 AD."},"1305681328389226637":{"questionID":"H001134","answers":["SEVERANS"],"genus":"history","question":"Which dynasty reigned from 193–235 AD?"},"1305697688154538024":{"questionID":"H000481","answers":["DUILIUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What Roman admiral won Rome's first major naval battle at Mylae in 260 BC?"},"1305697654155513876":{"questionID":"H001228","answers":["RULE BY 4 (FOUR)"],"genus":"history","question":"What does \"tetrarchy\" mean?"},"1305700589413335090":{"questionID":"H000413","answers":["298–290 BC"],"genus":"history","question":"What were the years of the Third Samnite War?"},"1305740737870037053":{"questionID":"H000034","answers":["TARQUINNIUS SUPERBUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Who took refuge at Caere in Etruria after he and his sons were banished from Rome in 509 BC?"},"1305750462334500878":{"questionID":"H000598","answers":["168 BC"],"genus":"history","question":"In what year did Aemilius Paullus defeat Perseus of Macedon at Pydna?"},"1305750496471941134":{"questionID":"H000749","answers":["CRASSUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Which triumvir was killed fighting the the Parthians at Carrhae in 53 BC?"},"1305759192468029440":{"questionID":"H000367","answers":["6 MONTHS","SIX MONTHS"],"genus":"history","question":"How long did a dictator serve?"},"1305791177722691674":{"questionID":"H000816","answers":["59 BC"],"genus":"history","question":"In what year was Julius Caesar elected consul for the first time?"},"1305791314612453406":{"questionID":"H000622","answers":["188 BC"],"genus":"history","question":"In what year did the Treaty of Apamea officially end the war against Antiochus III?"},"1306454574059622422":{"questionID":"F000278","answers":["DIANA"],"genus":"myth","question":"What was the Roman name of Artemis?"},"1306454630879723530":{"questionID":"F000467","answers":["HECATE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What deity was known for bearing a torch?"},"1306456781484200017":{"questionID":"F000793","answers":["OENOMAUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Hippodamia?"},"1306884932169240646":{"questionID":"H000197","answers":["COMMODUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What son of Marcus Aurelius ruled from 180–192 AD?"},"1306884989736190004":{"questionID":"H000999","answers":["SENECA THE YOUNGER"],"genus":"history","question":"What teacher of Nero was forced to commit suicide in 65 AD because of his involvement in the Pisonian Conspiracy?"},"1307131993095536731":{"questionID":"L1015557","answers":["restituet"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future active indicative** of *restituo* (to give back, restore)?"},"1307132040402964621":{"questionID":"L1019086","answers":["committemus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future active indicative** of *committo* (to connect; to engage in)?"},"1307137359095271536":{"questionID":"H000607","answers":["192–188 BC"],"genus":"history","question":"What were the years of the War with Antiochus?"},"1307151941851418684":{"questionID":"L1000017","answers":["puellis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *puella, puellae* (girl)?"},"1307151959689662615":{"questionID":"L1010155","answers":["salutavero"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *saluto* (to greet, salute)?"},"1307151923203411989":{"questionID":"L1019111","answers":["colitis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *colo* (to cultivate; to inhabit; to care for; to honor)?"},"1307153361568665752":{"questionID":"L1005990","answers":["humanis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine ablative plural** of *humanus* (human, gentle)?"},"1307176850942070866":{"questionID":"P000212","answers":["MAKE HASTE SLOWLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Festina lente**."},"1307176893568520262":{"questionID":"P000179","answers":["BY THE VERY FACT ITSELF"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *ipso facto*?"},"1307176935381536852":{"questionID":"P000162","answers":["JUSTIFICATION FOR WAR"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Casus Belli*?"},"1307177039341686804":{"questionID":"P000020","answers":["AD MAIOREM DEI GLORIAM (\"FOR THE GREATER GLORY OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *The Jesuit*?"},"1307177445308370984":{"questionID":"P000184","answers":["AN UNSOUND MAN"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Non compos mentis*?"},"1307177621125070933":{"questionID":"P000090","answers":["(ANTE CIBOS) BEFORE MEALS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *a.c.*?"},"1307177629635448853":{"questionID":"P000204","answers":["TIME FLIES"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *tempus fugit*?"},"1307177637168418856":{"questionID":"P000162","answers":["JUSTIFICATION FOR WAR"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Casus Belli*?"},"1307177644491804745":{"questionID":"P000143","answers":["NEVER, OR WHEN HELL FREEZES OVER (LIT. \"AT THE GREEK CALENDS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *ad kalendas graecas*?"},"1307177914751778836":{"questionID":"P000027","answers":["ET DOCERE ET RERUM EXQUIRERE CAUSAS (\"BOTH TO TEACH & TO INQUIRE INTO THE CAUSES OF THINGS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Georgia*?"},"1307205920601804892":{"questionID":"H000457","answers":["275 BC"],"genus":"history","question":"In what year did the Romans defeat Pyrrhus at Beneventum?"},"1307206587416445038":{"questionID":"F000194","answers":["CINYRAS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the son of Paphos?"},"1307213504650154048":{"questionID":"H000552","answers":["ROMULUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Who won the first Spolia Opima by defeating Acron?"},"1307224069267132426":{"questionID":"D000761","answers":["sero"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *season* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1307374874569998427":{"questionID":"LFIFTH000795","answers":["lacunar"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative singular** of *lacunar, lacunaris* (ceiling)?"},"1307374914701103218":{"questionID":"LFIFTH000971","answers":["clade"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *clades, cladis* (disaster, defeat)?"},"1307375069458206750":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004772","answers":["maeruisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *maereo* (to be sad, mournful)?"},"1307463067478790204":{"questionID":"H000408","answers":["BRENNUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Who said \"Vae Victis\" when the Romans complained about false weights on the scale used to weigh his ransom money?"},"1307463103822172231":{"questionID":"H001084","answers":["117–138 AD"],"genus":"history","question":"What were the years of Hadrian's reign?"},"1307465472618401802":{"questionID":"H001052","answers":["COLOSSUS STATUE OF NERO IN FRONT"],"genus":"history","question":"How did the Colosseum receive its name?"},"1307472526871625848":{"questionID":"H000878","answers":["PERUSIA"],"genus":"history","question":"At what battle of 40 BC did Octavian capture Fulvia and Lucius Antony?"},"1307473450771939340":{"questionID":"H000612","answers":["GLABRIO"],"genus":"history","question":"What Roman general was victorious at Thermopylae against Antiochus III?"},"1307474615043362898":{"questionID":"H000071","answers":["AQUAE SEXTIAE"],"genus":"history","question":"At what battle in 102 BC were Teutobod and the Teutones defeated by Marius?"},"1307487565439565856":{"questionID":"H000593","answers":["196 BC"],"genus":"history","question":"In what year did Flamininus declare freedom and independence for all the Greek states at the Isthmian Games?"},"1307487604597325866":{"questionID":"H000292","answers":["ANCUS MARCIUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Which king started a settlement at Ostia where the Tiber meets the Mediterranean?"},"1307487768330506250":{"questionID":"H000539","answers":["QUINTUS FABIUS MAXIMUS CUNCTATOR"],"genus":"history","question":"Who adopted a delaying strategy and avoided all out battle with Hannibal when he was appointed dictator?"},"1307896898350354512":{"questionID":"H000329","answers":["SEXTUS TARQUINIUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What son of Tarquinius Superbus abused royal power by taking advantage of Lucretia, the wife of Collatinus?"},"1307896936849870949":{"questionID":"H001119","answers":["COLONIA COMMODIANA"],"genus":"history","question":"What did Commodus change Rome's name to?"},"1307897086368415754":{"questionID":"H000793","answers":["CATO THE YOUNGER"],"genus":"history","question":"What statesman routinely opposed Julius Caesar and fought for the death penalty for Catiline and his co-conspirators?"},"1307913857184043058":{"questionID":"H001026","answers":["CAECINA & VALENS"],"genus":"history","question":"Who were the two star generals of Vitellius?"},"1307913841417388055":{"questionID":"H001036","answers":["VESPASIAN"],"genus":"history","question":"Which emperor was the father of Titus & Domitian?"},"1307913885608837191":{"questionID":"H000861","answers":["JULIA"],"genus":"history","question":"Who was the daughter of Caesar and Cornelia?"},"1307914057139093625":{"questionID":"H000327","answers":["BURNED 3 OF THEM"],"genus":"history","question":"What did the Sibyl do each time Tarquinius Superbus refused to pay the price for the Sibylline books?"},"1308271866326286359":{"questionID":"D000361","answers":["hospes"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *hotel* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1308271917677019177":{"questionID":"D000624","answers":["plecto"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *apply* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1308271964846293102":{"questionID":"D000570","answers":["parco"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *parsimonious* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1308675223234678814":{"questionID":"H000462","answers":["ELEPHANTS"],"genus":"history","question":"What military innovation was Pyrrhus the first to use against the Romans?"},"1308683071436099665":{"questionID":"L1009275","answers":["detulerit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *defero* (to bear or bring away; to report)?"},"1308683131494334514":{"questionID":"L1017072","answers":["iunxerint"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *iungo* (to join)?"},"1308683392656740353":{"questionID":"L1021324","answers":["accepimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *accipio* (to receive)?"},"1308683409895460885":{"questionID":"L1011105","answers":["negaverat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *nego* (to say no, to deny)?"},"1308683417088692254":{"questionID":"L1014693","answers":["vincet"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future active indicative** of *vinco* (to win, to prevail)?"},"1308683566938325002":{"questionID":"L1015929","answers":["quaesiverat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *quaero* (to seek, ask, inquire, desire)?"},"1308683576379969547":{"questionID":"L1011147","answers":["narraverit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *narro* (to tell, narrate)?"},"1308683744902905978":{"questionID":"L1013381","answers":["prohibebitis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future active indicative** of *prohibeo* (to forbid, prohibit)?"},"1308683805023797259":{"questionID":"L1019988","answers":["addent"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future active indicative** of *addo* (to add)?"},"1308684015963734037":{"questionID":"D000235","answers":["dignus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *dainty* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1308684039418282044":{"questionID":"D000325","answers":["foro"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *perforate* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1308684069755682816":{"questionID":"D000732","answers":["scamnum"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *shambles* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1308684078094225439":{"questionID":"D000698","answers":["rego"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *rail* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1308684091805274142":{"questionID":"D000110","answers":["cano"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *charm* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1308684184977674250":{"questionID":"P000059","answers":["SALUS POPULI SUPREMA LEX ESTO. (\"LET THE WELFARE OF THE PEOPLE BE THE SUPREME LAW.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Missouri*?"},"1308684477739958363":{"questionID":"P000234","answers":["I HAVE RAISED A MONUMENT MORE LASTING THAN BRONZE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Exegi monumentum aere perennius**."},"1308684657017225227":{"questionID":"P000235","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **parturient montes, nasceture ridiculus mus**?"},"1308684686473564231":{"questionID":"P000249","answers":["OVID"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Tempus edax rerum**?"},"1308684696116396103":{"questionID":"P000077","answers":["SEMPER PARATUS (\"ALWAYS READY\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Coast Guard*?"},"1308684709307355157":{"questionID":"P000016","answers":["QUAECUM SUNT VERA (\"WHATEVER IS TRUE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Northwestern University*?"},"1308684845337284628":{"questionID":"P000084","answers":["\"A NEW ORDER OF THE AGES\""],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate \"Novus Ordo Seclorum,\" a Latin motto on the US $1 bill."},"1308684861590212679":{"questionID":"P000246","answers":["WHAT IN ARTIST DIES IN ME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Qualis artifex pereo**."},"1308685006364868628":{"questionID":"P000039","answers":["LUX SIT. (\"LET THERE BE LIGHT.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Washington*?"},"1308685167820275733":{"questionID":"P000075","answers":["FLUCTUAT NEC MERGITUR (\"IT IS TOSSED BY THE WAVES BUT DOES NOT SINK\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Paris*?"},"1308685182122852404":{"questionID":"P000055","answers":["ENSE PETIT PLACIDAM SUB LIBERTATE QUIETEM (\"WITH THE SWORD HE SEEKS PEACE UNDER LIBERTY\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Massachusettes*?"},"1308685432497901589":{"questionID":"P000087","answers":["HIC IACET SEPULTUS (\"HERE LIES BURIED\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *H.J.S.*?"},"1308685444241948683":{"questionID":"P000175","answers":["IN THE PLACE OF A PARENT"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *in loco parentis*?"},"1308685517717508176":{"questionID":"P000254","answers":["LET THEM HATE ME PROVIDED THAT THEY FEAR ME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Oderint dum metuant**."},"1308685527255613444":{"questionID":"P000254","answers":["LET THEM HATE ME PROVIDED THAT THEY FEAR ME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Oderint dum metuant**."},"1308685537812418570":{"questionID":"P000078","answers":["PER ARDUA AD ASTRA (\"THROUGH STRUGGLE TO THE STARS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *The Royal Air Force*?"},"1308685548138922004":{"questionID":"P000080","answers":["AD MAIOREM DEI GLORIAM (\"FOR THE GREATER GLORY OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Society of Jesuits*?"},"1308685562080792647":{"questionID":"P000007","answers":["VOX CLAMANTIS IN DESERTO. (\"A VOICE OF ONE CRYING IN THE WILDERNESS.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Dartmouth College*?"},"1308685820743651329":{"questionID":"P000235","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **parturient montes, nasceture ridiculus mus**?"},"1308686031192588369":{"questionID":"P000100","answers":["(QUOTIDIANUS) DAILY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *quot.*?"},"1308686045432512522":{"questionID":"P000168","answers":["BY RIGHT","LEGALLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *De jure*?"},"1308686056115408916":{"questionID":"P000027","answers":["ET DOCERE ET RERUM EXQUIRERE CAUSAS (\"BOTH TO TEACH & TO INQUIRE INTO THE CAUSES OF THINGS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Georgia*?"},"1308686063560167525":{"questionID":"P000183","answers":["PERFECTION"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Ne plus ultra*?"},"1308686073198809098":{"questionID":"P000224","answers":["IN THIS SIGN YOU WILL CONQUER"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **In hoc signo vinces**."},"1308686094098894858":{"questionID":"P000099","answers":["(QUANTUM SUFFICIAT) AS MUCH AS NEEDED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *q.s.*?"},"1308686115527589960":{"questionID":"P000035","answers":["LEGES SINE MORIBUS VANAE (\"LAWS WITHOUT MORALS ARE USELESS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Pennsylvania*?"},"1308686124582961212":{"questionID":"P000171","answers":["THEREFORE, LET US REJOICE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Gaudeamus igitur*?"},"1308686135270178836":{"questionID":"P000225","answers":["DESCARTES"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous person said **Cogito ergo sum**?"},"1308686282909683765":{"questionID":"P000136","answers":["(SI OPUS SIT) IF THERE IS NEED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *s.o.s.*?"},"1308686356347617321":{"questionID":"P000083","answers":["CITIUS, ALTIUS, FORTIUS (\"FASTER, HIGHER, STRONGER\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Olympics*?"},"1308686455929045003":{"questionID":"P000174","answers":["FOREVER"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *In aeternum*?"},"1308686466687307786":{"questionID":"P000092","answers":["(GUTTAE) DROPS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *g.t.t.*?"},"1308686476145590312":{"questionID":"P000056","answers":["SI QUAERIS PENINSULAM AMOENAM, CIRCUMSPICE (\"IF YOU SEEK A PLEASANT PENINSULA, LOOK AROUND\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Michigan*?"},"1308686597562040360":{"questionID":"P000098","answers":["(QUAQUE DIE) EVERYDAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *q.d.*?"},"1308686611722141727":{"questionID":"P000025","answers":["CRESCAT SCIENTIA, VITA EXCOLATUR (\"LET KNOWLEDGE INCREASE, LET LIFE BE PERFECTED\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Chicago*?"},"1308686617510412318":{"questionID":"P000092","answers":["(GUTTAE) DROPS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *g.t.t.*?"},"1308686623311003678":{"questionID":"P000203","answers":["A CLEAN SLATE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *tabula rasa*?"},"1308686632718696469":{"questionID":"P000001","answers":["PRO ECCLESIA, PRO TEXANA (\"FOR CHURCH, FOR TEXAS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Baylor University*?"},"1308686638419017730":{"questionID":"P000030","answers":["SALUS POPULI. (\"THE WELFARE OF THE PEOPLE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Missouri*?"},"1308686668835979294":{"questionID":"P000032","answers":["LUX HOMINUM VITA. (\"LIGHT OF THE LIFE OF MEN.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of New Mexico*?"},"1308686776633917440":{"questionID":"P000119","answers":["(FOLIO RECTO) ON THE RIGHT-HAND PAGE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *f.r.*?"},"1308686795290054687":{"questionID":"P000012","answers":["LUX ET VERITAS (\"LIGHT AND TRUTH\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Indiana University Bloomington*?"},"1308686804513456148":{"questionID":"P000146","answers":["SPEAK ONLY GOOD OF THE DEAD"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *De mortuis nil nisi bonum*?"},"1308686824599851048":{"questionID":"P000016","answers":["QUAECUM SUNT VERA (\"WHATEVER IS TRUE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Northwestern University*?"},"1308686830752759871":{"questionID":"P000001","answers":["PRO ECCLESIA, PRO TEXANA (\"FOR CHURCH, FOR TEXAS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Baylor University*?"},"1308687072000872500":{"questionID":"P000027","answers":["ET DOCERE ET RERUM EXQUIRERE CAUSAS (\"BOTH TO TEACH & TO INQUIRE INTO THE CAUSES OF THINGS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Georgia*?"},"1308687091684737056":{"questionID":"P000219","answers":["THE DIE IS CAST"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Alea iacta est**."},"1308687103898419210":{"questionID":"P000064","answers":["JOANNES EST NOMAN EIUS (\"JOHN IS HIS NAME.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Puerto Rico*?"},"1308687111704018977":{"questionID":"P000073","answers":["SPERAMUS MELIORA, RESURGET CINERIBUS (\"WE HOPE FOR BETTER THINGS, IT WILL RISE FROM THE ASHES\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Detroit*?"},"1308687117357940778":{"questionID":"P000224","answers":["IN THIS SIGN YOU WILL CONQUER"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **In hoc signo vinces**."},"1308687122789564426":{"questionID":"P000009","answers":["DEUS NOBIS FIDUCIA (\"GOD IS OUR TRUST\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *George Washington University*?"},"1308687134630350868":{"questionID":"P000006","answers":["IN LUMINE TUO VIDEBIMUS LUMEN. (\"IN THY LIGHT, WE SHALL SEE LIGHT.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Columbia University*?"},"1308687237554245652":{"questionID":"P000031","answers":["LITTERIS DEDICATA ET OMNIBUS ARTIBUS (\"DEDICATED TO LETTERS AND ALL THE ARTS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Nebraska*?"},"1308687245183680584":{"questionID":"P000084","answers":["\"A NEW ORDER OF THE AGES\""],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate \"Novus Ordo Seclorum,\" a Latin motto on the US $1 bill."},"1308687252653871134":{"questionID":"P000100","answers":["(QUOTIDIANUS) DAILY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *quot.*?"},"1308687259918274630":{"questionID":"P000027","answers":["ET DOCERE ET RERUM EXQUIRERE CAUSAS (\"BOTH TO TEACH & TO INQUIRE INTO THE CAUSES OF THINGS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Georgia*?"},"1308687265198899212":{"questionID":"P000192","answers":["HOW MUCH"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Quantum*?"},"1308687273415413831":{"questionID":"P000232","answers":["ALAS, THE FLEETING YEARS GLIDE BY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Eheu fugaces labuntur anni**."},"1308687292063551588":{"questionID":"P000083","answers":["CITIUS, ALTIUS, FORTIUS (\"FASTER, HIGHER, STRONGER\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Olympics*?"},"1308687299550253106":{"questionID":"P000244","answers":["WHO WILL GUARD THE GUARDS THEMSELVES?"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Quis custodiet ipsos custodes?**."},"1308687305455960135":{"questionID":"P000170","answers":["WITHOUT PREPARATION"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Ex tempore*?"},"1308687312871231498":{"questionID":"P000111","answers":["(DEO VOLENTE) GOD WILLING"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *D.V.*?"},"1308687319070543882":{"questionID":"P000179","answers":["BY THE VERY FACT ITSELF"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *ipso facto*?"},"1308687331523559466":{"questionID":"P000014","answers":["PRODESSE QUAM CONSPICI. (\"TO THE PRODUCTIVE, RATHER THAN TO BE ORNAMENTAL.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Miami University of Ohio*?"},"1308687338083188790":{"questionID":"P000023","answers":["PAX ET LUX (\"PEACE AND LIGHT\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Tufts University*?"},"1308687343217147935":{"questionID":"P000023","answers":["PAX ET LUX (\"PEACE AND LIGHT\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Tufts University*?"},"1308687348581797919":{"questionID":"P000034","answers":["MENS AGITAT MOLEM (\"MIND MOVES THE MASS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Oregon*?"},"1308687354701283329":{"questionID":"P000124","answers":["(LOCO CITATO) IN A PREVIOUSLY CITED PLACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *loc. cit.*?"},"1308687366323441725":{"questionID":"P000033","answers":["CIVI ET REI PUBLICAE (\"FOR THE CITIZEN AND THE STATE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Oklahoma*?"},"1308687462129995796":{"questionID":"P000147","answers":["YOU HIT THE NAIL ON THE HEAD"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *rem acu tetigisti*?"},"1308687488813891604":{"questionID":"P000124","answers":["(LOCO CITATO) IN A PREVIOUSLY CITED PLACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *loc. cit.*?"},"1308687497244577822":{"questionID":"P000218","answers":["CAESAR"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Alea iacta est**?"},"1308687504697983026":{"questionID":"P000021","answers":["PRO ECCLESIA ET PATRIA. (\"FOR CHURCH AND COUNTRY.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Trinity College*?"},"1308687665935286323":{"questionID":"P000099","answers":["(QUANTUM SUFFICIAT) AS MUCH AS NEEDED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *q.s.*?"},"1308687675338788897":{"questionID":"P000070","answers":["CEDANT ARMA TOGAE (\"LET ARMS YIELD TO THE TOGA\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Wyoming*?"},"1308687683140194345":{"questionID":"P000244","answers":["WHO WILL GUARD THE GUARDS THEMSELVES?"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Quis custodiet ipsos custodes?**."},"1308687689494827051":{"questionID":"P000124","answers":["(LOCO CITATO) IN A PREVIOUSLY CITED PLACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *loc. cit.*?"},"1308687698587942933":{"questionID":"P000038","answers":["STUDIIS ET REBUS HONESTIS (\"BY HONORABLE PURSUITS AND DEEDS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Vermont*?"},"1308687707035271188":{"questionID":"P000018","answers":["DOMINUS ILLUMINATIO MEA (\"THE LORD IS MY LIGHT\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Oxford University*?"},"1308687715323215932":{"questionID":"P000220","answers":["CROSSING THE RUBICON"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Before what major event did Caesar say **Alea iacta est**?"},"1308687738513391616":{"questionID":"P000173","answers":["IN ABSENCE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *In absentia*?"},"1308687752916631553":{"questionID":"P000175","answers":["IN THE PLACE OF A PARENT"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *in loco parentis*?"},"1308687759703277590":{"questionID":"P000072","answers":["URBS IN HORTO (\"CITY IN A GARDEN\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Chicago*?"},"1308687767248572426":{"questionID":"P000192","answers":["HOW MUCH"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Quantum*?"},"1308687774840389656":{"questionID":"P000014","answers":["PRODESSE QUAM CONSPICI. (\"TO THE PRODUCTIVE, RATHER THAN TO BE ORNAMENTAL.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Miami University of Ohio*?"},"1308687787259854908":{"questionID":"P000214","answers":["THE STORY IS FINISHED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Acta est fabula**."},"1308687819069460490":{"questionID":"P000013","answers":["VERITAS VOS LIBERABIT. (\"TRUTH WILL FREE YOU.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Johns Hopkins University*?"},"1308687825956372530":{"questionID":"P000107","answers":["(AB URBE CONDITA, ANNO URBIS CONDITAE) FROM THE FOUNDING OF THE CITY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *a.u.c.*?"},"1308687836848848926":{"questionID":"P000206","answers":["A CONSTANT COMPANION (GO WITH ME)"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *vade mecum*?"},"1308688066482798632":{"questionID":"P000051","answers":["AD ASTRA PER ASPERA (\"TO THE STARS THROUGH DIFFICULTIES\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Kansas*?"},"1308688092764311582":{"questionID":"P000060","answers":["CRESCIT EUNDO (\"IT GROWS AS IT GOES\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *New Mexico*?"},"1308688101098520586":{"questionID":"P000167","answers":["IN FACT","ACTUALLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *De facto*?"},"1308688114897649715":{"questionID":"P000245","answers":["NERO"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Qualis artifex pereo**?"},"1308688123156234260":{"questionID":"P000037","answers":["ECCE QUAM BONAM (\"BEHOLD HOW GOOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of the South (Sewanee)*?"},"1308688132731834398":{"questionID":"P000204","answers":["TIME FLIES"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *tempus fugit*?"},"1308688141481152512":{"questionID":"P000024","answers":["CIVIUM IN MORIBUS REI PUBLIAE SALUS. (\"IN THE CHARACTER OF ITS CITIZENS LIES THE WELFARE OF THE STATE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Univ. Florida*?"},"1308688149957836860":{"questionID":"P000242","answers":["BREAD AND CIRCUS GAMES"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Panem et circenses**."},"1308688157004267562":{"questionID":"P000122","answers":["(IBIDEM) IN THE SAME PLACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *ibid.*?"},"1308688167410470912":{"questionID":"P000036","answers":["DISCIPLINA PRAESIDIUM CIVITATIS (\"INSTRUCTION IS THE SAFEGUARD OF THE STATE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Texas*?"},"1308688175908257882":{"questionID":"P000146","answers":["SPEAK ONLY GOOD OF THE DEAD"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *De mortuis nil nisi bonum*?"},"1308688186486030358":{"questionID":"P000158","answers":["NOURISHING MOTHER (FOR ANY SCHOOL/COLLEGE)"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Alma mater*?"},"1308810540944199732":{"questionID":"P000182","answers":["WITH THE NECESSARY CHANGES HAVING BEEN MADE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *mutatis mutandis*?"},"1308810572090970182":{"questionID":"P000004","answers":["DEUS LUX MEA (\"GOD IS MY LIGHT\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Catholic University of America*?"},"1308810592055857172":{"questionID":"P000177","answers":["IN MEMORY OF"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *in memoriam*?"},"1308810614776528968":{"questionID":"P000123","answers":["(INFRA DIGNITATEM) BENEATH ONE'S DIGNITY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *Infra. dig.*?"},"1308810708233748541":{"questionID":"P000093","answers":["(HORA SOMNI) AT BEDTIME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *h.s.*?"},"1308810827637460993":{"questionID":"P000211","answers":["AUGUSTUS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Festina lente**?"},"1308810835367563304":{"questionID":"P000106","answers":["(ANTE MERIDIEM) BEFORE MIDDAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *A.M.*?"},"1308810844766732359":{"questionID":"P000213","answers":["AUGUSTUS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Acta est fabula**?"},"1308810912630837318":{"questionID":"P000164","answers":["LET THE BUYER BEWARE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Caveat emptor*?"},"1308810920083980359":{"questionID":"P000120","answers":["(FOLIO VERSO) ON THE LEFT HAND PAGE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *f.v.*?"},"1308810940061581403":{"questionID":"P000139","answers":["(VIDE SUPER) SEE ABOVE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *v.s.*?"},"1308811057573138482":{"questionID":"P000235","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **parturient montes, nasceture ridiculus mus**?"},"1308811065391452285":{"questionID":"P000080","answers":["AD MAIOREM DEI GLORIAM (\"FOR THE GREATER GLORY OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Society of Jesuits*?"},"1308811071565336739":{"questionID":"P000214","answers":["THE STORY IS FINISHED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Acta est fabula**."},"1308811193401479199":{"questionID":"P000201","answers":["ONE OF A KIND"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *sui generis*?"},"1308811314969317510":{"questionID":"P000113","answers":["(ET ALIA) AND OTHERS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *et al.*?"},"1308811352042897492":{"questionID":"P000206","answers":["A CONSTANT COMPANION (GO WITH ME)"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *vade mecum*?"},"1308811416953819146":{"questionID":"P000130","answers":["(PINXIT) HE PAINTED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *pinx.*?"},"1308811467113631766":{"questionID":"P000241","answers":["JUVENAL"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Panem et circenses**?"},"1308811484280913981":{"questionID":"P000250","answers":["TIME, THE DEVOURER OF ALL THINGS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Tempus edax rerum**."},"1308811541155549205":{"questionID":"P000027","answers":["ET DOCERE ET RERUM EXQUIRERE CAUSAS (\"BOTH TO TEACH & TO INQUIRE INTO THE CAUSES OF THINGS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Georgia*?"},"1308811593458384927":{"questionID":"P000027","answers":["ET DOCERE ET RERUM EXQUIRERE CAUSAS (\"BOTH TO TEACH & TO INQUIRE INTO THE CAUSES OF THINGS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Georgia*?"},"1308811641990680596":{"questionID":"P000198","answers":["WITHOUT CHILDREN"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *sine prole*?"},"1308811648479526912":{"questionID":"P000034","answers":["MENS AGITAT MOLEM (\"MIND MOVES THE MASS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Oregon*?"},"1308812830551703642":{"questionID":"P000229","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Dulce et decorum est pro patria mori**?"},"1308813667881451612":{"questionID":"P000113","answers":["(ET ALIA) AND OTHERS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *et al.*?"},"1308813806352334918":{"questionID":"P000253","answers":["CALIGULA (POSSIBLY TIBERIUS)"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Oderint dum metuant**?"},"1308813987223179404":{"questionID":"P000242","answers":["BREAD AND CIRCUS GAMES"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Panem et circenses**."},"1308814102151299102":{"questionID":"P000105","answers":["(ANNO DOMINI) IN THE YEAR OF OUR LORD"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *A.D.*?"},"1308814274445185044":{"questionID":"P000219","answers":["THE DIE IS CAST"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Alea iacta est**."},"1308814287275425883":{"questionID":"P000176","answers":["IN THE MIDDLE OF THINGS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *in medias res*?"},"1308814295114584065":{"questionID":"P000130","answers":["(PINXIT) HE PAINTED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *pinx.*?"},"1308814303645929573":{"questionID":"P000079","answers":["ARS ARTIS GRATIA (\"ART FOR THE SAKE OF ART\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer*?"},"1308814493450502164":{"questionID":"P000090","answers":["(ANTE CIBOS) BEFORE MEALS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *a.c.*?"},"1308814500685680751":{"questionID":"P000235","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **parturient montes, nasceture ridiculus mus**?"},"1308814543975223406":{"questionID":"P000041","answers":["PER VIRTUTEM VIS (\"STRENGTH THROUGH VIRTUE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Washington University*?"},"1308814555513622549":{"questionID":"P000022","answers":["NON SIBI, SED SUIS. (\"NOT FOR HERSELF, BUT FOR HER OWN.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Tulane University*?"},"1308814565663969360":{"questionID":"P000252","answers":["TO ERR IS HUMAN"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Errare humanum est**."},"1308814662380425309":{"questionID":"P000148","answers":["ON THE RIGHT"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *a dextra*?"},"1308814815745146900":{"questionID":"P000024","answers":["CIVIUM IN MORIBUS REI PUBLIAE SALUS. (\"IN THE CHARACTER OF ITS CITIZENS LIES THE WELFARE OF THE STATE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Univ. Florida*?"},"1308814926722240545":{"questionID":"P000254","answers":["LET THEM HATE ME PROVIDED THAT THEY FEAR ME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Oderint dum metuant**."},"1308815060411355188":{"questionID":"P000034","answers":["MENS AGITAT MOLEM (\"MIND MOVES THE MASS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Oregon*?"},"1308815127088201769":{"questionID":"P000147","answers":["YOU HIT THE NAIL ON THE HEAD"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *rem acu tetigisti*?"},"1308815136160616500":{"questionID":"P000089","answers":["DIS MINIBUS (\"TO THE SPIRITS OF THE DEAD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *D.M.*?"},"1308815177994469508":{"questionID":"P000002","answers":["NIL SINE MAGNO LABORE. (\"NOTHING WITHOUT GREAT EFFORT.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Brooklyn College*?"},"1308815185951330435":{"questionID":"P000118","answers":["(FLORUIT) PERIOD OF TIME DURING WHICH A PERSON OR THING FLOURISHED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *fl.*?"},"1309006450470686760":{"questionID":"H001272","answers":["378 AD"],"genus":"history","question":"In what year was Valens captured by the Goths at Adrianople?"},"1309006501154783232":{"questionID":"H000985","answers":["MUSHROOMS"],"genus":"history","question":"What poisonous food was said to have killed Claudius?"},"1309006596600238080":{"questionID":"H000347","answers":["HELD HIS RIGHT HAND IN A FIRE TO SHOW LARS PORSENNA THE ROMANS WOULD NOT SURRENDER"],"genus":"history","question":"How did Mucius Scaevola earn his cognomen?"},"1309013409551089736":{"questionID":"H001244","answers":["CHRISTIANITY"],"genus":"history","question":"What religion did Constantine make the official religion of the empire?"},"1309013821024894976":{"questionID":"H000837","answers":["ALEA IACTA EST"],"genus":"history","question":"What did Caesar reportedly say before crossing the Rubicon in 49 BC?"},"1309697701352570880":{"questionID":"L1002018","answers":["facto"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *factum, facti* (deed, act)?"},"1309697750585180225":{"questionID":"L1021584","answers":["reppererant"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *reperio* (to find)?"},"1309700775311708160":{"questionID":"D000146","answers":["cauda"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *cue* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1309750222611812382":{"questionID":"P000206","answers":["A CONSTANT COMPANION (GO WITH ME)"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *vade mecum*?"},"1309750286067302420":{"questionID":"P000158","answers":["NOURISHING MOTHER (FOR ANY SCHOOL/COLLEGE)"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Alma mater*?"},"1309750304866304061":{"questionID":"P000055","answers":["ENSE PETIT PLACIDAM SUB LIBERTATE QUIETEM (\"WITH THE SWORD HE SEEKS PEACE UNDER LIBERTY\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Massachusettes*?"},"1309750327804694548":{"questionID":"P000191","answers":["AFTER CHILDBIRTH"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *post partum*?"},"1309752028809138196":{"questionID":"P000002","answers":["NIL SINE MAGNO LABORE. (\"NOTHING WITHOUT GREAT EFFORT.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Brooklyn College*?"},"1309752054641725460":{"questionID":"P000041","answers":["PER VIRTUTEM VIS (\"STRENGTH THROUGH VIRTUE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Washington University*?"},"1309752061285634141":{"questionID":"P000022","answers":["NON SIBI, SED SUIS. (\"NOT FOR HERSELF, BUT FOR HER OWN.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Tulane University*?"},"1309752293628842036":{"questionID":"P000174","answers":["FOREVER"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *In aeternum*?"},"1309752302923419739":{"questionID":"P000001","answers":["PRO ECCLESIA, PRO TEXANA (\"FOR CHURCH, FOR TEXAS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Baylor University*?"},"1309752390152359986":{"questionID":"P000232","answers":["ALAS, THE FLEETING YEARS GLIDE BY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Eheu fugaces labuntur anni**."},"1309752512907182100":{"questionID":"P000231","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Eheu fugaces labuntur anni**?"},"1309752523560714342":{"questionID":"P000017","answers":["CRUX SPES UNICA (\"THE CROSS IS THE ONLY HOPE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Notre Dame University*?"},"1309752768373854218":{"questionID":"P000243","answers":["JUVENAL"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Quis custodiet ipsos custodes?**?"},"1309752780231282780":{"questionID":"P000138","answers":["(VIDE INFRA) SEE BELOW"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *v.i.*?"},"1309752871268519936":{"questionID":"P000239","answers":["JUVENAL"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Mens sana in corpore sano**?"},"1309752989031858246":{"questionID":"P000080","answers":["AD MAIOREM DEI GLORIAM (\"FOR THE GREATER GLORY OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Society of Jesuits*?"},"1310031488237965323":{"questionID":"P000101","answers":["(RECIPE) TAKE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *Rx*?"},"1310031525177331822":{"questionID":"P000190","answers":["AUTOPSY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *post mortem*?"},"1310032639406768269":{"questionID":"P000036","answers":["DISCIPLINA PRAESIDIUM CIVITATIS (\"INSTRUCTION IS THE SAFEGUARD OF THE STATE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Texas*?"},"1310033536895684699":{"questionID":"P000247","answers":["OVID"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Rident stolidi verba Latina**?"},"1310033562673741955":{"questionID":"P000231","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Eheu fugaces labuntur anni**?"},"1310033643573350430":{"questionID":"P000203","answers":["A CLEAN SLATE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *tabula rasa*?"},"1310033824499105822":{"questionID":"P000201","answers":["ONE OF A KIND"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *sui generis*?"},"1310033865129070754":{"questionID":"P000250","answers":["TIME, THE DEVOURER OF ALL THINGS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Tempus edax rerum**."},"1310033876629848214":{"questionID":"P000081","answers":["DUM VIVIMUS VIVAMUS (\"WHILE WE LIVE LET US LIVE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Epicureans*?"},"1310033995177660507":{"questionID":"P000018","answers":["DOMINUS ILLUMINATIO MEA (\"THE LORD IS MY LIGHT\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Oxford University*?"},"1310314848822886431":{"questionID":"D000564","answers":["panis"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *appanage* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1310354030886785065":{"questionID":"GMDR000323","answers":["instrument used to measure or count"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What does the Greek medical root **-meter** mean?"},"1310353989346525204":{"questionID":"GMDR001640","answers":["hepat-, hepatic- (e) meaning of or pertaining to the liver"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Identify a Greek medical root of **hepatology** (*study of the liver*)."},"1310354206796025896":{"questionID":"GMDR001274","answers":["chlor- (h) meaning denoting a green color"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Identify a Greek medical root of **chloroma** (*rare type of tumor containing green pigment*)."},"1310362670461091900":{"questionID":"GMDR003783","answers":["sigmoido-"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots appears in **sigmoiditis** (*inflammation of the sigmoid colon*)? The choices are *schisto-*, *schizo-*, *sclero-*, and *sigmoido-*."},"1310365856739364975":{"questionID":"GMDR002168","answers":["rod-like structures in some invertebrates (with **rhabdo-** meaning __rod shaped, striated__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **rhabdite**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *rhabd(o)-*."},"1310409922906685480":{"questionID":"H000420","answers":["CAUDINE FORKS"],"genus":"history","question":"At what battle in 321 BC did the Samnite force a Roman army to walk under the yoke?"},"1310409943429419098":{"questionID":"H000841","answers":["PHARSALUS"],"genus":"history","question":"At what battle in 48 BC did Caesar defeat Pompey and put him to flight?"},"1310409964904255569":{"questionID":"H000879","answers":["FULVIA AND LUCIUS ANTONY"],"genus":"history","question":"What wife and brother of Marc Antony did Octavian capture at Perusia?"},"1310411102135521425":{"questionID":"H000901","answers":["27 BC–14 AD"],"genus":"history","question":"What were the years of Augustus' reign?"},"1310431378160091166":{"questionID":"GMDR000719","answers":["blepharo-"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots implies **of or pertaining to the eyelid**? The choices are *blast-*, *blepharo-*, *brachy-*, and *brady-*."},"1310431332362489971":{"questionID":"GMDR001837","answers":["membrane around heart (with **peri-** meaning __denoting something with a position 'surrounding' or 'around' another__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **pericardium**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *peri-*."},"1310437796132946041":{"questionID":"GMDR002335","answers":["recording uterine contractions during labor (with **toco-** meaning __childbirth__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **tocography**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *toco-*."},"1310437911132377138":{"questionID":"GMDR002165","answers":["a condition involving the breakdown of muscle tissue, releasing harmful proteins into the bloodstream (with **rhabdo-** meaning __rod shaped, striated__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **rhabdomyolysis**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *rhabd(o)-*."},"1310438056599486547":{"questionID":"GMDR001884","answers":["canal carrying urine (with **ur-** meaning __of or pertaining to urine, the urinary system__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **urethra**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *ur-*."},"1310438633773465600":{"questionID":"GMDR001955","answers":["a performance or expression involving gestures and no speech (with **pan-** meaning __denoting something as 'complete' or containing 'everything'","\"all\"__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **pantomime**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *pan-, pant(o)-*."},"1310439088926625873":{"questionID":"GMDR000360","answers":["odyn- (meaning **pain**)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What Greek medical root comes from the Greek **ὀδύνη (odúnē)**?"},"1310439104672043048":{"questionID":"GMDR002069","answers":["a term used historically for seizures induced by electrical shock (with **-plexy** meaning __stroke or seizure__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **electroplexy**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *-plexy*."},"1310439307143807018":{"questionID":"GMDR002157","answers":["having a thick, stocky body build (with **pykno-** meaning __to thicken (as the nucleus does in early stages of cell death)__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **pyknic**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *pykno-*."},"1310439898171445329":{"questionID":"GMDR001640","answers":["small brain cells (with **micr-** meaning __millionth","denoting something as small, relating to smallness__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **microglia**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *micr-*."},"1310497592051765330":{"questionID":"GMDR000940","answers":["myelo-"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots implies **of or relating to bone marrow or the spinal cord**? The choices are *myri-*, *myo-*, *myelo-*, and *myco-*."},"1310497631553982485":{"questionID":"GMDR001269","answers":["brachy-"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots appears in **brachygnathia** (*abnormal shortness of jaw*)? The choices are *blast-*, *blepharo-*, *brachy-*, and *brady-*."},"1310497614008946779":{"questionID":"GMDR002282","answers":["combined action or cooperation (with **sy-** meaning __indicates similarity, likeness, or being together","assimilates before some consonants: before l to syl-, s to sys-, before a labial consonant to sym-__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **synergy**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *sy-, syl-, sym-, syn-, sys-*."},"1310497650637803581":{"questionID":"GMDR002098","answers":["a pigment involved in forming heme, a component of hemoglobin (with **porphyr-** meaning __denotes a purple color__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **porphyrin**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *porphyr-*."},"1310498681316704287":{"questionID":"D000614","answers":["piscis"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *porpoise* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1310500451405402142":{"questionID":"GMDR000633","answers":["turned toward, with an orientation toward, having an affinity for, affecting"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What does the Greek medical root **-trop** mean?"},"1310500766859001960":{"questionID":"GMDR000854","answers":["pachy-"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots implies **thick**? The choices are *pachy-*, *pleur-*, *phyllo-*, and *-plasty*."},"1310500857543917598":{"questionID":"GMDR000417","answers":["denotes something relating to digestion, or the digestive tract."],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What does the Greek medical root **-pepsia** mean?"},"1310500964607983627":{"questionID":"GMDR002362","answers":["congenital fissure of the neck (with **trachelo-** meaning __of or pertaining to the neck__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **tracheloschisis**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *trachel(o)-*."},"1310501045063122944":{"questionID":"GMDR000166","answers":["encephal(o)-, encephalo- (meaning **of or pertaining to the brain","see also cerebro-**)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What Greek medical root comes from the Greek **ἐγκέφαλος (enképhalos), the brain**?"},"1310501338949353492":{"questionID":"GMDR001990","answers":["an organism that eats wood (with **phagist-** meaning __feeder of or the act of feeding on__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **xylophagist**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *phagist-, -phagy*."},"1310501394171695166":{"questionID":"GMDR000092","answers":["chem(o)-, chemo- (meaning **chemistry, drug**)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What Greek medical root comes from the Greek **χημεία (khēmeía)**?"},"1310501458424102972":{"questionID":"GMDR002205","answers":["a fragmented part of a red blood cell (with **schisto-** meaning __split, cleft__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **schistocyte**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *schist(o)-*."},"1310501555279106058":{"questionID":"GMDR001744","answers":["ear pain (with **oto-** meaning __of or pertaining to the ear__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **otalgia**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *ot(o)-*."},"1310501837786447904":{"questionID":"GMDR001750","answers":["cutting into or drawing blood from a vein (with **phleb-** meaning __of or pertaining to the (blood) veins, a vein__","**-tomy** meaning __act of cutting","incising, incision__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **phlebotomy**, which is derived from the Greek medical roots *phleb-*; *-tomy*."},"1310502263013511188":{"questionID":"GMDR001990","answers":["an organism that eats wood (with **phagist-** meaning __feeder of or the act of feeding on__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **xylophagist**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *phagist-, -phagy*."},"1310503230903685180":{"questionID":"GMDR000311","answers":["extremity"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What does the Greek medical root **melos** mean?"},"1310503761386668034":{"questionID":"GMDR002275","answers":["excessively strong or vigorous (with **stheno-** meaning __strength, force, power__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **hypersthenic**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *stheno-*."},"1310503775491985469":{"questionID":"GMDR001577","answers":["white patches on mucous membranes (with **leuco-** meaning __denoting a white color__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **leukoplakia**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *leuc(o)-, leuk(o)-*."},"1310710936113512469":{"questionID":"GMDR000842","answers":["lyso-"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots implies **dissolution**? The choices are *lyso-*, *leuco-*, *-lysis*, and *lipo-*."},"1310711825536520304":{"questionID":"GMDR001691","answers":["eardrum repair (with **myri-** meaning __ten thousand__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **myringoplasty**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *myri-*."},"1310725688973594637":{"questionID":"H000791","answers":["ANTIUM"],"genus":"history","question":"Where did the prows used for the rostra come from?"},"1310786640524087376":{"questionID":"GMDR000483","answers":["denotes something as 'before' another (in [physical] position or time)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What does the Greek medical root **pro-** mean?"},"1310786659846979725":{"questionID":"GMDR000649","answers":["boil"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What does the Greek medical root **ze-** mean?"},"1310786619757953034":{"questionID":"GMDR001176","answers":["increased sensitivity (with **aesthesi-** meaning __sensation__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **hyperaesthesia**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *aesthesi- (Brit.)*."},"1310788540048605215":{"questionID":"GMDR001949","answers":["twins joined at the chest (with **-pagus** meaning __Indicates conjoined twins, with the first part denoting the organs fused__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **thoracopagus**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *-pagus*."},"1310788710408785950":{"questionID":"GMDR002304","answers":["pain in the nipple (with **thel-** meaning __of or pertaining to a nipple (uncommon as a prefix)__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **thelalgia**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *thel-*."},"1310790422649634936":{"questionID":"GMDR001196","answers":["myelo-"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots appears in **myelofibrosis** (*replacement of bone marrow with fibrous tissue*)? The choices are *myri-*, *myo-*, *myelo-*, and *myco-*."},"1310792676123344916":{"questionID":"GMDR000921","answers":["**-ectomy** meaning __denotes a surgical operation or removal of a body part","resection, excision__","**spleno-** meaning __spleen__ (and **splenectomy** meaning __removal of spleen__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **splenectomy**."},"1310794119395807333":{"questionID":"D000804","answers":["tempto"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *tentacle* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1310859225408213012":{"questionID":"D000581","answers":["parvus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *paraffin* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1310859263601807390":{"questionID":"D000336","answers":["fundo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *futile* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1310859244806869024":{"questionID":"D000163","answers":["cingo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *cinch* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1310859280244539512":{"questionID":"D000374","answers":["inter"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *enter* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1310861289479999590":{"questionID":"D000795","answers":["sum"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *puissance* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1310861409780760617":{"questionID":"D000487","answers":["moneo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *muster* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1310863784209813545":{"questionID":"GMDR000266","answers":["kine- (meaning **movement**)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What Greek medical root comes from the Greek **κινέω (kinéō), to move, to change**?"},"1311065076580483113":{"questionID":"GMDR000101","answers":["cartilage, gristle, granule, granular"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What does the Greek medical root **chondr(i)o-** mean?"},"1311065019638878328":{"questionID":"GMDR000588","answers":["-gen"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots implies **born in, from**? The choices are *-gen*, *-genic*, *galact-*, and *gastr-*."},"1311065040182317086":{"questionID":"GMDR001090","answers":["**laryngo-** meaning __of or pertaining to the larynx, the lower throat cavity where the voice box is__ (and **laryngitis** meaning __inflammation of larynx__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **laryngitis**."},"1311065059769974944":{"questionID":"GMDR001079","answers":["**kerat-** meaning __cornea (eye or skin)__ (and **LASIK** meaning __surgical reshaping of cornea with laser__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **LASIK**."},"1311065777872306176":{"questionID":"GMDR000769","answers":["**archi-** meaning __first, primitive__ (and **archipallium** meaning __primitive brain region__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **archipallium**."},"1311146495852019712":{"questionID":"D000196","answers":["costa"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *accost* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1311153267564089404":{"questionID":"GMDR000002","answers":["-ac (meaning **pertaining to","one afflicted with**)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What Greek medical root comes from the Greek **-ακός (-akós)**?"},"1311154740809175050":{"questionID":"D000726","answers":["sal"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *sauce* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1311495880024784917":{"questionID":"H001184","answers":["SHAPUR"],"genus":"history","question":"What Persian king captured Valerian at Edessa in 260 AD?"},"1311495923670585344":{"questionID":"H000852","answers":["46 BC"],"genus":"history","question":"In what year did Caesar win the battle of Thapsus against Pompey's sons & Cato the Younger?"},"1311496475628277813":{"questionID":"H000132","answers":["CLAUDIUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Which emperor advanced the efforts of his predecessor when he moved beyond the shores of Kent and conquered Britain in 43 AD?"},"1311523598225244200":{"questionID":"D000562","answers":["pango"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *impinge* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1311523634292068352":{"questionID":"D000545","answers":["oro"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *orison* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1311523650913964144":{"questionID":"D000462","answers":["memini"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *comment* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1311523616982040656":{"questionID":"D000648","answers":["prehendo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *entrepreneur* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1311524022558654475":{"questionID":"D000448","answers":["mando"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *commodore* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1311843868840562749":{"questionID":"D000282","answers":["exsul"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *exile* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1311843886293061683":{"questionID":"D000146","answers":["cauda"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *cue* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1311843849899081800":{"questionID":"D000174","answers":["claudo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *sluice* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1311843837810835466":{"questionID":"D000780","answers":["sto"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *arrest* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1311891887937818725":{"questionID":"D000609","answers":["pila"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *platoon* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1311891868757262406":{"questionID":"D000753","answers":["sero"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *assert* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1311896767998197830":{"questionID":"D000410","answers":["side","flank"],"genus":"derivative","question":"What is the definition of the Latin root that *lateral* derives from?"},"1311931244535353385":{"questionID":"GMDR000198","answers":["gluco- (meaning **sweet**)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What Greek medical root comes from the Greek **γλυκύς (glukús), sweet**?"},"1311931282086821931":{"questionID":"GMDR001018","answers":["**hetero-** meaning __denotes something as \"the other\" (of two), as an addition, or different__ (and **heteroplasty** meaning __surgical grafting from different species__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **heteroplasty**."},"1311952213647818755":{"questionID":"D000670","answers":["quails"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *kickshaw* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1312103448526979143":{"questionID":"D000517","answers":["nomen"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *renown* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1312103426104234055":{"questionID":"D000110","answers":["cano"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *charm* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1312103466038202378":{"questionID":"D000810","answers":["teneo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *rein* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1312110033613361293":{"questionID":"D000023","answers":["altus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *exalt* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1312146320684748810":{"questionID":"H000212","answers":["LAVINIA"],"genus":"history","question":"What daughter of King Latinus did Aeneas marry in Italy?"},"1312147755908595773":{"questionID":"H000979","answers":["BRITANNICUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Who was the son of Claudius and Messalina?"},"1312164421824544850":{"questionID":"D000312","answers":["focus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *foyer* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1312164442594873496":{"questionID":"D000162","answers":["cilium"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *supercilious* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1312164459695050774":{"questionID":"D000547","answers":["bone"],"genus":"derivative","question":"What is the definition of the Latin root that *osprey* derives from?"},"1312164477973561445":{"questionID":"D000200","answers":["cratis"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *grill* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1312164541496430763":{"questionID":"D000090","answers":["calx"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *cockatrice* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1312239642099318784":{"questionID":"H000580","answers":["PHILIP V"],"genus":"history","question":"What king of Macedon allied with Hannibal and attacked Rome in 215 BC?"},"1312277518539034625":{"questionID":"D000302","answers":["fingo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *feign* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1312277538810105947":{"questionID":"D000726","answers":["sal"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *sauce* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1312279417099128892":{"questionID":"GMDR000293","answers":["denotes someone who studies a certain field (the field of ------logy)","a specialist","one who treats"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What does the Greek medical root **-logist** mean?"},"1312279659664244848":{"questionID":"GMDR000837","answers":["**chromato-** meaning __color__ (and **chromatin** meaning __material of which chromosomes are composed__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **chromatin**."},"1312289251597090836":{"questionID":"D000685","answers":["racemus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *raisin* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1312636543436849242":{"questionID":"GMDR001068","answers":["**-ismus** meaning __spasm, contraction__ (and **vaginismus** meaning __vaginal muscle spasm__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **vaginismus**."},"1312636595379372072":{"questionID":"GMDR001151","answers":["**met-** meaning __after, beside, beyond or change__","**-stasis** meaning __stopping, standing__ (and **metastasis** meaning __spread of disease__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **metastasis**."},"1312637261593972768":{"questionID":"GMDR000858","answers":["**cor-** meaning __of or pertaining to the eye's pupil__ (and **corectomy** meaning __excision of part of the iris__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **corectomy**."},"1313305633495453737":{"questionID":"A000006","answers":["aeido (αειδω), to sing"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **ode**?"},"1313305679825604710":{"questionID":"A000627","answers":["little, small... micros (μικρος)","behold, examine, inspect, consider, see... skopeo (σκοπεω)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **microscope**?"},"1313309870472171520":{"questionID":"A000715","answers":["water... hydor (ὑδωρ)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **hydrochloric**?"},"1313341989881647154":{"questionID":"A000198","answers":["monos (μονος), alone","gamos (γαμος), wedding, marriage"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **monogamous**?"},"1313341966250938378":{"questionID":"A000179","answers":["book... biblos (βιβλος)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **Bible**?"},"1313394938188136459":{"questionID":"A000342","answers":["theomai (θεαομαι), to behold"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **theory**?"},"1313394892709433344":{"questionID":"A000166","answers":["ballo (βαλλω), throw"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **parliament**?"},"1313395301532307487":{"questionID":"A000535","answers":["homos (ὁμος)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What Greek word means **one and the same, like**?"},"1313756790399303681":{"questionID":"D000260","answers":["emo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *exempt* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1313759614021533748":{"questionID":"D000169","answers":["clamo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *clarity* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1313759978930311198":{"questionID":"D000658","answers":["pretium"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *price* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1313760924431286302":{"questionID":"D000434","answers":["ligo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *liaison* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1313761571297689612":{"questionID":"P000079","answers":["ARS ARTIS GRATIA (\"ART FOR THE SAKE OF ART\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer*?"},"1313761580042682418":{"questionID":"D000553","answers":["palus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *travel* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1313761671554007060":{"questionID":"D000295","answers":["fido"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *federal* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1313761767314292737":{"questionID":"P000106","answers":["(ANTE MERIDIEM) BEFORE MIDDAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *A.M.*?"},"1313761800856014910":{"questionID":"P000116","answers":["(FIDEI DEFENSOR) DEFENDER OF THE FAITH (A TITLE OF THE BRITISH MONARCHS)"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *F.D.*?"},"1313761825279447121":{"questionID":"P000208","answers":["WORD FOR WORD"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *verbatim*?"},"1313761904652714025":{"questionID":"P000135","answers":["(SINE GRATIA) WITHOUT EXAMPLE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *s.g.*?"},"1313761914941345804":{"questionID":"P000207","answers":["WOE TO THE CONQUERED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *vae victis*?"},"1313761921316425768":{"questionID":"P000107","answers":["(AB URBE CONDITA, ANNO URBIS CONDITAE) FROM THE FOUNDING OF THE CITY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *a.u.c.*?"},"1313762065302687744":{"questionID":"D000312","answers":["focus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *foyer* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1313762090858844180":{"questionID":"P000154","answers":["FOR THIS PURPOSE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *ad hoc*?"},"1313762140095647797":{"questionID":"D000827","answers":["torqueo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *torch* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1313762225952915456":{"questionID":"P000252","answers":["TO ERR IS HUMAN"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Errare humanum est**."},"1313762234668810240":{"questionID":"P000235","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **parturient montes, nasceture ridiculus mus**?"},"1313762241316655146":{"questionID":"P000164","answers":["LET THE BUYER BEWARE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Caveat emptor*?"},"1313762248614744135":{"questionID":"P000032","answers":["LUX HOMINUM VITA. (\"LIGHT OF THE LIFE OF MEN.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of New Mexico*?"},"1313762264880386110":{"questionID":"P000237","answers":["JUVENAL"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Dificile est saturam non scribere**?"},"1313762270811263037":{"questionID":"P000081","answers":["DUM VIVIMUS VIVAMUS (\"WHILE WE LIVE LET US LIVE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Epicureans*?"},"1313762277824004116":{"questionID":"P000129","answers":["(PASSIM) EVERYWHERE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *pass.*?"},"1313762284857856040":{"questionID":"P000094","answers":["(OCULUS DEXTER) RIGHT EYE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *o.d.*?"},"1313762290880876556":{"questionID":"P000142","answers":["FROM THE BOTTOM OF THE HEART"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *ab imo pectore*?"},"1313762297231179879":{"questionID":"P000228","answers":["SEIZE THE DAY, TRUSTING AS LITTLE AS POSSIBLE IN TOMORROW"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Carpe diem, quam minimum credula postero**."},"1313762303564316762":{"questionID":"P000011","answers":["MIHI CURA FUTURI. (\"MY ANXIETY IS FOR THE FUTURE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Hunter College*?"},"1313763668957073459":{"questionID":"P000060","answers":["CRESCIT EUNDO (\"IT GROWS AS IT GOES\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *New Mexico*?"},"1313763679250153492":{"questionID":"P000081","answers":["DUM VIVIMUS VIVAMUS (\"WHILE WE LIVE LET US LIVE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Epicureans*?"},"1313763689408757760":{"questionID":"P000016","answers":["QUAECUM SUNT VERA (\"WHATEVER IS TRUE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Northwestern University*?"},"1313763695125598270":{"questionID":"P000085","answers":["\"HE LOOKS WITH FAVOR ON OUR UNDERTAKINGS\""],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate \"Annuit Coeptis,\" a Latin motto of the US."},"1313763703128199250":{"questionID":"P000135","answers":["(SINE GRATIA) WITHOUT EXAMPLE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *s.g.*?"},"1313763712984813639":{"questionID":"P000077","answers":["SEMPER PARATUS (\"ALWAYS READY\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Coast Guard*?"},"1313763774003679265":{"questionID":"P000002","answers":["NIL SINE MAGNO LABORE. (\"NOTHING WITHOUT GREAT EFFORT.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Brooklyn College*?"},"1313763782635294761":{"questionID":"P000099","answers":["(QUANTUM SUFFICIAT) AS MUCH AS NEEDED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *q.s.*?"},"1313763792336977981":{"questionID":"P000047","answers":["NIL SINE NUMINE (\"NOTHING WITHOUT GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Colorado*?"},"1313763799043674143":{"questionID":"P000024","answers":["CIVIUM IN MORIBUS REI PUBLIAE SALUS. (\"IN THE CHARACTER OF ITS CITIZENS LIES THE WELFARE OF THE STATE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Univ. Florida*?"},"1313763960281108510":{"questionID":"P000005","answers":["RESPICE, ADSPICE, PROSPICE. (\"LOOK BACK, LOOK TO THE PRESENT, LOOK TO THE FUTURE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *City College of NY*?"},"1313764208776577106":{"questionID":"P000246","answers":["WHAT IN ARTIST DIES IN ME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Qualis artifex pereo**."},"1313764254662524938":{"questionID":"P000022","answers":["NON SIBI, SED SUIS. (\"NOT FOR HERSELF, BUT FOR HER OWN.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Tulane University*?"},"1313764422514118686":{"questionID":"P000147","answers":["YOU HIT THE NAIL ON THE HEAD"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *rem acu tetigisti*?"},"1313764441543802920":{"questionID":"P000054","answers":["CRESCITE ET MULTIPLICAMINI (\"INCREASE AND MULTIPLY\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Maryland*?"},"1313764449315979327":{"questionID":"P000007","answers":["VOX CLAMANTIS IN DESERTO. (\"A VOICE OF ONE CRYING IN THE WILDERNESS.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Dartmouth College*?"},"1313764455586205726":{"questionID":"P000005","answers":["RESPICE, ADSPICE, PROSPICE. (\"LOOK BACK, LOOK TO THE PRESENT, LOOK TO THE FUTURE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *City College of NY*?"},"1313764610804940871":{"questionID":"P000067","answers":["DUM SPIRO, SPERO (\"WHILE I BREATHE, I HOPE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *South Carolina*?"},"1313764983602937867":{"questionID":"P000032","answers":["LUX HOMINUM VITA. (\"LIGHT OF THE LIFE OF MEN.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of New Mexico*?"},"1313764993203830855":{"questionID":"P000063","answers":["LABOR OMNIA VINCIT (\"WORK CONQUERS ALL\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Oklahoma*?"},"1313765002985082930":{"questionID":"P000054","answers":["CRESCITE ET MULTIPLICAMINI (\"INCREASE AND MULTIPLY\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Maryland*?"},"1313765010094161980":{"questionID":"P000011","answers":["MIHI CURA FUTURI. (\"MY ANXIETY IS FOR THE FUTURE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Hunter College*?"},"1313765015760797716":{"questionID":"P000151","answers":["FROM THE BEGINNING"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *ab initio*?"},"1313765397446529094":{"questionID":"P000012","answers":["LUX ET VERITAS (\"LIGHT AND TRUTH\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Indiana University Bloomington*?"},"1313765405478883338":{"questionID":"P000146","answers":["SPEAK ONLY GOOD OF THE DEAD"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *De mortuis nil nisi bonum*?"},"1313765420599214090":{"questionID":"P000208","answers":["WORD FOR WORD"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *verbatim*?"},"1313891670852636703":{"questionID":"D000028","answers":["ante"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *ancient* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1313891653190418493":{"questionID":"D000809","answers":["teneo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *abstain* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1313891688862846996":{"questionID":"D000627","answers":["plecto"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *pleat* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1313891706944360510":{"questionID":"D000807","answers":["tendo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *standard* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1313892819907379200":{"questionID":"D000506","answers":["nego"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *renegade* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1313893637590876223":{"questionID":"P000244","answers":["WHO WILL GUARD THE GUARDS THEMSELVES?"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Quis custodiet ipsos custodes?**."},"1313893646256439367":{"questionID":"P000254","answers":["LET THEM HATE ME PROVIDED THAT THEY FEAR ME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Oderint dum metuant**."},"1313893731186774097":{"questionID":"P000142","answers":["FROM THE BOTTOM OF THE HEART"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *ab imo pectore*?"},"1313893742004011008":{"questionID":"P000080","answers":["AD MAIOREM DEI GLORIAM (\"FOR THE GREATER GLORY OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Society of Jesuits*?"},"1313893914683510905":{"questionID":"P000153","answers":["TO ONE'S TASTE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *ad gustum*?"},"1313893923416051723":{"questionID":"P000051","answers":["AD ASTRA PER ASPERA (\"TO THE STARS THROUGH DIFFICULTIES\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Kansas*?"},"1313893974028587059":{"questionID":"P000133","answers":["(SCILICET) ACTUALLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *sc.*?"},"1313893983063244870":{"questionID":"P000234","answers":["I HAVE RAISED A MONUMENT MORE LASTING THAN BRONZE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Exegi monumentum aere perennius**."},"1313893991481217088":{"questionID":"P000079","answers":["ARS ARTIS GRATIA (\"ART FOR THE SAKE OF ART\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer*?"},"1313893997797707816":{"questionID":"P000225","answers":["DESCARTES"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous person said **Cogito ergo sum**?"},"1313894203130122240":{"questionID":"P000209","answers":["BY WAY OF"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *via*?"},"1313894213410095114":{"questionID":"P000138","answers":["(VIDE INFRA) SEE BELOW"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *v.i.*?"},"1313894221022892143":{"questionID":"P000088","answers":["SIT TIBI TERRA LEVIS (\"MAY THE EARTH REST LIGHTLY ON YOU\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *S.T.T.L.*?"},"1314132778370990130":{"questionID":"LFIFTH001803","answers":["candidi"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine nominative plural** of *candidus* (white, clear)?"},"1314132824487493632":{"questionID":"LFIFTH001778","answers":["blando"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter ablative singular** of *blandus* (agreeable)?"},"1314137697832665109":{"questionID":"LFIFTH004001","answers":["laceravisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *lacero* (to tear to pieces, to lacerate)?"},"1314784903593853028":{"questionID":"H000520","answers":["HANNIBAL"],"genus":"history","question":"What enemy of Rome crossed the Alps with 37 war elephants in 219 BC?"},"1314784934904463432":{"questionID":"H000225","answers":["RHEA SILVIA"],"genus":"history","question":"What daughter of Numitor did Amulius force to become a Vestal Virgin?"},"1314786357838610462":{"questionID":"H000678","answers":["JUGURTHINE WAR"],"genus":"history","question":"What war did the Romans fight from 111–104 BC?"},"1315488625659482172":{"questionID":"P000200","answers":["SECRETLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Sub rosa*?"},"1315530283088609290":{"questionID":"P000006","answers":["IN LUMINE TUO VIDEBIMUS LUMEN. (\"IN THY LIGHT, WE SHALL SEE LIGHT.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Columbia University*?"},"1315530308447375441":{"questionID":"P000176","answers":["IN THE MIDDLE OF THINGS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *in medias res*?"},"1315530327170613288":{"questionID":"P000170","answers":["WITHOUT PREPARATION"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Ex tempore*?"},"1315530848484986940":{"questionID":"P000201","answers":["ONE OF A KIND"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *sui generis*?"},"1315531340044697701":{"questionID":"P000140","answers":["(VIDELICET) NAMELY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *viz.*?"},"1315531711509172234":{"questionID":"P000162","answers":["JUSTIFICATION FOR WAR"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Casus Belli*?"},"1316988985427628082":{"questionID":"H000426","answers":["APPIUS CLAUDIUS CAECUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Who built a road from Rome to Capua which helped the Romans win the 2nd Samnite War?"},"1316993319921782804":{"questionID":"H000437","answers":["2","TWO"],"genus":"history","question":"How many censors served at once?"},"1318067523257897061":{"questionID":"H000195","answers":["COMMODUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What emperor could allegedly hit an ostrich with a javelin at 50 paces and could frequently be seen in the arena dressed as Hercules?"},"1318067497114796092":{"questionID":"H001243","answers":["CONSTANTINE"],"genus":"history","question":"Which emperor made Christianity the official religion of the empire?"},"1318067563204444201":{"questionID":"H001140","answers":["CARACALLA & GETA"],"genus":"history","question":"Who were the two sons of Septimius Severus & Julia Domna?"},"1318067854729281586":{"questionID":"H001234","answers":["DIOCLETIAN"],"genus":"history","question":"Who was the first emperor to abdicate from power and retire?"},"1318072044826660894":{"questionID":"H001240","answers":["MAXIMIAN"],"genus":"history","question":"Which Tetrarch was the father of Maxentius?"},"1318072067031044156":{"questionID":"H001037","answers":["VESPASIAN"],"genus":"history","question":"Which emperor said on his deathbed \"vae, puto, deus fio\"?"},"1318415536446640241":{"questionID":"H001305","answers":["ODOACER"],"genus":"history","question":"What Germanic chieftain sacked Rome in 476 AD?"},"1318415501482790922":{"questionID":"H000743","answers":["SPARTACUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Whose rebellion was put down by Crassus?"},"1318420201745809439":{"questionID":"H000172","answers":["THEODOSIUS I"],"genus":"history","question":"Who was the last emperor to rule a united Roman Empire?"},"1318427641539203092":{"questionID":"H000158","answers":["DOMITIAN"],"genus":"history","question":"What emperor first led a campaign against Decebalus and the Dacians?"},"1318433840548810752":{"questionID":"H000635","answers":["SALTED THE FIELDS"],"genus":"history","question":"What did Scipio Aemilianus do to ensure Carthage would never be able to grow crops again?"},"1328933767292780605":{"questionID":"H000477","answers":["TO MAKE CARTHAGE LEAVE MESSANA"],"genus":"history","question":"Why did the Mamertines appeal to Rome for help?"},"1328933814944272514":{"questionID":"H000105","answers":["SATURNINUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Whose career as tribune began in 103 BC with legislation to provide land settlements to Marius' veterans and ended with a senatus consultum ultimum and a shower of roof tiles?"},"1328933900482777191":{"questionID":"H001045","answers":["TITUS'"],"genus":"history","question":"During which emperor's reign did Mt. Vesuvius erupt?"},"1328934633924067471":{"questionID":"H001096","answers":["161–180 AD"],"genus":"history","question":"What were the years of Marcus Aurelius' reign?"},"1328944788552028220":{"questionID":"H001139","answers":["ARCH OF SEPTIMIUS SEVERUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What structure in the Forum Romanum commemorates the military accomplishments of Septimius Severus?"},"1329300051364675624":{"questionID":"H000652","answers":["TIBERIUS GRACCHUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Who negotiated with Numantia for the release of 20,000 Roman soldiers in 137 BC?"},"1329300077294129233":{"questionID":"H000093","answers":["LEX TITIA"],"genus":"history","question":"What law of 43 BC legalized the Second Triumvirate?"},"1329300095472111700":{"questionID":"H000911","answers":["PANTHEON"],"genus":"history","question":"What temple did Augutus' chief leiutenant Agrippa build?"},"1329301778205904926":{"questionID":"H000666","answers":["TIBERIUS GRACCHUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What tribune of 133 BC was killed for proposing radical legislation which favored the plebeians?"},"1336882366127276073":{"questionID":"H000543","answers":["SYRACUSE"],"genus":"history","question":"What Sicilian city did Marcellus capture in 211 BC?"},"1336882347269685311":{"questionID":"H000422","answers":["WALK UNDER THE YOKE"],"genus":"history","question":"What sign of complete surrender did the Samnites force upon the Romans after the Caudine Forks?"},"1336882400235622441":{"questionID":"H000185","answers":["ADRIANOPLE"],"genus":"history","question":"At what battle of 378 AD was the emperor Valens killed in battle?"},"1336882328219287637":{"questionID":"H000813","answers":["QUAESTOR"],"genus":"history","question":"Which officials were in charge of Rome's finances?"},"1336882444321689641":{"questionID":"H001266","answers":["THE APOSTATE"],"genus":"history","question":"What name did Julian receive for trying to restore Pagan worship throughout the empire?"},"1336884926070394993":{"questionID":"H000522","answers":["218 BC"],"genus":"history","question":"In what year did Hannibal defeat Publius Cornelius Scipio and the Romans at the Ticinus River?"},"1336898219007021107":{"questionID":"H000054","answers":["CINCINNATUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What man did the Senate chose to be dictator to save the Romans at Mt. Algidus?"},"1336898254104690769":{"questionID":"H000785","answers":["43 BC"],"genus":"history","question":"In what year was Cicero executed at Formiae?"},"1336898313164689469":{"questionID":"H001112","answers":["MARCUS AURELIUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Which emperor put down the rebellion of Avidius Cassius?"},"1336900669151383643":{"questionID":"H000025","answers":["MINORES GENTES"],"genus":"history","question":"Tarquinnius Priscus enlarged the Senate by adding another 100 members, many of whom were probably Etruscan. What were these new members called?"},"1337277996649680966":{"questionID":"L1002160","answers":["astrum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative singular** of *astrum, astri* (star)?"},"1337277929855389756":{"questionID":"L1011213","answers":["mirabat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *miror* (to wonder, to be amazed, to admire)?"},"1337282960545550377":{"questionID":"LFIFTH002640","answers":["fideles"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine/feminine nominative plural** of *fidelis* (loyal, trusty, faithful)?"},"1337480440373575780":{"questionID":"L1015079","answers":["tenuistis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *teneo* (to hold, keep, possess)?"},"1337480465677815859":{"questionID":"L1020805","answers":["ieceram"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *iacio* (to throw)?"},"1337480401299570689":{"questionID":"L1022093","answers":["aperueritis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *aperio* (to uncover)?"},"1337481897823178772":{"questionID":"LFIFTH006300","answers":["coniunxit"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *coniungo* (to join)?"},"1337886014798172190":{"questionID":"L1008804","answers":["perferebatis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *perfero* (to bear through, endure to the end)?"},"1337885953410338826":{"questionID":"L1021601","answers":["oriebatis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *orior* (to rise, get up)?"},"1337886049971470407":{"questionID":"L1009713","answers":["vetat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *veto* (to forbid)?"},"1337886522632048722":{"questionID":"L1009495","answers":["abes"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active imperative** of *absum* (to be away, to be absent)?"},"1337886574821769357":{"questionID":"L1011953","answers":["dubitabatis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *dubito* (to be in doubt, to doubt)?"},"1337886614633840701":{"questionID":"L1007199","answers":["civili"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter ablative singular** of *civilis* (pertaining to the citizen)?"},"1339054242215755820":{"questionID":"GMDR000764","answers":["**cyano-** meaning __having a blue color__ (and **cyanopsia** meaning __blue vision__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **cyanopsia**."},"1339054287342538794":{"questionID":"GMDR000657","answers":["**aero-** meaning __air, gas__ (and **aeroembolism** meaning __air bubble in blood vessels__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **aeroembolism**."},"1339055360580911166":{"questionID":"P000109","answers":["(CONFER) COMPARE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *cf.*?"},"1339055530211147818":{"questionID":"L1010720","answers":["oras"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *oro* (to pray, to plead)?"},"1339055996055720007":{"questionID":"P000105","answers":["(ANNO DOMINI) IN THE YEAR OF OUR LORD"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *A.D.*?"},"1339056133846859806":{"questionID":"P000236","answers":["ALL THAT WORK AND NOTHING TO SHOW FOR IT"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **parturient montes, nasceture ridiculus mus**."},"1339057036587040768":{"questionID":"L1011262","answers":["mandamus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *mando* (to order, command)?"},"1339057269983150215":{"questionID":"L1010678","answers":["peccaveris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *pecco* (to commit a fault, to sin)?"},"1339057664629407886":{"questionID":"P000192","answers":["HOW MUCH"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Quantum*?"},"1339057959430262804":{"questionID":"P000114","answers":["(ET SEQUENS) AND THE FOLLOWING"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *et seq.*?"},"1339057968855126036":{"questionID":"P000164","answers":["LET THE BUYER BEWARE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Caveat emptor*?"},"1339058171767164988":{"questionID":"P000183","answers":["PERFECTION"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Ne plus ultra*?"},"1339058725079613440":{"questionID":"P000032","answers":["LUX HOMINUM VITA. (\"LIGHT OF THE LIFE OF MEN.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of New Mexico*?"},"1339059005733081108":{"questionID":"P000124","answers":["(LOCO CITATO) IN A PREVIOUSLY CITED PLACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *loc. cit.*?"},"1339059585339752469":{"questionID":"P000014","answers":["PRODESSE QUAM CONSPICI. (\"TO THE PRODUCTIVE, RATHER THAN TO BE ORNAMENTAL.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Miami University of Ohio*?"},"1339060057882759208":{"questionID":"P000240","answers":["A SOUND MIND IN A SOUND BODY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Mens sana in corpore sano**."},"1339062485558235207":{"questionID":"L1020971","answers":["effeceratis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *efficio* (to accomplish, make, form)?"},"1339062623458562108":{"questionID":"P000054","answers":["CRESCITE ET MULTIPLICAMINI (\"INCREASE AND MULTIPLY\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Maryland*?"},"1339062781860778075":{"questionID":"P000027","answers":["ET DOCERE ET RERUM EXQUIRERE CAUSAS (\"BOTH TO TEACH & TO INQUIRE INTO THE CAUSES OF THINGS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Georgia*?"},"1339063405146935296":{"questionID":"P000129","answers":["(PASSIM) EVERYWHERE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *pass.*?"},"1339063984438906990":{"questionID":"P000074","answers":["DOMINE, DIRIGE NOS (\"LORD, GUIDE US\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *London*?"},"1339064051954876458":{"questionID":"P000207","answers":["WOE TO THE CONQUERED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *vae victis*?"},"1339064061031219251":{"questionID":"P000163","answers":["BEWARE THE DOG"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Cave canem*?"},"1339064069096738866":{"questionID":"P000208","answers":["WORD FOR WORD"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *verbatim*?"},"1339064104727613573":{"questionID":"P000035","answers":["LEGES SINE MORIBUS VANAE (\"LAWS WITHOUT MORALS ARE USELESS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Pennsylvania*?"},"1339064346449547386":{"questionID":"P000090","answers":["(ANTE CIBOS) BEFORE MEALS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *a.c.*?"},"1339064355517366313":{"questionID":"P000171","answers":["THEREFORE, LET US REJOICE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Gaudeamus igitur*?"},"1339064371392938027":{"questionID":"P000036","answers":["DISCIPLINA PRAESIDIUM CIVITATIS (\"INSTRUCTION IS THE SAFEGUARD OF THE STATE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Texas*?"},"1339064383321673799":{"questionID":"P000134","answers":["(SENATUS CONSULTUM ULTIMUM) FINAL DECREE OF THE SENATE (MARITAL LAW)"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *S.C.U.*?"},"1339064391127269419":{"questionID":"P000123","answers":["(INFRA DIGNITATEM) BENEATH ONE'S DIGNITY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *Infra. dig.*?"},"1339064579657039902":{"questionID":"P000033","answers":["CIVI ET REI PUBLICAE (\"FOR THE CITIZEN AND THE STATE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Oklahoma*?"},"1339064754957717655":{"questionID":"P000011","answers":["MIHI CURA FUTURI. (\"MY ANXIETY IS FOR THE FUTURE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Hunter College*?"},"1339064764248100936":{"questionID":"P000033","answers":["CIVI ET REI PUBLICAE (\"FOR THE CITIZEN AND THE STATE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Oklahoma*?"},"1339065078028308645":{"questionID":"P000203","answers":["A CLEAN SLATE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *tabula rasa*?"},"1339065087478071367":{"questionID":"P000137","answers":["(SENATUS POPULUSQUE ROMANUS) THE SENATE AND POPULACE OF ROME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *S.P.Q.R.*?"},"1339065095212503111":{"questionID":"P000129","answers":["(PASSIM) EVERYWHERE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *pass.*?"},"1339065101117952031":{"questionID":"P000148","answers":["ON THE RIGHT"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *a dextra*?"},"1339065208982732860":{"questionID":"P000164","answers":["LET THE BUYER BEWARE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Caveat emptor*?"},"1339065316587737219":{"questionID":"P000081","answers":["DUM VIVIMUS VIVAMUS (\"WHILE WE LIVE LET US LIVE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Epicureans*?"},"1339065398989033593":{"questionID":"P000175","answers":["IN THE PLACE OF A PARENT"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *in loco parentis*?"},"1339065408678006866":{"questionID":"P000036","answers":["DISCIPLINA PRAESIDIUM CIVITATIS (\"INSTRUCTION IS THE SAFEGUARD OF THE STATE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Texas*?"},"1339065425023078440":{"questionID":"P000027","answers":["ET DOCERE ET RERUM EXQUIRERE CAUSAS (\"BOTH TO TEACH & TO INQUIRE INTO THE CAUSES OF THINGS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Georgia*?"},"1339065585643950221":{"questionID":"P000171","answers":["THEREFORE, LET US REJOICE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Gaudeamus igitur*?"},"1339065828146020403":{"questionID":"P000008","answers":["SAPIENTIA ET DOCTRINA. (\"WISDOM AND KNOWLEDGE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Fordham University*?"},"1339065836324917288":{"questionID":"P000235","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **parturient montes, nasceture ridiculus mus**?"},"1339100725493366815":{"questionID":"GMDR000068","answers":["-pepsia (meaning **denotes something relating to digestion, or the digestive tract.**)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What Greek medical root comes from the Greek **πεπτός (peptós), cooked, digested < πέσσω (péssō), I boil, cook; digest**?"},"1339100743814217788":{"questionID":"GMDR000304","answers":["zym(o)-, zymo- (meaning **fermentation**)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What Greek medical root comes from the Greek **ζύμη (zúmē), leaven, yeast**?"},"1339100708674342922":{"questionID":"GMDR000749","answers":["**omphalo-** meaning __of or pertaining to the navel, the umbilicus__ (and **omphalophobia** meaning __fear of navels__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **omphalophobia**."},"1339100688407334952":{"questionID":"GMDR001188","answers":["**-tony** meaning __tension__ (and **atony** meaning __lack of muscle tone__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **atony**."},"1339104609360285759":{"questionID":"P000061","answers":["EXCELSIOR! (\"HIGHER!\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *New York*?"},"1339104754130882581":{"questionID":"P000171","answers":["THEREFORE, LET US REJOICE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Gaudeamus igitur*?"},"1339104807931346954":{"questionID":"P000146","answers":["SPEAK ONLY GOOD OF THE DEAD"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *De mortuis nil nisi bonum*?"},"1339105916053622824":{"questionID":"L000287","answers":["MONUMENTUM ANCYRANUM"],"genus":"literature","question":"Where was Augustus' Res Gestae found inscribed?"},"1339106642112938045":{"questionID":"P000108","answers":["(CETERIS PARIBUS) WITH OTHER THINGS BEING EQUAL"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *Cet. Par.*?"},"1339110539317481502":{"questionID":"GMDR000168","answers":["rhin(o)-, rhino- (meaning **of or pertaining to the nose**)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What Greek medical root comes from the Greek **ῥίς/ῥῑνο- (rhís/rhīno-), nose**?"},"1339110563703296020":{"questionID":"GMDR000273","answers":["place, topical"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What does the Greek medical root **top(o)-** mean?"},"1339110654300127344":{"questionID":"GMDR000687","answers":["**-phagia** meaning __Forms terms denoting conditions relating to eating or ingestion__ (and **macrophage** meaning __a type of white blood cell that engulfs and digests pathogens__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **macrophage**."},"1339110668158373888":{"questionID":"GMDR000002","answers":["narc(o)-, narco- (meaning **numb, sleep**)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What Greek medical root comes from the Greek **νάρκη (nárkē), numbess, torpor**?"},"1339110681433083935":{"questionID":"GMDR000540","answers":["myo-"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots appears in **myopathy** (*muscle disease*)? The choices are *myo-*, *myco-*, *myelo-*, and *mylo-*."},"1339110743341137960":{"questionID":"GMDR000354","answers":["pod-"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots implies **of or pertaining to the foot, -footed**? The choices are *pod-*, *polio-*, *poly-*, and *por-*."},"1339110755051634708":{"questionID":"GMDR000440","answers":["-oid"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots implies **resemblance to**? The choices are *-oma*, *-opsy*, *-oid*, and *-osis*."},"1339110771379933186":{"questionID":"GMDR000405","answers":["-rrhexis"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots implies **rupture**? The choices are *-rrhage*, *-rrhaphy*, *-rrhea*, and *-rrhexis*."},"1339110784915079168":{"questionID":"GMDR000972","answers":["**psor-** meaning __Itching__ (and **psoroma** meaning __an old term for a skin condition with itching__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **psoroma**."},"1339110803118358613":{"questionID":"GMDR000379","answers":["phot-"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots implies **of or pertaining to light**? The choices are *phos-*, *phot-*, *pan-*, and *phon-*."},"1339110813352460308":{"questionID":"GMDR000482","answers":["hema-"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots appears in **hemophilia** (*disorder preventing blood from properly clotting*)? The choices are *hema-*, *homo-*, *homeo-*, and *hemi-*."},"1339110826295951394":{"questionID":"GMDR001166","answers":["**-tic** meaning __pertaining to__ (and **diabetic** meaning __relating to diabetes__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **diabetic**."},"1339111567752429568":{"questionID":"T001219","answers":["CHANGE BUT THE NAME, AND THE STORY IS TOLD OF YOURSELF"],"genus":"translation","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *mutato nomine de te fabula narratur*?"},"1339111890005135372":{"questionID":"D000151","answers":["cavea"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *cage* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1339111982749585458":{"questionID":"D000183","answers":["coquo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *apricot* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1339112061661085746":{"questionID":"D000678","answers":["quattor"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *quire* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1339112189050617906":{"questionID":"D000367","answers":["iacio"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *jetty* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1339112216670240852":{"questionID":"D000592","answers":["pendo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *avoirdupois* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1339112238832685118":{"questionID":"D000659","answers":["pretium"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *prize* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1339112431280197704":{"questionID":"L1009364","answers":["afferes"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future active indicative** of *affero* (to bring to; to allege, assert)?"},"1339417696747520062":{"questionID":"GMDR000080","answers":["-phago- (meaning **eating, devouring**)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What Greek medical root comes from the Greek **-φᾰ́γος (-phágos), eater of, eating**?"},"1339417746227593318":{"questionID":"GMDR000021","answers":["shoulder"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What does the Greek medical root **om(o)-** mean?"},"1339417755774095400":{"questionID":"GMDR000069","answers":["denotes something relating to digestion, or the digestive tract."],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What does the Greek medical root **-pepsia** mean?"},"1339417725180579920":{"questionID":"GMDR000790","answers":["**-pagus** meaning __Indicates conjoined twins, with the first part denoting the organs fused__ (and **pygopagus** meaning __twins joined at the pelvis__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **pygopagus**."},"1339417715445731369":{"questionID":"GMDR001001","answers":["**pykno-** meaning __to thicken (as the nucleus does in early stages of cell death)__ (and **pyknomorphic** meaning __thickly or densely formed__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **pyknomorphic**."},"1339418932083429387":{"questionID":"GMDR000527","answers":["**-lepsis** meaning __attack, seizure__","**narco-** meaning __numb, sleep__","**-plexy** meaning __stroke or seizure__ (and **narcolepsy** meaning __a condition characterized by sudden, uncontrollable sleep episodes__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **narcolepsy**."},"1339422438802456657":{"questionID":"L1006692","answers":["prime"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine vocative singular** of *primus* (first)?"},"1339470452526944266":{"questionID":"GMDR000066","answers":["peo- (meaning **of or pertaining to the penis**)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What Greek medical root comes from the Greek **πέος (péos)**?"},"1339470477302960149":{"questionID":"GMDR000530","answers":["**-logy** meaning __denotes the academic study or practice of a certain field","the study of__","**patho-** meaning __disease__ (and **pathology** meaning __study of disease__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **pathology**."},"1339470503332806656":{"questionID":"GMDR000497","answers":["**col-** meaning __colon__","**-scope** meaning __instrument for or process of viewing__ (and **colonoscopy** meaning __examination of the colon__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **colonoscopy**."},"1339471087947354134":{"questionID":"L1002990","answers":["matres"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *mater, matris* (mother)?"},"1339471133891629106":{"questionID":"P000064","answers":["JOANNES EST NOMAN EIUS (\"JOHN IS HIS NAME.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Puerto Rico*?"},"1339617177313087498":{"questionID":"GMDR000148","answers":["ptero-, ptery- (meaning **pertaining to a wing","'pterygo-', wing-shaped**)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What Greek medical root comes from the Greek **πτερόν (pterón), wing, feather**?"},"1339617196883836928":{"questionID":"GMDR000028","answers":["onych(o)-, onycho- (meaning **of or pertaining to the nail (of a finger or toe)**)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What Greek medical root comes from the Greek **ὄνυξ/ὀνυχο- (ónux/onukho-), nail; claw; talon**?"},"1339617214138945568":{"questionID":"GMDR000318","answers":["py-"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots implies **pus**? The choices are *py-*, *psych-*, *pseud-*, and *pyel-*."},"1339617155615817819":{"questionID":"GMDR000829","answers":["**phaco-** meaning __lens-shaped__ (and **phacomalacia** meaning __softening of the lens of the eye__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **phacomalacia**."},"1339621186866516018":{"questionID":"GMDR000918","answers":["**pne-** meaning __air, breath, lung__ (and **pneumoconiosis** meaning __lung disease caused by dust inhalation__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **pneumoconiosis**."},"1339659385156272230":{"questionID":"P000093","answers":["(HORA SOMNI) AT BEDTIME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *h.s.*?"},"1339665980183543818":{"questionID":"GMDR000256","answers":["thyr(o)-, thyro- (meaning **thyroid**)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What Greek medical root comes from the Greek **θῠρεός (thureós), large oblong shield; + εἶδος (eîdos), a form or shape**?"},"1339723564844191765":{"questionID":"P000127","answers":["(POST MERIDIEM) AFTER MIDDAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *P.M.*?"},"1340932092896215080":{"questionID":"P000214","answers":["THE STORY IS FINISHED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Acta est fabula**."},"1340932897649201223":{"questionID":"F001222","answers":["NESTOR"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the only Greek king to travel safely by sea back to his kingdom?"},"1341082631378440322":{"questionID":"P000180","answers":["A SLIP OF THE TONGUE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *lapsus linguae*?"},"1341082702341996707":{"questionID":"T000485","answers":["GOD WITH US"],"genus":"translation","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Deus nobiscum*?"},"1342869894659837953":{"questionID":"P000018","answers":["DOMINUS ILLUMINATIO MEA (\"THE LORD IS MY LIGHT\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Oxford University*?"},"1342871861050081381":{"questionID":"P000023","answers":["PAX ET LUX (\"PEACE AND LIGHT\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Tufts University*?"},"1342872185731026985":{"questionID":"P000147","answers":["YOU HIT THE NAIL ON THE HEAD"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *rem acu tetigisti*?"},"1342872563302531092":{"questionID":"P000017","answers":["CRUX SPES UNICA (\"THE CROSS IS THE ONLY HOPE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Notre Dame University*?"},"1342872670944886884":{"questionID":"P000017","answers":["CRUX SPES UNICA (\"THE CROSS IS THE ONLY HOPE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Notre Dame University*?"},"1342873274505232386":{"questionID":"L1020400","answers":["proficiemus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future active indicative** of *proficio* (to go on, to make progress)?"},"1342873881526014024":{"questionID":"H000528","answers":["217 BC"],"genus":"history","question":"In what year did Hannibal entrap and defeat Flaminius at Lake Trasimene?"},"1348447040052531211":{"questionID":"F000472","answers":["CELEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Callidice, Cleisidice, Demo & Callithoe?"},"1348446962399318026":{"questionID":"F001557","answers":["TAYGETE"],"genus":"myth","question":"According to Pindar, who stamped the Cerynean Hind's horns with Artemis' name?"},"1348446991054798939":{"questionID":"F002253","answers":["ZEUS (NOT JUPITER)"],"genus":"myth","question":"According to Homer, who was the eldest son of Cronus and Rhea?"},"1348449634980204575":{"questionID":"F002340","answers":["PENELOPE"],"genus":"myth","question":"Agenor, Leodes, Amphimedon, Eurymachus, and Antinous were all suitors of what Ithacan queen?"},"1348935587398422558":{"questionID":"P000016","answers":["QUAECUM SUNT VERA (\"WHATEVER IS TRUE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Northwestern University*?"},"1348935640980389910":{"questionID":"F000730","answers":["TYDEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was attacked by 50 Thebans, and killed all but one?"},"1355145970089721997":{"questionID":"H000562","answers":["CARTHAGO NOVA"],"genus":"history","question":"What city in Spain did Scipio Africanus capture in 209 BC?"},"1355145947193151539":{"questionID":"H000466","answers":["PHOENICIA"],"genus":"history","question":"Where did the Carthaginians originate from?"},"1355146017414185170":{"questionID":"H000468","answers":["AGRIGENTUM"],"genus":"history","question":"What Sicilian city did the Romans besiege in 262 BC?"},"1355146054978506892":{"questionID":"H000254","answers":["TO RECOVER THEIR WIVES"],"genus":"history","question":"What did Titus Tatius lead a group of Sabines to Rome?"},"1355150451833831465":{"questionID":"H000597","answers":["PYDNA"],"genus":"history","question":"At what battle in 168 BC did the Roman general Aemilius Paullus defeat Perseus of Macedon?"},"1355168301021401128":{"questionID":"P000228","answers":["SEIZE THE DAY, TRUSTING AS LITTLE AS POSSIBLE IN TOMORROW"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Carpe diem, quam minimum credula postero**."},"1355169467499282605":{"questionID":"P000007","answers":["VOX CLAMANTIS IN DESERTO. (\"A VOICE OF ONE CRYING IN THE WILDERNESS.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Dartmouth College*?"},"1355169488751956139":{"questionID":"P000207","answers":["WOE TO THE CONQUERED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *vae victis*?"},"1355170800268869682":{"questionID":"P000234","answers":["I HAVE RAISED A MONUMENT MORE LASTING THAN BRONZE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Exegi monumentum aere perennius**."},"1355173266272288965":{"questionID":"P000000","answers":["TERRAS IRRADIENT. (\"LET THEM ILLUMINATE THE EARTH.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Amherst College*?"},"1355173643318984854":{"questionID":"P000080","answers":["AD MAIOREM DEI GLORIAM (\"FOR THE GREATER GLORY OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Society of Jesuits*?"},"1355173710176190545":{"questionID":"P000240","answers":["A SOUND MIND IN A SOUND BODY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Mens sana in corpore sano**."},"1355177121823199422":{"questionID":"P000145","answers":["THERE IS NO ACCOUNTING FOR TASTE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *De gustibus non est disputandum*?"},"1355177145890111678":{"questionID":"P000122","answers":["(IBIDEM) IN THE SAME PLACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *ibid.*?"},"1355177165926432828":{"questionID":"P000018","answers":["DOMINUS ILLUMINATIO MEA (\"THE LORD IS MY LIGHT\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Oxford University*?"},"1355177418930917437":{"questionID":"P000064","answers":["JOANNES EST NOMAN EIUS (\"JOHN IS HIS NAME.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Puerto Rico*?"},"1355177436123365467":{"questionID":"P000235","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **parturient montes, nasceture ridiculus mus**?"},"1355178289777606807":{"questionID":"P000079","answers":["ARS ARTIS GRATIA (\"ART FOR THE SAKE OF ART\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer*?"},"1355178307494084618":{"questionID":"P000022","answers":["NON SIBI, SED SUIS. (\"NOT FOR HERSELF, BUT FOR HER OWN.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Tulane University*?"},"1355180146075762789":{"questionID":"P000031","answers":["LITTERIS DEDICATA ET OMNIBUS ARTIBUS (\"DEDICATED TO LETTERS AND ALL THE ARTS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Nebraska*?"},"1355180881131864136":{"questionID":"P000230","answers":["THERE'S NO GREATER HONOR THAN TO DIE FOR ONE'S COUNTRY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Dulce et decorum est pro patria mori**."},"1355296882158731405":{"questionID":"P000240","answers":["A SOUND MIND IN A SOUND BODY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Mens sana in corpore sano**."},"1355296911342440448":{"questionID":"P000019","answers":["DEI SUB NUMINE VIGET (\"IT FLOURISHES UNDER THE WILL OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Princeton University*?"},"1355296900340908293":{"questionID":"P000025","answers":["CRESCAT SCIENTIA, VITA EXCOLATUR (\"LET KNOWLEDGE INCREASE, LET LIFE BE PERFECTED\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Chicago*?"},"1355296928509988904":{"questionID":"P000216","answers":["I CAME, I SAW, I CONQUERED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Veni, vidi, vici**."},"1355296936231571506":{"questionID":"P000024","answers":["CIVIUM IN MORIBUS REI PUBLIAE SALUS. (\"IN THE CHARACTER OF ITS CITIZENS LIES THE WELFARE OF THE STATE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Univ. Florida*?"},"1355297545366016040":{"questionID":"P000250","answers":["TIME, THE DEVOURER OF ALL THINGS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Tempus edax rerum**."},"1355297804981112913":{"questionID":"P000079","answers":["ARS ARTIS GRATIA (\"ART FOR THE SAKE OF ART\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer*?"},"1355298348646793409":{"questionID":"P000023","answers":["PAX ET LUX (\"PEACE AND LIGHT\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Tufts University*?"},"1355298551210578082":{"questionID":"P000183","answers":["PERFECTION"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Ne plus ultra*?"},"1355298951254900806":{"questionID":"P000011","answers":["MIHI CURA FUTURI. (\"MY ANXIETY IS FOR THE FUTURE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Hunter College*?"},"1355299220160253982":{"questionID":"P000037","answers":["ECCE QUAM BONAM (\"BEHOLD HOW GOOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of the South (Sewanee)*?"},"1355299406232031242":{"questionID":"P000081","answers":["DUM VIVIMUS VIVAMUS (\"WHILE WE LIVE LET US LIVE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Epicureans*?"},"1355299725925945395":{"questionID":"P000002","answers":["NIL SINE MAGNO LABORE. (\"NOTHING WITHOUT GREAT EFFORT.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Brooklyn College*?"},"1355299737779048488":{"questionID":"P000235","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **parturient montes, nasceture ridiculus mus**?"},"1355302874099482865":{"questionID":"D000593","answers":["pendo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *expend* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1355361525191151696":{"questionID":"D000345","answers":["genus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *gent* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1355361502927917168":{"questionID":"D000600","answers":["penes"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *penetrate* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1355361516660064455":{"questionID":"D000256","answers":["duo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *dual* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1355361544409583666":{"questionID":"D000799","answers":["tango"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *attain* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1355361555385946163":{"questionID":"D000662","answers":["pulvis"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *powder* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1355362999560568923":{"questionID":"D000575","answers":["paro"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *emperor* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1355387837830140116":{"questionID":"D000567","answers":["par"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *pair* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1355387813939515500":{"questionID":"D000823","answers":["tono"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *astound* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"1355578135340646451":{"questionID":"G000563","answers":["converto convertere converti conversum"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find all 4 principal parts of the verb that matches the definition *turn about, turn, change*. Do not include macrons."},"1355578788901163268":{"questionID":"P000040","answers":["PRO HUMANITATE (\"FOR HUMANITY\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Wake Forest Univesity*?"},"1355579379308167342":{"questionID":"P000000","answers":["TERRAS IRRADIENT. (\"LET THEM ILLUMINATE THE EARTH.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Amherst College*?"},"1355579700952568149":{"questionID":"P000234","answers":["I HAVE RAISED A MONUMENT MORE LASTING THAN BRONZE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Exegi monumentum aere perennius**."},"1355580021015711784":{"questionID":"P000021","answers":["PRO ECCLESIA ET PATRIA. (\"FOR CHURCH AND COUNTRY.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Trinity College*?"},"1355580254881579230":{"questionID":"P000024","answers":["CIVIUM IN MORIBUS REI PUBLIAE SALUS. (\"IN THE CHARACTER OF ITS CITIZENS LIES THE WELFARE OF THE STATE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Univ. Florida*?"},"1355580499883589754":{"questionID":"P000022","answers":["NON SIBI, SED SUIS. (\"NOT FOR HERSELF, BUT FOR HER OWN.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Tulane University*?"},"1355580848249766100":{"questionID":"L1021873","answers":["evenero"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *evenio* (to happen)?"},"1355598541258621028":{"questionID":"L1017790","answers":["expleverimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *expleo* (to fill, complete)?"},"1355598517565001848":{"questionID":"L1017859","answers":["evasero"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *evado* (to come out, escape)?"},"1355598798088569053":{"questionID":"A000057","answers":["another... allos (αλλος)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **parallelogram**?"},"1355598961699717321":{"questionID":"P000072","answers":["URBS IN HORTO (\"CITY IN A GARDEN\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Chicago*?"},"1355599023968489522":{"questionID":"P000245","answers":["NERO"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Qualis artifex pereo**?"},"1355599043123871806":{"questionID":"P000074","answers":["DOMINE, DIRIGE NOS (\"LORD, GUIDE US\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *London*?"},"1355599053135548659":{"questionID":"P000222","answers":["CARTHAGE MUST BE DESTROYED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Delenda est Carthago**."},"1377005218469908480":{"questionID":"G000156","answers":["V1"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the part of speech/Latin inflection category of the word *amo amare*.\n\nPlease use the following for your answer.\n**Adjective: 1st and 2nd Declension:** A12\n**Adjective: 3rd Declension:** A3\n**Adjective: Indeclinable:** AI\n**Adjective: Numeral:** AN\n**Adverb:** ADV\n**Conjunction:** CONJ\n**Noun: 1st Declension:** N1\n**Noun: 2nd Declension:** N2\n**Noun: 3rd Declension:** N3\n**Noun: 4th Declension:** N4\n**Noun: 5th Declension:** N5\n**Noun: Indeclinable:** NI\n**Preposition:** PREP\n**Pronoun:** PRO\n**Verb: 1st Conjugation:** V1\n**Verb: 2nd Conjugation:** V2\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -io:** V3i\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -o:** V3\n**Verb: 4th Conjugation:** V4\n**Verb: Deponent:** VD\n**Verb: Impersonal:** VIP\n**Verb: Irregular:** VIRR"},"1377005245971828837":{"questionID":"G001333","answers":["journey, route"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *iter itineris n.*."},"1377005175251795978":{"questionID":"G001905","answers":["N1"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the part of speech/Latin inflection category of the word *pecunia pecuniae f.*.\n\nPlease use the following for your answer.\n**Adjective: 1st and 2nd Declension:** A12\n**Adjective: 3rd Declension:** A3\n**Adjective: Indeclinable:** AI\n**Adjective: Numeral:** AN\n**Adverb:** ADV\n**Conjunction:** CONJ\n**Noun: 1st Declension:** N1\n**Noun: 2nd Declension:** N2\n**Noun: 3rd Declension:** N3\n**Noun: 4th Declension:** N4\n**Noun: 5th Declension:** N5\n**Noun: Indeclinable:** NI\n**Preposition:** PREP\n**Pronoun:** PRO\n**Verb: 1st Conjugation:** V1\n**Verb: 2nd Conjugation:** V2\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -io:** V3i\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -o:** V3\n**Verb: 4th Conjugation:** V4\n**Verb: Deponent:** VD\n**Verb: Impersonal:** VIP\n**Verb: Irregular:** VIRR"},"1377005283695657073":{"questionID":"G002548","answers":["aspect, appearance"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *species speciei f.*."},"1377005312405668034":{"questionID":"G000858","answers":["N3"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the part of speech/Latin inflection category of the word *error erroris m.*.\n\nPlease use the following for your answer.\n**Adjective: 1st and 2nd Declension:** A12\n**Adjective: 3rd Declension:** A3\n**Adjective: Indeclinable:** AI\n**Adjective: Numeral:** AN\n**Adverb:** ADV\n**Conjunction:** CONJ\n**Noun: 1st Declension:** N1\n**Noun: 2nd Declension:** N2\n**Noun: 3rd Declension:** N3\n**Noun: 4th Declension:** N4\n**Noun: 5th Declension:** N5\n**Noun: Indeclinable:** NI\n**Preposition:** PREP\n**Pronoun:** PRO\n**Verb: 1st Conjugation:** V1\n**Verb: 2nd Conjugation:** V2\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -io:** V3i\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -o:** V3\n**Verb: 4th Conjugation:** V4\n**Verb: Deponent:** VD\n**Verb: Impersonal:** VIP\n**Verb: Irregular:** VIRR"},"1377005501795139604":{"questionID":"G002808","answers":["CONJ"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the part of speech/Latin inflection category of the word *vel*.\n\nPlease use the following for your answer.\n**Adjective: 1st and 2nd Declension:** A12\n**Adjective: 3rd Declension:** A3\n**Adjective: Indeclinable:** AI\n**Adjective: Numeral:** AN\n**Adverb:** ADV\n**Conjunction:** CONJ\n**Noun: 1st Declension:** N1\n**Noun: 2nd Declension:** N2\n**Noun: 3rd Declension:** N3\n**Noun: 4th Declension:** N4\n**Noun: 5th Declension:** N5\n**Noun: Indeclinable:** NI\n**Preposition:** PREP\n**Pronoun:** PRO\n**Verb: 1st Conjugation:** V1\n**Verb: 2nd Conjugation:** V2\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -io:** V3i\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -o:** V3\n**Verb: 4th Conjugation:** V4\n**Verb: Deponent:** VD\n**Verb: Impersonal:** VIP\n**Verb: Irregular:** VIRR"},"1377005772084478143":{"questionID":"G002177","answers":["quamquam"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find all 1 principal parts of the conjunction that matches the definition *however, although*. Do not include macrons."},"1377306593166889121":{"questionID":"L2019733","answers":["laceraverimus"],"genus":"L2_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active subjunctive** of *lacero* (to tear to pieces, to lacerate)?"},"1377306525353377844":{"questionID":"L2036062","answers":["restitui"],"genus":"L2_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *restituo* (to give back, restore)?"},"1377306553056493638":{"questionID":"L2078670","answers":["eductus est"],"genus":"L2_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect passive indicative** of *educo* (to lead forth, bring away)?"},"1377308226030145536":{"questionID":"L2060749","answers":["inveniebam"],"genus":"L2_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *invenio* (to find)?"},"1377308390010786015":{"questionID":"L2085092","answers":["expertum"],"genus":"L2_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative singular neuter perfect participle** of *experior* (to try, to prove; to experience)?"},"1377310989376295044":{"questionID":"L2073615","answers":["statutum"],"genus":"L2_inflection","question":"What is the **vocative singular neuter perfect participle** of *statuo* (to set up, establish; to decide)?"},"1377345594296631479":{"questionID":"L2061570","answers":["conveniebat"],"genus":"L2_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *convenio* (to come or meet together; to agree)?"},"1377345654690414612":{"questionID":"L2063241","answers":["esus eras"],"genus":"L2_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular pluperfect passive indicative** of *edo* (to eat)?"},"1377349566848045056":{"questionID":"F000300","answers":["SCORPION"],"genus":"myth","question":"What creature does Artemis create to defend herself from Orion?"},"1379349941436153877":{"questionID":"L1013180","answers":["silueris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *sileo* (to keep silent, to be quiet)?"},"1383304715244408852":{"questionID":"PW000137","answers":["SYRACUSE"],"genus":"pw","question":"What main city in Sicily attacked an Athenian ally, prompting the Sicilian Expedition?"},"1383304795401617469":{"questionID":"PW000062","answers":["PLAGUE"],"genus":"pw","question":"What event in 430 BC significantly weakened the Athenian military?"},"1383304957834297364":{"questionID":"PW000069","answers":["ATHENIAN VICTORY AND CAPTURE OF SPARTAN SOLDIERS"],"genus":"pw","question":"What was the significance of the Battle of Pylos?"},"1383304989820321803":{"questionID":"PW000086","answers":["DISMANTLE WALLS, SURRENDER FLEET, AND LOSE OVERSEAS POSSESSIONS"],"genus":"pw","question":"What were the terms of Athens' surrender in 404 BC?"},"1383305061974933555":{"questionID":"PW000108","answers":["CYRUS THE YOUNGER"],"genus":"pw","question":"What Persian prince played a significant role in supporting Sparta?"},"1383305079624568862":{"questionID":"PW000043","answers":["ALCIBIADES"],"genus":"pw","question":"What Athenian general, despite his earlier defection to Sparta, was not re-elected after the Spartan victory at Notium in 406 BC?"},"1383305088885329931":{"questionID":"PW000143","answers":["THE DECELEAN WAR"],"genus":"pw","question":"What term refers to the final phase of the Second Peloponnesian War?"},"1383305097685110824":{"questionID":"PW000131","answers":["AMPHIPOLIS"],"genus":"pw","question":"What Athenian colony in Thrace was captured by the Spartan general Brasidas?"},"1383305126894239864":{"questionID":"PW000102","answers":["RELIGIOUS STATUES WHOSE MUTILATION WAS A BAD OMEN"],"genus":"pw","question":"What were the hermai, and why were they significant?"},"1383305139452117104":{"questionID":"PW000048","answers":["REGAIN IONIAN CONTROL AND WEAKEN ATHENS"],"genus":"pw","question":"What was the primary motivation of the Persians in supporting Sparta?"},"1383305161337995284":{"questionID":"PW000109","answers":["SPARTAN VICTORY LEADING TO ALCIBIADES' DOWNFALL"],"genus":"pw","question":"What was the Battle of Notium?"},"1383305170783440946":{"questionID":"PW000077","answers":["CHARISMATIC ATHENIAN GENERAL WHO SWITCHED SIDES"],"genus":"pw","question":"Who was Alcibiades?"},"1383312738448572516":{"questionID":"LADV013532","answers":["vigilaveritis"],"genus":"LADV_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *vigilo* (to be awake)?"},"1383312799836541018":{"questionID":"H000986","answers":["AGRIPPINA THE YOUNGER"],"genus":"history","question":"Who reportedly served Claudius a bowl of poisoned mushrooms?"},"1383312933886628050":{"questionID":"H001192","answers":["GOTHS"],"genus":"history","question":"What group did Gallienus and Claudius Gothicus defeat at Naissus?"},"1383313289580384266":{"questionID":"H000970","answers":["41–54 AD"],"genus":"history","question":"What were the years of Claudius' reign?"},"1383313350242467890":{"questionID":"H000820","answers":["VETOED A LAND REFORM BILL"],"genus":"history","question":"How did Bibulus get on Caesar's bad side?"},"1383313534750035968":{"questionID":"H001127","answers":["PERTINAX"],"genus":"history","question":"Which emperor succeeded Commodus and ruled briefly in 193 AD?"},"1383313906122100847":{"questionID":"T001929","answers":["MAY IT BE WORTHY OF THE NAME"],"genus":"translation","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *sit nomine digna*?"},"1383313921737359422":{"questionID":"T002044","answers":["SPRING TIME"],"genus":"translation","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *tempus vernum*?"},"1383315258268975185":{"questionID":"F001823","answers":["POSEIDON"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Euphemus?"},"1383315414209007678":{"questionID":"F002039","answers":["IPHICLUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What son of Phylacus suffered from impotence?"},"1383315518752030730":{"questionID":"F000493","answers":["HIEROPHANT"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the chief priest of the Eleusinian Mysteries?"},"1383316910086819850":{"questionID":"F001627","answers":["SCYTHES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Which of the sons of Heracles and Echidna was able to string Heracles' bow?"},"1383317366179495987":{"questionID":"F001681","answers":["MYSIANS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Of what people was Telephus king?"},"1383318820264869968":{"questionID":"F001988","answers":["CALYDONIAN BOAR"],"genus":"myth","question":"On what hunt did Peleus accompany Euytion?"},"1383318874941820968":{"questionID":"F000659","answers":["ANTIOPE"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the sister of Nycteis?"},"1383319011550560337":{"questionID":"F000901","answers":["IDAS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Which of the Apharidae was killed by Zeus' thunderbolt?"},"1383319772191658034":{"questionID":"F001530","answers":["TEMPLE OF ZEUS AT OLYMPIA"],"genus":"myth","question":"On what temple's metopes were the 12 labors of Heracles depicted?"},"1383320463144390746":{"questionID":"F000856","answers":["ATHENIAN CITIZENS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who are the jury of the Areopagus?"},"1383637223647477834":{"questionID":"F001527","answers":["TIRYNS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What city was the kingdom of Eurystheus?"},"1383674103323557918":{"questionID":"F000619","answers":["BULL"],"genus":"myth","question":"In what disguise did Zeus abduct Europa?"},"1383981551334850590":{"questionID":"H000264","answers":["TITUS TATIUS"],"genus":"history","question":"With whom did Romulus co-rule in order to appease the Sabines?"},"1383981644481826856":{"questionID":"H000874","answers":["LEX TITIA"],"genus":"history","question":"What of 43 BC legallized the Second Triumvirate for 5 years?"},"1383993594423021568":{"questionID":"F000780","answers":["TIRESIAS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who foretold the end of Odysseus' wanderings and the manner of his death?"},"1383993548621217842":{"questionID":"F001329","answers":["ARETE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What queen of the Phaeacians was the wife of Alcinous and mother of Nausicaa?"},"1383993571396292721":{"questionID":"F002237","answers":["POSEIDON"],"genus":"myth","question":"Which Greek Olympian was called the \"Earthshaker\" because he was responsible for earthquakes?"},"1383997595000635463":{"questionID":"F000038","answers":["CYDIPPE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What priestess of Hera was the mother of Cleobis and Biton?"},"1384002180671078451":{"questionID":"F000440","answers":["ZEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"To whom did Hermes and Apollo take their cattle dispute?"},"1385431050939011092":{"questionID":"H000342","answers":["PONS SUBLICIUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What bridge did Horatius Cocles single-handedly defend from the assault of Lars Porsenna?"},"1385694388168167455":{"questionID":"F000585","answers":["THE FROGS"],"genus":"myth","question":"In what play does Aristophanes write 'brekekekex koax koax'?"},"1385694414646677645":{"questionID":"F000428","answers":["PLEIADES"],"genus":"myth","question":"To what group did Maia belong?"},"1385694355645399121":{"questionID":"F002250","answers":["HEPHAESTUS (NOT VULCAN)"],"genus":"myth","question":"According to Homer, which god created a new shield for Achilles?"},"1387538832567828480":{"questionID":"F002251","answers":["ATHENA"],"genus":"myth","question":"What Greek goddess of wisdom was born from Zeus' head?"},"1387539657910124544":{"questionID":"H001254","answers":["324 AD"],"genus":"history","question":"In what year did Constantine defeat Licinius at Chrysopolis?"},"1387542562763706389":{"questionID":"H000074","answers":["BIBULUS"],"genus":"history","question":"The year 59 BC was jokingly referred to as the year of Gaius and Caesar because of the lack of influence of what co-consular colleague of Caesar?"},"1388930687528075456":{"questionID":"L1005959","answers":["horrida"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter accusative plural** of *horridus* (rough, terrible)?"},"1389108322656845965":{"questionID":"H001179","answers":["CHRISTIANS"],"genus":"history","question":"What group was Decius the first emperor to systematically persecute throughout the empire?"},"1389110387974082611":{"questionID":"F000536","answers":["AVERNUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Where does Aeneas enter the underworld?"},"1389462885016801332":{"questionID":"F000767","answers":["PHEGEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the king of Arcadia whose daughter married Alcmaeon?"},"1389462839751868416":{"questionID":"F000913","answers":["PRIAM AND HECUBA"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who were the parents of Paris?"},"1389829192727658509":{"questionID":"H000216","answers":["ALBA LONGA"],"genus":"history","question":"What city did Iulus establish near the future site of Rome?"},"1389829239729164288":{"questionID":"H000916","answers":["AUGUSTUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Which emperor reportedly said \"I found Rome a city of brick, and left it a city of marble\"?"},"1390531619751727114":{"questionID":"H000416","answers":["SECOND SAMNITE WAR"],"genus":"history","question":"What war was fought over a disputue at Neapolis from 327–303 BC?"}},"questions":{"LFIFTH005167":{"interactionID":"1290018120442052669","answers":["advenit"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *advenio* (to come to, reach, arrive at)?"},"L1012757":{"interactionID":"1290018247093125151","answers":["accusavistis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *accuso* (to accuse, blame)?"},"G001018":{"interactionID":"1290029197594464286","answers":["chance"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *fors fortis f.*."},"I028784":{"interactionID":"1290034684482555985","answers":["conandis"],"genus":"inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural feminine gerundive** of *conor* (to attempt, try)?"},"L1010893":{"interactionID":"1290034725276221543","answers":["occupavero"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *occupo* (to occupy, seize)?"},"L1021299":{"interactionID":"1290034823829782549","answers":["aspexerit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *aspicio* (to look at, see)?"},"I080765":{"interactionID":"1290035726829748307","answers":["afferendi"],"genus":"inflection","question":"What is the **vocative plural masculine gerundive** of *affero* (to bring to; to allege, assert)?"},"I096719":{"interactionID":"1290036880515137598","answers":["vendendis"],"genus":"inflection","question":"What is the **dative plural masculine gerundive** of *vendo* (to sell)?"},"I073150":{"interactionID":"1290037335747989614","answers":["decipiendis"],"genus":"inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural feminine gerundive** of *decipio* (to deceive, cheat)?"},"G002322":{"interactionID":"1290041477623447603","answers":["V3i"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the part of speech/Latin inflection category of the word *respicio respicere respexi respectum*.\n\nPlease use the following for your answer.\n**Adjective: 1st and 2nd Declension:** A12\n**Adjective: 3rd Declension:** A3\n**Adjective: Indeclinable:** AI\n**Adjective: Numeral:** AN\n**Adverb:** ADV\n**Conjunction:** CONJ\n**Noun: 1st Declension:** N1\n**Noun: 2nd Declension:** N2\n**Noun: 3rd Declension:** N3\n**Noun: 4th Declension:** N4\n**Noun: 5th Declension:** N5\n**Noun: Indeclinable:** NI\n**Preposition:** PREP\n**Pronoun:** PRO\n**Verb: 1st Conjugation:** V1\n**Verb: 2nd Conjugation:** V2\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -io:** V3i\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -o:** V3\n**Verb: 4th Conjugation:** V4\n**Verb: Deponent:** VD\n**Verb: Impersonal:** VIP\n**Verb: Irregular:** VIRR"},"PW000055":{"interactionID":"1290050042866176081","answers":["431 BC"],"genus":"pw","question":"What year did the Peloponnesian War begin?"},"PW000080":{"interactionID":"1290044529998565518","answers":["Devastating Athenian defeat"],"genus":"pw","question":"What was the outcome of the Athenian expedition to Sicily?"},"PW000100":{"interactionID":"1290045102361677844_0","answers":["Defeat and dissolution of the alliance"],"genus":"pw","question":"What was the outcome of the Battle of Mantinea for the democratic alliance led by Argos?"},"PW000033":{"interactionID":"1290045102361677844_1","answers":["Xenophon"],"genus":"pw","question":"What other Greek historian, who wrote the Hellenica, provided an account of the later years of the war and its aftermath?"},"PW000041":{"interactionID":"1290045102361677844_2","answers":["Samos"],"genus":"pw","question":"What was the name of the island where the Athenian fleet was based after its revolt against the oligarchs in 411 BC?"},"PW000121":{"interactionID":"1290045102361677844_3","answers":["404 BC"],"genus":"pw","question":"What year did the Second Peloponnesian War end?"},"PW000012":{"interactionID":"1290045102361677844_4","answers":["Sparta"],"genus":"pw","question":"What city-state was Athens' main rival for power in Greece?"},"PW000086":{"interactionID":"1383304989820321803","answers":["DISMANTLE WALLS, SURRENDER FLEET, AND LOSE OVERSEAS POSSESSIONS"],"genus":"pw","question":"What were the terms of Athens' surrender in 404 BC?"},"PW000049":{"interactionID":"1290045102361677844_6","answers":["More brutal and less restrained warfare"],"genus":"pw","question":"What was the significance of the Peloponnesian War for the future of Greek warfare?"},"PW000029":{"interactionID":"1290045102361677844_7","answers":["Long Walls"],"genus":"pw","question":"What were the fortifications called that connected Athens to its port of Piraeus?"},"PW000101":{"interactionID":"1290045102361677844_8","answers":["Siege and subjugation of Melos"],"genus":"pw","question":"What event in 416 BC demonstrated Athenian aggression and alienated potential allies?"},"PW000138":{"interactionID":"1290045102361677844_9","answers":["Alcibiades"],"genus":"pw","question":"Who persuaded the Athenians to launch the Sicilian Expedition?"},"PW000063":{"interactionID":"1290045244057845791","answers":["Pericles"],"genus":"pw","question":"Who was the influential Athenian leader who advised a defensive strategy at the war's beginning?"},"PW000132":{"interactionID":"1290046545235808287_0","answers":["The Battle of Amphipolis"],"genus":"pw","question":"Which battle resulted in the deaths of both Cleon and Brasidas?"},"PW000015":{"interactionID":"1290046545235808287_2","answers":["Strong land army"],"genus":"pw","question":"What was Sparta's main military advantage?"},"PW000008":{"interactionID":"1290046545235808287_3","answers":["Battle of Aegospotami"],"genus":"pw","question":"What was the name of the decisive naval battle where Sparta defeated Athens in 405 BC?"},"PW000031":{"interactionID":"1290046545235808287_4","answers":["Thirty Tyrants"],"genus":"pw","question":"What group of Athenian citizens briefly held power after the war?"},"PW000149":{"interactionID":"1290046545235808287_5","answers":["Thrasybulus"],"genus":"pw","question":"What Athenian leader helped restore democracy to Athens in 403 BC?"},"PW000111":{"interactionID":"1290046545235808287_6","answers":["Cut off Athenian grain supply"],"genus":"pw","question":"Why did Lysander sail to the Dardanelles?"},"PW000137":{"interactionID":"1383304715244408852","answers":["SYRACUSE"],"genus":"pw","question":"What main city in Sicily attacked an Athenian ally, prompting the Sicilian Expedition?"},"PW000003":{"interactionID":"1290046545235808287_8","answers":["Plague"],"genus":"pw","question":"What event in 430 BC significantly weakened the Athenian military?"},"PW000096":{"interactionID":"1290046545235808287_9","answers":["Speech honoring Athenian soldiers and values"],"genus":"pw","question":"What was Pericles' Funeral Oration?"},"PW000002":{"interactionID":"1290046776165924956","answers":["Archidamus II"],"genus":"pw","question":"What was the name of the Spartan king who initially led invasions of Attica?"},"F002285":{"interactionID":"1290056814049755199","answers":["EURYSTHEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who terrified by the sight of the Nemean Lion hid in a bronze jar?"},"F000261":{"interactionID":"1290056838938755133","answers":["QUAIL ISLAND"],"genus":"myth","question":"What does Ortygia mean?"},"F001516":{"interactionID":"1290056850573627566","answers":["HIS DAUGHTER MEGARA AS WIFE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What prize did Creon, regent of Thebes, give to Heracles for helping the city?"},"T001188":{"interactionID":"1290077336812781599","answers":["A MONASTERY WITHOUT BOOKS IS LIKE A CITY WITHOUT WEALTH"],"genus":"translation","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Monasterium sine libris est sicut civitas sine opibus*?"},"H000056":{"interactionID":"1290078941272604763","answers":["BRENNUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What Sennonian chieftain reportedly said vae victis to the Romans when they complained of weighted scales?"},"H000733":{"interactionID":"1290079015046090753","answers":["PERPERNA"],"genus":"history","question":"What subordinate of Sertorius assassinated him?"},"H001246":{"interactionID":"1290080855183851612","answers":["IN HOC SIGNO VINCES"],"genus":"history","question":"What words did Constantine reportedly see in a cross before the battle of Milvian Bridge?"},"H001298":{"interactionID":"1290097021918642258","answers":["RAVENNA"],"genus":"history","question":"Where did Honorius flee to when Alaric sacked Rome?"},"H001272":{"interactionID":"1309006450470686760","answers":["378 AD"],"genus":"history","question":"In what year was Valens captured by the Goths at Adrianople?"},"L1004765":{"interactionID":"1290116397241864263","answers":["albis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter ablative plural** of *albus* (white)?"},"L1013577":{"interactionID":"1290116434080432258","answers":["paruerit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *pareo* (to appear; to obey)?"},"L1018499":{"interactionID":"1290116633687232602","answers":["deduxistis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *deduco* (to lead away)?"},"L1020325":{"interactionID":"1290117622909767680","answers":["recipiam"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future active indicative** of *recipio* (to take back; to receive)?"},"L1009495":{"interactionID":"1337886522632048722","answers":["abes"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active imperative** of *absum* (to be away, to be absent)?"},"L1000664":{"interactionID":"1290117904745889853","answers":["materias"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *materia, materiae* (wood, material)?"},"LFIFTH003542":{"interactionID":"1290530544618045508","answers":["superamus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *supero* (to go over, exceed, remain)?"},"LFIFTH004387":{"interactionID":"1290530582836809740","answers":["appellaverunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *appello* (to call, implore)?"},"LFIFTH005262":{"interactionID":"1290530643511607317","answers":["revertistis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *reverto* (to come back, turn back, return)?"},"LFIFTH000175":{"interactionID":"1290718853566828624","answers":["pugna"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *pugna, pugnae* (battle)?"},"LFIFTH002730":{"interactionID":"1290718812588478474","answers":["omni"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine/feminine ablative singular** of *omnis* (all, every)?"},"G002981":{"interactionID":"1290718976258867293","answers":["utor uti usus sum"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find all 4 principal parts of the verb that matches the definition *use, consume, employ (+ abl.)*. Do not include macrons."},"LFIFTH003736":{"interactionID":"1290719140864196752","answers":["potant"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *poto* (to drink)?"},"LFIFTH004656":{"interactionID":"1290729770019197008","answers":["pares"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *pareo* (to appear; to obey)?"},"LFIFTH006578":{"interactionID":"1290730115767996458","answers":["agnoscis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *agnosco* (to recognize; to admit)?"},"A000460":{"interactionID":"1290758681922764852","answers":["logos (λογος), word, speech, reasoning"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **dialogue**?"},"A000547":{"interactionID":"1290759721053196298","answers":["name... οnoma (ονομα)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **synonym**?"},"A000480":{"interactionID":"1290786562618949733","answers":["misos (μισος), hatred"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **misoneism**?"},"LFIFTH000064":{"interactionID":"1290814769850482769","answers":["sagitta"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *sagitta, sagittae* (arrow)?"},"LFIFTH006798":{"interactionID":"1290831150553501726","answers":["percepisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *percipio* (to occupy; to perceive, observe)?"},"LFIFTH001952":{"interactionID":"1290848406314680453","answers":["duri"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter genitive singular** of *durus* (hard)?"},"LFIFTH002887":{"interactionID":"1290889609047314433","answers":["te"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *tu* (you, yourself)?"},"LFIFTH000445":{"interactionID":"1290890481810804748","answers":["bellum"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative singular** of *bellum, belli* (war)?"},"LFIFTH003713":{"interactionID":"1290891132556939337","answers":["praestatis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *praesto* (to stand before, surpass, warrant)?"},"LFIFTH000088":{"interactionID":"1290891172012621926","answers":["experientia"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *experientia, experientiae* (experience)?"},"LFIFTH006988":{"interactionID":"1291087784425164841","answers":["conspexi"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *conspicio* (to observe, to gaze upon)?"},"LFIFTH000874":{"interactionID":"1291167071824121906","answers":["senectutes"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *senectus, senectutis* (old age)?"},"LFIFTH002890":{"interactionID":"1291167523470839848","answers":["nobis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *nos* (we, us, ourselves; emph. I, me, myself)?"},"LFIFTH005607":{"interactionID":"1291168631295574016","answers":["occidistis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *occido* (to kill)?"},"LFIFTH000436":{"interactionID":"1291170257523708025","answers":["simulacrum"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative singular** of *simulacrum, simulacri* (image, portrait, phantom)?"},"A000619":{"interactionID":"1291189724081557524","answers":["flesh... sarx (σαρξ)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **sarcasm**?"},"LFIFTH004210":{"interactionID":"1291209330598744175","answers":["desperamus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *despero* (to despair of, to give up)?"},"LFIFTH004814":{"interactionID":"1291209818647957515","answers":["intuent"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *intueor* (to look at, regard)?"},"LFIFTH005237":{"interactionID":"1291209918543691838","answers":["ruisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *ruo* (to fall down; to cast down, prostrate)?"},"LFIFTH000767":{"interactionID":"1291210712567513098","answers":["corpora"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *corpus, corporis* (body)?"},"LFIFTH003299":{"interactionID":"1291210811884437514","answers":["tulisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *fero* (to bear, carry, bring)?"},"H000721":{"interactionID":"1291254424332795945","answers":["LIVIUS DRUSUS THE YOUNGER"],"genus":"history","question":"What tribune of 91 BC was killed for trying to promote citizenship for the Latin allies?"},"PW000107":{"interactionID":"1291258218043146290","answers":["ATHENIAN VICTORY AND PARTIAL RECOVERY"],"genus":"pw","question":"What was the significance of the Battle of Cyzicus?"},"G001129":{"interactionID":"1291263000854003812","answers":["winter"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *hiems hiemis f.*."},"LFIFTH002672":{"interactionID":"1291263367968854016","answers":["humiles"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine/feminine nominative plural** of *humilis* (small, humble)?"},"LFIFTH002441":{"interactionID":"1291265530992267314","answers":["saeva"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter nominative plural** of *saevus* (furious, ferocious)?"},"LFIFTH002823":{"interactionID":"1291267466978394142","answers":["celebris"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive singular** of *celeber* (crowded, renowned)?"},"LFIFTH004753":{"interactionID":"1291268434176512112","answers":["meruistis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *mereo* (to deserve, merit, serve in the army)?"},"LFIFTH006938":{"interactionID":"1291268463838629908","answers":["deiecerunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *deicio* (to throw or cast down)?"},"LFIFTH003319":{"interactionID":"1291268688548204567","answers":["eunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *eo* (to go)?"},"LFIFTH006803":{"interactionID":"1291269145685659691","answers":["patis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *patior* (to bear, suffer, endure, allow)?"},"LFIFTH004810":{"interactionID":"1291269511688749056","answers":["intues"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *intueor* (to look at, regard)?"},"L1013508":{"interactionID":"1291270141132406856","answers":["placuerint"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *placeo* (to please)?"},"L1003911":{"interactionID":"1291270997294452746","answers":["auribus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative plural** of *auris, auris* (ear)?"},"L1012455":{"interactionID":"1291271011504754748","answers":["clamaverat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *clamo* (to call, cry out, declare)?"},"L1018361":{"interactionID":"1291271273380315236","answers":["deserueratis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *desero* (to leave, abandon)?"},"L1020593":{"interactionID":"1291271281584640080","answers":["perceperatis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *percipio* (to occupy; to perceive, observe)?"},"L1002146":{"interactionID":"1291271294415015957","answers":["barbarorum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural** of *barbarus, barbari* (barbarian)?"},"L1000014":{"interactionID":"1291271533964038285","answers":["puellarum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural** of *puella, puellae* (girl)?"},"L1008117":{"interactionID":"1291271546337235076","answers":["ipsius"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter genitive singular** of *ipse* (in person, himself, herself, itself)?"},"L1008269":{"interactionID":"1291271627283370075","answers":["quacumque"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine ablative singular** of *quicumque* (whoever, whatever)?"},"L1015668":{"interactionID":"1291272158391173120","answers":["rebunt"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future active indicative** of *reor* (to believe, think, imagine)?"},"L1015293":{"interactionID":"1291272429985071128","answers":["sprevit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *sperno* (to despise, reject, spurn)?"},"LFIFTH004867":{"interactionID":"1291272657593040918","answers":["fovetis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *foveo* (to keep warm; to caress, love)?"},"LFIFTH002854":{"interactionID":"1291272795258490980","answers":["equestri"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter ablative singular** of *equester* (equestrian)?"},"LFIFTH002538":{"interactionID":"1291273148339327037","answers":["adulescentis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive singular** of *adulescens* (young)?"},"LFIFTH004637":{"interactionID":"1291274479732920372","answers":["placetis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *placeo* (to please)?"},"L1017176":{"interactionID":"1291274772512116746","answers":["instrues"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future active indicative** of *instruo* (to set in order, equip; to teach, instruct)?"},"LFIFTH006648":{"interactionID":"1291274913184874551","answers":["accedunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *accedo* (to go near to, approach; to agree with)?"},"L1008466":{"interactionID":"1291275453398650892","answers":["transtuleris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *transfero* (to bear across, transport, transfer)?"},"L1010551":{"interactionID":"1291275491751366750","answers":["postulabo"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future active indicative** of *postulo* (to ask, demand, summon)?"},"L1015571":{"interactionID":"1291275552509923389","answers":["restitueratis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *restituo* (to give back, restore)?"},"L1005393":{"interactionID":"1291275580364554260","answers":["commodi"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine genitive singular** of *commodus* (proper, suitable)?"},"L1020770":{"interactionID":"1291275600358801428","answers":["inceperas"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *incipio* (to begin)?"},"L1002699":{"interactionID":"1291276285259153420","answers":["tempore"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *tempus, temporis* (period of time)?"},"L1017319":{"interactionID":"1291276352716144710","answers":["imponam"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future active indicative** of *impono* (to lay upon, impose)?"},"L1010549":{"interactionID":"1291276460719476827","answers":["postulabatis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *postulo* (to ask, demand, summon)?"},"L1004107":{"interactionID":"1291276511122296874","answers":["amnes"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *amnis, amnis* (stream, river)?"},"L1016277":{"interactionID":"1291276704534233108","answers":["persequet"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future active indicative** of *persequor* (to follow, to pursue)?"},"L1000236":{"interactionID":"1291276724373295155","answers":["littera"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **vocative singular** of *littera, litterae* (letter)?"},"L1020038":{"interactionID":"1291276751262978119","answers":["accideris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *accido* (to fall upon; to happen)?"},"L1017172":{"interactionID":"1291276762667417600","answers":["instruebamus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *instruo* (to set in order, equip; to teach, instruct)?"},"L1014344":{"interactionID":"1291276836252160092","answers":["exercueras"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *exerceo* (to exercise, occupy, employ)?"},"L1017901":{"interactionID":"1291276853184696381","answers":["erige"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active imperative** of *erigo* (to rise up, erect, build)?"},"L1021062":{"interactionID":"1291276985825366068","answers":["deficiebant"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *deficio* (to withdraw, desert; to cease, disappear)?"},"L1017589":{"interactionID":"1291277305402101760","answers":["floram"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future active indicative** of *floreo* (to bloom, blossom; to be prosperous)?"},"L1020113":{"interactionID":"1291277394115690508","answers":["accesseritis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *accedo* (to go near to, approach; to agree with)?"},"L1005051":{"interactionID":"1291277532842426432","answers":["asperorum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine genitive plural** of *asper* (rough, harsh)?"},"L1012049":{"interactionID":"1291278106492928052","answers":["dederitis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *do* (to give)?"},"L1008275":{"interactionID":"1291398113801801800","answers":["quarumcumque"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive plural** of *quicumque* (whoever, whatever)?"},"L1006801":{"interactionID":"1291278293668204596","answers":["pulchris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine ablative plural** of *pulcher* (beautiful, handsome)?"},"L1010913":{"interactionID":"1291278303889457202","answers":["obstabit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future active indicative** of *obsto* (to stand against, oppose)?"},"L1018030":{"interactionID":"1291278313339355158","answers":["edidimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *edo* (to bring forth, beget, publish)?"},"L1004487":{"interactionID":"1291278363465482250","answers":["dierum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural** of *dies, diei* (day)?"},"L1011190":{"interactionID":"1291278371745038406","answers":["moramus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *moror* (to delay, linger, hinder)?"},"L1018397":{"interactionID":"1291278484441665641","answers":["descenderatis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *descendo* (to come down, descend)?"},"L1010174":{"interactionID":"1291278869701070859","answers":["rogabis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future active indicative** of *rogo* (to ask, interrogate)?"},"L1009936":{"interactionID":"1291278883223765063","answers":["steteramus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *sto* (to stand)?"},"L1003979":{"interactionID":"1291278978619015219","answers":["manibus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative plural** of *manes, manium* (ghosts of the departed)?"},"L1008750":{"interactionID":"1291278987816996924","answers":["praetuleramus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *praefero* (to bear before, prefer, display)?"},"L1014765":{"interactionID":"1291279117907398748","answers":["vendet"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future active indicative** of *vendo* (to sell)?"},"L1001387":{"interactionID":"1291279132428210276","answers":["tumule"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **vocative singular** of *tumulus, tumuli* (mound, hill)?"},"L1003946":{"interactionID":"1291279197175550023","answers":["aestatum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural** of *aestas, aestatis* (summer)?"},"L1006209":{"interactionID":"1291397091893055560","answers":["iustum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine accusative singular** of *iustus* (lawful, right)?"},"L1010036":{"interactionID":"1291397143940038718","answers":["simulavisti"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *simulo* (to imitate)?"},"L1014458":{"interactionID":"1291397422676709489","answers":["docueris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *doceo* (to teach)?"},"L1004996":{"interactionID":"1291397516780376144","answers":["aptis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter dative plural** of *aptus* (suitable)?"},"L1002457":{"interactionID":"1291397536765972490","answers":["vasorum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural** of *vas, vasis* (vase)?"},"L1001835":{"interactionID":"1291397836788727981","answers":["iuvenco"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *iuvencus, iuvenci* (young bullock)?"},"L1011790":{"interactionID":"1291397924869247027","answers":["expectaveramus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *expecto* (to expect, to be waiting for)?"},"L1003965":{"interactionID":"1302337798505893990","answers":["aequoribus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative plural** of *aequor, aequoris* (surface of the sea, sea)?"},"L1018789":{"interactionID":"1291397946180370577","answers":["contempseram"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *contemno* (to despise, not to fear)?"},"L1004698":{"interactionID":"1291398030200799305","answers":["aegris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine dative plural** of *aeger* (ill, troubled)?"},"L1006204":{"interactionID":"1291398045946216489","answers":["iustae"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive singular** of *iustus* (lawful, right)?"},"L1021863":{"interactionID":"1291398204507816028","answers":["evenit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *evenio* (to happen)?"},"L1010398":{"interactionID":"1291398255183401080","answers":["probavimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *probo* (to test, approve)?"},"L1019839":{"interactionID":"1291398701293506661","answers":["agam"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future active indicative** of *ago* (to lead, to drive, to do)?"},"L1009267":{"interactionID":"1291398715244019753","answers":["detuleram"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *defero* (to bear or bring away; to report)?"},"L1012822":{"interactionID":"1291398723317927988","answers":["videbimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future active indicative** of *video* (to see)?"},"L1019254":{"interactionID":"1291398775729950770","answers":["coepit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *coepi* (to begin)?"},"L1015011":{"interactionID":"1291398794805641306","answers":["sustulerat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *tollo* (to rise up, elevate, exhalt)?"},"L1009789":{"interactionID":"1291398803836112918","answers":["vacaveram"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *vaco* (to be empty, vacant, free, idle)?"},"L1010040":{"interactionID":"1291398809506676838","answers":["simulaverunt"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *simulo* (to imitate)?"},"L1017593":{"interactionID":"1291398954336129074","answers":["floretis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future active indicative** of *floreo* (to bloom, blossom; to be prosperous)?"},"L1006004":{"interactionID":"1291398964653985792","answers":["ignotum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter vocative singular** of *ignotus* (unknown)?"},"L1001061":{"interactionID":"1291399109663785001","answers":["agno"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *agnus, agni* (lamb)?"},"L1001875":{"interactionID":"1291399179184111698","answers":["initia"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *initium, initii* (beginning)?"},"L1011468":{"interactionID":"1291399230577184902","answers":["iuraverant"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *iuro* (to swear, take an oath)?"},"L1015070":{"interactionID":"1291399241994080377","answers":["tenebis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future active indicative** of *teneo* (to hold, keep, possess)?"},"L1013246":{"interactionID":"1291399419853275196","answers":["riseras"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *rideo* (to laugh)?"},"L1007583":{"interactionID":"1291399428300607539","answers":["omnium"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter genitive plural** of *omnis* (all, every)?"},"L1012408":{"interactionID":"1291399436244881452","answers":["cogitabimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future active indicative** of *cogito* (to think, meditate, plan)?"},"L1011109":{"interactionID":"1291399523549315174","answers":["negavero"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *nego* (to say no, to deny)?"},"L1012755":{"interactionID":"1291399673193431040","answers":["accusavit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *accuso* (to accuse, blame)?"},"L1018097":{"interactionID":"1291399694165213235","answers":["dividetis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future active indicative** of *divido* (to divide)?"},"L1001570":{"interactionID":"1291399776947929119","answers":["proeliorum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural** of *proelium, proelii* (battle)?"},"L1010805":{"interactionID":"1291409001677983917","answers":["optabit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future active indicative** of *opto* (to choose, to wish)?"},"L1000548":{"interactionID":"1291399914638803025","answers":["potentiis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *potentia, potentiae* (power)?"},"L1021480":{"interactionID":"1291399931860484096","answers":["sepeliverimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *sepelio* (to bury)?"},"L1005235":{"interactionID":"1291399943487098910","answers":["caecis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine dative plural** of *caecus* (blind)?"},"L1000308":{"interactionID":"1291399952509177907","answers":["pecunia"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **vocative singular** of *pecunia, pecuniae* (money, wealth)?"},"L1014163":{"interactionID":"1291399960746524796","answers":["horrueram"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *horreo* (to be frightened at)?"},"L1015419":{"interactionID":"1291399969114161185","answers":["scripsit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *scribo* (to write)?"},"L1013428":{"interactionID":"1291399981747408960","answers":["praebueramus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *praebeo* (to give, offer)?"},"L1010051":{"interactionID":"1291399987875414106","answers":["simulaveritis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *simulo* (to imitate)?"},"L1018941":{"interactionID":"1291399994401882144","answers":["coniunget"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future active indicative** of *coniungo* (to join)?"},"L1017934":{"interactionID":"1291400021492891689","answers":["emerimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *emo* (to buy)?"},"L1000878":{"interactionID":"1291969720693555221","answers":["copiae"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *copia, copiae* (abundance)?"},"L1021437":{"interactionID":"1291400132729896960","answers":["serviverat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *servio* (to be a servant or slave, to serve)?"},"L1009783":{"interactionID":"1291400173528023143","answers":["vacavi"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *vaco* (to be empty, vacant, free, idle)?"},"L1013218":{"interactionID":"1291400195384283268","answers":["sederimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *sedeo* (to sit)?"},"L1017662":{"interactionID":"1291400207359279194","answers":["finges"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future active indicative** of *fingo* (to form, make, shape)?"},"L1014900":{"interactionID":"1291400229039378473","answers":["tribuerunt"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *tribuo* (to assign, grant)?"},"L1006472":{"interactionID":"1291400267631165521","answers":["nimiis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter ablative plural** of *nimius* (excessive)?"},"L1002008":{"interactionID":"1291400282596573244","answers":["famule"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **vocative singular** of *famulus, famuli* (servant)?"},"L1010535":{"interactionID":"1291400288250368051","answers":["potaverit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *poto* (to drink)?"},"L1005427":{"interactionID":"1291400386007269491","answers":["contentae"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine dative singular** of *contentus* (tense, intent; satisfied)?"},"L1013598":{"interactionID":"1291400395280879636","answers":["obtinebunt"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future active indicative** of *obtineo* (to hold, occupy, possess)?"},"L1017703":{"interactionID":"1291400405992996947","answers":["favi"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *faveo* (to be favorable or inclined towards)?"},"L1022010":{"interactionID":"1291400425744109689","answers":["compererunt"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *comperio* (to find out, ascertain)?"},"L1021036":{"interactionID":"1291400442537971804","answers":["deiecimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *deicio* (to throw or cast down)?"},"L1012100":{"interactionID":"1291400450880442398","answers":["desperaveris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *despero* (to despair of, to give up)?"},"L1012645":{"interactionID":"1291400469742223452","answers":["appellavi"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *appello* (to call, implore)?"},"L1016966":{"interactionID":"1291400480802738187","answers":["legisti"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *lego* (to gather, collect; to read)?"},"L1021330":{"interactionID":"1291400636516143114","answers":["acceperamus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *accipio* (to receive)?"},"L1011717":{"interactionID":"1291400669194092635","answers":["habitaverat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *habito* (to inhabit, dwell)?"},"L1004504":{"interactionID":"1291400707551006741","answers":["speciei"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *species, speciei* (appearance)?"},"L1005118":{"interactionID":"1291400863440699483","answers":["avidas"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine accusative plural** of *avidus* (eager, greedy)?"},"L1003278":{"interactionID":"1291400917144436751","answers":["praetores"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *praetor, praetoris* (praetor, commander)?"},"L1015934":{"interactionID":"1291401013768622163","answers":["quaesiveris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *quaero* (to seek, ask, inquire, desire)?"},"L1016529":{"interactionID":"1291401027102441534","answers":["pepercerit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *parco* (to spare, have mercy upon)?"},"L1007287":{"interactionID":"1291401035771940927","answers":["dulce"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter vocative singular** of *dulcis* (sweet, charming)?"},"L1019158":{"interactionID":"1291401045381087293","answers":["colligemus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future active indicative** of *colligo* (to gather, draw or bring together)?"},"L1002960":{"interactionID":"1291401110199865355","answers":["civitates"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *civitas, civitatis* (citizenship, state)?"},"L1000887":{"interactionID":"1291401311345971280","answers":["comae"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *coma, comae* (hair)?"},"L1006940":{"interactionID":"1291401319935901737","answers":["superba"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter nominative plural** of *superbus* (proud, arrogant)?"},"L1008335":{"interactionID":"1291401331139149856","answers":["utrorum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine genitive plural** of *uter* (which of two?)?"},"L1006554":{"interactionID":"1291401612241403954","answers":["novis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine dative plural** of *novus* (new)?"},"L1018888":{"interactionID":"1291401620982206464","answers":["consuescemus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future active indicative** of *consuesco* (to be accustomed)?"},"L1000737":{"interactionID":"1291401630557667449","answers":["horis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *hora, horae* (hour)?"},"L1009041":{"interactionID":"1291401649771778160","answers":["inibit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future active indicative** of *ineo* (to go into, enter)?"},"L1020342":{"interactionID":"1291406563294187622","answers":["receperant"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *recipio* (to take back; to receive)?"},"L1002485":{"interactionID":"1291406929196875817","answers":["plebibus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative plural** of *plebs, plebis* (common people, the plebeians)?"},"L1001869":{"interactionID":"1291406942782230672","answers":["iocos"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *iocus, ioci* (joke)?"},"L1016852":{"interactionID":"1291406964630224906","answers":["metueris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *metuo* (to fear, to be afraid of)?"},"L1008804":{"interactionID":"1337886014798172190","answers":["perferebatis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *perfero* (to bear through, endure to the end)?"},"L1005326":{"interactionID":"1291407062839984179","answers":["certis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter dative plural** of *certus* (determined, settled)?"},"L1009656":{"interactionID":"1291407100441919498","answers":["vitabunt"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future active indicative** of *vito* (to avoid)?"},"L1006913":{"interactionID":"1291407319099379723","answers":["summorum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter genitive plural** of *summus* (highest, topmost)?"},"L1002311":{"interactionID":"1291407439652061214","answers":["regiones"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *regio, regionis* (region)?"},"L1001961":{"interactionID":"1291407452008353955","answers":["freto"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *fretum, freti* (strait, sea)?"},"L1000151":{"interactionID":"1291407519524065375","answers":["victorias"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *victoria, victoriae* (victory)?"},"L1016372":{"interactionID":"1291407633613455392","answers":["perdidisti"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *perdo* (to destroy, ruin; to lose)?"},"L1012478":{"interactionID":"1291407645890183219","answers":["circumdabis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future active indicative** of *circumdo* (to surround, enclose)?"},"L1000612":{"interactionID":"1291407665452290070","answers":["naturae"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *natura, naturae* (nature)?"},"L1018176":{"interactionID":"1291407672012308694","answers":["discesserunt"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *discedo* (to go away from, to leave)?"},"L1018504":{"interactionID":"1291407735190982737","answers":["deduxeramus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *deduco* (to lead away)?"},"L1005807":{"interactionID":"1291407802446778493","answers":["firmos"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine accusative plural** of *firmus* (firm, strong)?"},"L1007781":{"interactionID":"1291407815575076866","answers":["alacris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive singular** of *alacer* (brisk, eager, active)?"},"L1019696":{"interactionID":"1291407821291913228","answers":["averteris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *averto* (to turn away from, to divert)?"},"L1020211":{"interactionID":"1291407840904351815","answers":["suffeceram"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *sufficio* (to be sufficient)?"},"L1015866":{"interactionID":"1291407877784731728","answers":["quiescent"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future active indicative** of *quiesco* (to rest, keep quiet)?"},"L1002583":{"interactionID":"1291407905903476899","answers":["religionum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural** of *religio, religionis* (religion)?"},"L1021847":{"interactionID":"1291407913411280907","answers":["evenitis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *evenio* (to happen)?"},"L1002005":{"interactionID":"1291407922936545351","answers":["fatis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *fatum, fati* (fate)?"},"L1013961":{"interactionID":"1291407930587091006","answers":["latuit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *lateo* (to be hidden, concealed, safe)?"},"L1004686":{"interactionID":"1291407980830658615","answers":["aegra"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine vocative singular** of *aeger* (ill, troubled)?"},"L1013399":{"interactionID":"1291407989202223285","answers":["prohibueritis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *prohibeo* (to forbid, prohibit)?"},"L1007920":{"interactionID":"1291408021796421756","answers":["silvestrium"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter genitive plural** of *silvester* (belonging to a forest, woody)?"},"L1017116":{"interactionID":"1291408031225090098","answers":["intenderas"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *intendo* (to bend, aim, stretch)?"},"L1017335":{"interactionID":"1291408113504882708","answers":["imposueratis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *impono* (to lay upon, impose)?"},"L1005432":{"interactionID":"1291408122828554301","answers":["contente"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine vocative singular** of *contentus* (tense, intent; satisfied)?"},"L1009086":{"interactionID":"1291408176754856017","answers":["tulerunt"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *fero* (to bear, carry, bring)?"},"L1001698":{"interactionID":"1291408187739869307","answers":["nuntia"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *nuntium, nuntii* (message)?"},"L1000134":{"interactionID":"1291408281801068584","answers":["provinciis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *provincia, provinciae* (province)?"},"L1011092":{"interactionID":"1291408289338228746","answers":["negabis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future active indicative** of *nego* (to say no, to deny)?"},"L1003721":{"interactionID":"1291408298402381946","answers":["discrimini"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *discrimen, discriminis* (interval, difference; turning-point)?"},"L1006599":{"interactionID":"1291408499108085760","answers":["pium"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine accusative singular** of *pius* (dutiful, pious, honest)?"},"L1019400":{"interactionID":"1291408633225285776","answers":["cesserunt"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *cedo* (to move; to happen, result)?"},"L1000756":{"interactionID":"1291408697565778003","answers":["formae"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *forma, formae* (form, figure, beauty)?"},"L1008035":{"interactionID":"1291408704624660522","answers":["istius"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive singular** of *iste* (that)?"},"L1002143":{"interactionID":"1291408710765117561","answers":["barbare"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **vocative singular** of *barbarus, barbari* (barbarian)?"},"L1014662":{"interactionID":"1291408716570165352","answers":["vixisti"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *vivo* (to live)?"},"L1000626":{"interactionID":"1291408723583172628","answers":["morarum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural** of *mora, morae* (delay)?"},"L1017500":{"interactionID":"1291408728813473804","answers":["frues"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future active indicative** of *fruor* (to use, enjoy)?"},"L1018948":{"interactionID":"1291408782676463616","answers":["coniunximus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *coniungo* (to join)?"},"L1009622":{"interactionID":"1291408797553787004","answers":["vocavisti"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *voco* (to call, summon, invoke)?"},"L1016622":{"interactionID":"1291408809553821696","answers":["omittent"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future active indicative** of *omitto* (to dismiss, neglect)?"},"L1009795":{"interactionID":"1291408818693210165","answers":["vacavero"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *vaco* (to be empty, vacant, free, idle)?"},"L1016813":{"interactionID":"1291408827396390933","answers":["miseratis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *mitto* (to send, throw)?"},"L1016785":{"interactionID":"1291408844152635455","answers":["nasce"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active imperative** of *nascor* (to be born)?"},"L1010426":{"interactionID":"1291408975711047804","answers":["precabis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future active indicative** of *precor* (to pray, request)?"},"L1004297":{"interactionID":"1291408986649923695","answers":["genua"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *genu, genus* (knee)?"},"L1010039":{"interactionID":"1291408993884966943","answers":["simulavistis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *simulo* (to imitate)?"},"L1008104":{"interactionID":"1291409021395533856","answers":["earundem"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive plural** of *idem* (the same)?"},"L1016658":{"interactionID":"1291409027603103744","answers":["occident"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future active indicative** of *occido* (to kill)?"},"L1015563":{"interactionID":"1291409035932864512","answers":["restituit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *restituo* (to give back, restore)?"},"L1000763":{"interactionID":"1291409043134349356","answers":["formas"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *forma, formae* (form, figure, beauty)?"},"L1002776":{"interactionID":"1291409056010997780","answers":["imperatoribus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *imperator, imperatoris* (commander, emperor)?"},"L1020524":{"interactionID":"1291409063330185319","answers":["perfeceris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *perficio* (to achieve, complete, accomplish)?"},"L1014168":{"interactionID":"1291409072117252158","answers":["horruerant"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *horreo* (to be frightened at)?"},"L1003039":{"interactionID":"1291409078995652651","answers":["vulnus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **vocative singular** of *vulnus, vulneris* (wound)?"},"L1020484":{"interactionID":"1291409087032201226","answers":["perveneramus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *pervenio* (to arrive at, reach)?"},"L1006243":{"interactionID":"1291409093386436620","answers":["laeta"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine vocative singular** of *laetus* (joyful)?"},"L1019332":{"interactionID":"1291409099090694144","answers":["cinxeramus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *cingo* (to surround, encircle)?"},"L1008597":{"interactionID":"1291409107428835398","answers":["redivi"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *redeo* (to go or come back)?"},"L1021174":{"interactionID":"1291409116589461545","answers":["corripiemus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future active indicative** of *corripio* (to seize, snatch; to blame)?"},"L1021706":{"interactionID":"1291409123111604254","answers":["muniveras"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *munio* (to fortify, defend)?"},"L1006237":{"interactionID":"1291409129507782657","answers":["laetae"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine dative singular** of *laetus* (joyful)?"},"L1017972":{"interactionID":"1291409136751476828","answers":["elegerint"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *eligo* (to choose, elect)?"},"L1005590":{"interactionID":"1291409148214513776","answers":["divina"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter nominative plural** of *divinus* (divine)?"},"L1019340":{"interactionID":"1291409157773197446","answers":["cinxerint"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *cingo* (to surround, encircle)?"},"L1007867":{"interactionID":"1291409240250122250","answers":["salubribus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine ablative plural** of *saluber* (salutary, beneficial)?"},"L1005482":{"interactionID":"1291409251138539531","answers":["crebris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter ablative plural** of *creber* (frequent, abounding in)?"},"L1004505":{"interactionID":"1291409258100949023","answers":["speciem"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative singular** of *species, speciei* (appearance)?"},"L1006797":{"interactionID":"1291409326233354262","answers":["pulchros"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine accusative plural** of *pulcher* (beautiful, handsome)?"},"L1005709":{"interactionID":"1291409336102551683","answers":["extremae"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine nominative plural** of *extremus* (extreme, latest)?"},"L1001403":{"interactionID":"1291409343832527009","answers":["telo"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *telum, teli* (dart, spear)?"},"L1000968":{"interactionID":"1291409351348588565","answers":["tenebrae"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *tenebrae, tenebrarum* (darkness)?"},"L1011575":{"interactionID":"1291409358885879951","answers":["indicaveratis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *indico* (to point out, indicate)?"},"L1000997":{"interactionID":"1291409381644177408","answers":["deliciis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *deliciae, deliciarum* (delight, pleasure; beloved)?"},"L1021246":{"interactionID":"1291409390150226111","answers":["capiemus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future active indicative** of *capio* (to take, seize, grasp)?"},"L1013995":{"interactionID":"1291409417312538645","answers":["iussi"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *iubeo* (to command, order)?"},"L1014358":{"interactionID":"1291409442776289301","answers":["egemus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *egeo* (to need, lack)?"},"L1016383":{"interactionID":"1291411717665980426","answers":["perdidero"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *perdo* (to destroy, ruin; to lose)?"},"L1016473":{"interactionID":"1291411735689039882","answers":["pascam"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future active indicative** of *pasco* (to pasture, feed, nourish)?"},"L1018156":{"interactionID":"1291412170713731105","answers":["discedimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *discedo* (to go away from, to leave)?"},"L1020216":{"interactionID":"1291412183590113405","answers":["suffecerant"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *sufficio* (to be sufficient)?"},"L1008634":{"interactionID":"1291412196223352872","answers":["profuisti"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *prosum* (to be useful or of use, to benefit)?"},"LADV105592":{"interactionID":"1291428141520261211","answers":["percussi estis"],"genus":"LADV_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect passive indicative** of *percutio* (to strike; to kill)?"},"LFIFTH006560":{"interactionID":"1291446414349697105","answers":["alunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *alo* (to feed, nourish)?"},"LFIFTH003027":{"interactionID":"1291446666150547517","answers":["quocumque"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine ablative singular** of *quicumque* (whoever, whatever)?"},"LFIFTH000476":{"interactionID":"1291520316216053780","answers":["studio"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *studium, studii* (desire, study)?"},"LFIFTH005073":{"interactionID":"1291520671230328862","answers":["trahit"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *traho* (to draw, drag)?"},"F001760":{"interactionID":"1291562565603692625","answers":["CHALCIOPE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What daughter of Aeetes married Phrixus?"},"F001913":{"interactionID":"1291529516543508651","answers":["ALCINOUS AND ARETE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What Phaeacian king and queen agreed to protect Medea from the Colchians if she marry Jason?"},"F001178":{"interactionID":"1291529453188550747","answers":["ACHILLES"],"genus":"myth","question":"To whom does Odysseus tell of the Trojan Horse in the underworld?"},"F000512":{"interactionID":"1291543258387845150","answers":["ORION"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who does Odysseus see driving beasts through the fields of Asphodel?"},"F000304":{"interactionID":"1291543606892695644","answers":["SIRIUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the dog of Orion?"},"F000124":{"interactionID":"1291543690007023626","answers":["PHEIDIAS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What sculptor and architect designed the Parthenon?"},"LFIFTH003924":{"interactionID":"1291544860255322173","answers":["narravi"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *narro* (to tell, narrate)?"},"LFIFTH001219":{"interactionID":"1291554037128495145","answers":["fulmen"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative singular** of *fulmen, fulminis* (lightning)?"},"LFIFTH004756":{"interactionID":"1291554061493080104","answers":["manet"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *maneo* (to stay, remain)?"},"F001432":{"interactionID":"1291554182486032395","answers":["MEGAPENTHES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who exchanged kingdoms with Perseus?"},"F000458":{"interactionID":"1291554254523207690","answers":["P. OVIDIUS NASO"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who wrote the Metamorphoses?"},"F000803":{"interactionID":"1291554341844680714","answers":["PISA"],"genus":"myth","question":"Where did the chariot race with Oenomaus begin?"},"F001278":{"interactionID":"1293050780139388969","answers":["POSEIDON"],"genus":"myth","question":"What father of Polyphemus cursed Odysseus?"},"F001907":{"interactionID":"1291554399629475972","answers":["PINDAR"],"genus":"myth","question":"What Greek poet wrote Odes, such as the Pythian Odes, to athletic champions?"},"F000187":{"interactionID":"1291554459670941716","answers":["CYPRUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What had the first prostitutes, as a result of a curse from Aphrodite?"},"F000548":{"interactionID":"1291554794519138354","answers":["OTUS AND EPHIALTES"],"genus":"myth","question":"What twin giants tried to storm Olympus?"},"F001225":{"interactionID":"1293802745287020587","answers":["NEREUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who told Menelaus how to return home safely?"},"F002036":{"interactionID":"1291554919261667408","answers":["NELEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who demanded that Bias steal the cattle of Phylacus?"},"F000616":{"interactionID":"1293438770284068865","answers":["AGENOR"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Cadmus?"},"F000633":{"interactionID":"1291555019413258311","answers":["ARES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Harmonia?"},"F000319":{"interactionID":"1291555114271903794","answers":["PHAEDRA"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who leaves a suicide note for Theseus, falsely incriminating Hippolytus?"},"L1001888":{"interactionID":"1291555205833297951","answers":["ingeniis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *ingenium, ingenii* (temperament, talent)?"},"L1011141":{"interactionID":"1291555233893449738","answers":["narraverat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *narro* (to tell, narrate)?"},"L1008988":{"interactionID":"1291555322665893949","answers":["maluerit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *malo* (to prefer)?"},"L1021425":{"interactionID":"1291555331205365861","answers":["serviet"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future active indicative** of *servio* (to be a servant or slave, to serve)?"},"L1021218":{"interactionID":"1291555338742403082","answers":["conspexerunt"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *conspicio* (to observe, to gaze upon)?"},"F000490":{"interactionID":"1291558435539783732","answers":["DIONYSUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What god was sometimes called Iacchus?"},"G002813":{"interactionID":"1291558494780129320","answers":["velut"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find all 1 principal parts of the adverb that matches the definition *even as, just as*. Do not include macrons."},"F002232":{"interactionID":"1291559123321622558","answers":["SEMIRAMIS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the queen of Babylon during Pyramus and Thisbe's lives?"},"F000816":{"interactionID":"1291559670766506085","answers":["ATREUS AND THYESTES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who were the sons of Pelops, called the Pelopidae?"},"F002166":{"interactionID":"1291566632392593411","answers":["DELPHI"],"genus":"myth","question":"Where did Aepytus learn that Iamus would be the greatest of seers?"},"F001772":{"interactionID":"1291559971221405748","answers":["JASON"],"genus":"myth","question":"Whose mother is variously named as Polymede, Alcimede or Amphinome?"},"F000703":{"interactionID":"1291560185562792057","answers":["COLONUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Where was Sophocles born?"},"F001621":{"interactionID":"1291560380354789438","answers":["RAINED STONES"],"genus":"myth","question":"How did Zeus help Heracles when he ran out of arrows against the Ligurians?"},"F001993":{"interactionID":"1291560528375840820","answers":["ASTYDAMIA"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the wife of Acastus?"},"F000583":{"interactionID":"1293370979124510783","answers":["VERGIL"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who does Dante describe as his guide in the underworld?"},"F002178":{"interactionID":"1291562015550341290","answers":["ESCAPE AGAMEMNON"],"genus":"myth","question":"Why did Dionysus turn Anius' daughters into white doves?"},"F000276":{"interactionID":"1291562308992241664","answers":["STAG"],"genus":"myth","question":"Into what type of animal was Actaeon transformed?"},"F000967":{"interactionID":"1291562571299815435","answers":["HELENUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Which of Priam's sons had the gift of prophecy?"},"F000280":{"interactionID":"1291562758847856681","answers":["CADMUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Autonoe?"},"F000766":{"interactionID":"1291564424158777354","answers":["FURIES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who pursued Alcmaeon after he killed his mother?"},"F002234":{"interactionID":"1291564451862155346","answers":["TOMB OF NINUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Where did Pyramus and Thisbe plan to meet?"},"F001490":{"interactionID":"1291565117271445524","answers":["IPHICLES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the son of Iolaus?"},"F000046":{"interactionID":"1291565736413761648","answers":["CYRUS THE GREAT"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the king of Persia when Croesus attacked?"},"F001709":{"interactionID":"1291566844305735702","answers":["CEYX"],"genus":"myth","question":"With what king of Trachis did Deianira live while Heracles served Omphale?"},"F001179":{"interactionID":"1291571533772226712","answers":["NEOPTOLEMUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who does Odysseus say was the one fellow warrior not afraid in the horse?"},"F000626":{"interactionID":"1291568167164055594","answers":["ARES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of the serpent which guarded a spring Cadmus used?"},"F002071":{"interactionID":"1291568280242491443","answers":["DEIANIRA"],"genus":"myth","question":"What daughter of Oeneus married Heracles?"},"L1011368":{"interactionID":"1291571330721910874","answers":["laceras"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *lacero* (to tear to pieces, to lacerate)?"},"L1010168":{"interactionID":"1291571397923045438","answers":["rogabas"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *rogo* (to ask, interrogate)?"},"F000015":{"interactionID":"1291571524742025337","answers":["DRYADS (OR HAMADRYADS)"],"genus":"myth","question":"What name was given to the nymphs of trees?"},"F000744":{"interactionID":"1291571553477328949","answers":["ZEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who hurled a thunderbolt to knock Capaneus from the walls of Thebes?"},"F002097":{"interactionID":"1291571633928146977","answers":["MADE LOVE IN SACRED PLACE"],"genus":"myth","question":"Why were Atalanta and Melanion transformed into lions?"},"D000195":{"interactionID":"1291590131592990773","answers":["costa"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *cutlet* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"H000548":{"interactionID":"1291590434312945826","answers":["MARCELLUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Who won the Spolia Opima by defeating Viridomarus in single combat at Clastidium in 222 BC?"},"H000462":{"interactionID":"1308675223234678814","answers":["ELEPHANTS"],"genus":"history","question":"What military innovation was Pyrrhus the first to use against the Romans?"},"T002160":{"interactionID":"1291590653695758426","answers":["FASTER THAN ASPARAGUS CAN BE COOKED"],"genus":"translation","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *velocius quam asparagi coquantur*?"},"T001640":{"interactionID":"1291590843458785280","answers":["FOR SCIENCE AND NATION"],"genus":"translation","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *pro scientia et patria*?"},"LFIFTH005859":{"interactionID":"1291591812967960688","answers":["frangis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *frango* (to break)?"},"LFIFTH003116":{"interactionID":"1291591976784756766","answers":["transivi"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *transeo* (to go over or across)?"},"L1012143":{"interactionID":"1291592332520456192","answers":["damnat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *damno* (to condemn)?"},"LFIFTH006853":{"interactionID":"1291592438607253514","answers":["incepit"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *incipio* (to begin)?"},"L1009448":{"interactionID":"1291592454369443893","answers":["adiveras"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *adeo* (to go to, approach)?"},"LFIFTH004367":{"interactionID":"1291592462669709365","answers":["armavisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *armo* (to arm, equip)?"},"LFIFTH007097":{"interactionID":"1291592473591808094","answers":["reperiunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *reperio* (to find)?"},"L1018592":{"interactionID":"1291592476146143354","answers":["currebas"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *curro* (to run)?"},"L1006749":{"interactionID":"1291592690995171369","answers":["publicum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine accusative singular** of *publicus* (public)?"},"L1020059":{"interactionID":"1291592945459400804","answers":["accendetis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future active indicative** of *accendo* (to kindle, set on fire; to incite)?"},"L1018106":{"interactionID":"1291592967798263840","answers":["diviseras"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *divido* (to divide)?"},"L1017742":{"interactionID":"1291593211143520337","answers":["fefellimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *fallo* (to deceive, cheat, disappoint)?"},"L1012412":{"interactionID":"1291593578941775954","answers":["cogitavisti"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *cogito* (to think, meditate, plan)?"},"L1005501":{"interactionID":"1291620017842032752","answers":["cunctorum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine genitive plural** of *cunctus* (all together, the whole)?"},"L1014981":{"interactionID":"1291620039144898560","answers":["tradiderit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *trado* (to deliver, betray, report)?"},"L1016547":{"interactionID":"1291620106652090419","answers":["ostendet"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future active indicative** of *ostendo* (to show, exhibit, display)?"},"LFIFTH004324":{"interactionID":"1291620344397959178","answers":["clamavit"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *clamo* (to call, cry out, declare)?"},"L1016314":{"interactionID":"1291620544499683339","answers":["permiserimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *permitto* (to allow, suffer, permit)?"},"L1012813":{"interactionID":"1291620615081558039","answers":["videbam"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *video* (to see)?"},"LFIFTH005412":{"interactionID":"1291621083002306630","answers":["processisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *procedo* (to go forth, advance)?"},"LFIFTH006027":{"interactionID":"1291621134764216392","answers":["ducitis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *duco* (to lead, conduct)?"},"LFIFTH005882":{"interactionID":"1291621382861488138","answers":["florit"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *floreo* (to bloom, blossom; to be prosperous)?"},"LFIFTH005042":{"interactionID":"1291621408732086283","answers":["veximus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *veho* (to bear, carry)?"},"LFIFTH004545":{"interactionID":"1291621431066755072","answers":["siluerunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *sileo* (to keep silent, to be quiet)?"},"LFIFTH001819":{"interactionID":"1291621797275500596","answers":["certae"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive singular** of *certus* (determined, settled)?"},"LFIFTH003859":{"interactionID":"1291621935905767455","answers":["obstitisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *obsto* (to stand against, oppose)?"},"LFIFTH006410":{"interactionID":"1291621972463190048","answers":["cingimus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *cingo* (to surround, encircle)?"},"LFIFTH006161":{"interactionID":"1291622010375508060","answers":["deduxi"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *deduco* (to lead away)?"},"LFIFTH005216":{"interactionID":"1291623697483825213","answers":["sequit"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *sequor* (to follow)?"},"LFIFTH003535":{"interactionID":"1291623903495589959","answers":["temptavisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *tempto* (to handle, touch; to attempt)?"},"LFIFTH004485":{"interactionID":"1291623915889758278","answers":["timuerunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *timeo* (to be afraid of)?"},"LFIFTH005794":{"interactionID":"1291624427489984532","answers":["incessisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *incedo* (to go, step, march along)?"},"LFIFTH006819":{"interactionID":"1291624764183674891","answers":["peperi"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *pario* (to bring forth, bear, produce)?"},"LFIFTH005241":{"interactionID":"1291624782038831144","answers":["ruerunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *ruo* (to fall down; to cast down, prostrate)?"},"LFIFTH002702":{"interactionID":"1291624798748672000","answers":["mitis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine/feminine genitive singular** of *mitis* (mild, gentle)?"},"LFIFTH005157":{"interactionID":"1291624806592020534","answers":["surreximus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *surgo* (to rise, arise, get up, stand up)?"},"LFIFTH003946":{"interactionID":"1291624813869273135","answers":["miras"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *miror* (to wonder, to be amazed, to admire)?"},"LFIFTH003057":{"interactionID":"1291624842633805894","answers":["utram"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine accusative singular** of *uter* (which of two?)?"},"LFIFTH003416":{"interactionID":"1291624856718409789","answers":["absumus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *absum* (to be away, to be absent)?"},"G001143":{"interactionID":"1291631708533424149","answers":["N1"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the part of speech/Latin inflection category of the word *hora horae f.*.\n\nPlease use the following for your answer.\n**Adjective: 1st and 2nd Declension:** A12\n**Adjective: 3rd Declension:** A3\n**Adjective: Indeclinable:** AI\n**Adjective: Numeral:** AN\n**Adverb:** ADV\n**Conjunction:** CONJ\n**Noun: 1st Declension:** N1\n**Noun: 2nd Declension:** N2\n**Noun: 3rd Declension:** N3\n**Noun: 4th Declension:** N4\n**Noun: 5th Declension:** N5\n**Noun: Indeclinable:** NI\n**Preposition:** PREP\n**Pronoun:** PRO\n**Verb: 1st Conjugation:** V1\n**Verb: 2nd Conjugation:** V2\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -io:** V3i\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -o:** V3\n**Verb: 4th Conjugation:** V4\n**Verb: Deponent:** VD\n**Verb: Impersonal:** VIP\n**Verb: Irregular:** VIRR"},"LFIFTH001470":{"interactionID":"1291632894703308821","answers":["fluctu"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *fluctus, fluctus* (wave)?"},"LFIFTH005021":{"interactionID":"1291633782020902934","answers":["vertistis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *verto* (to turn, transform, translate)?"},"LFIFTH000107":{"interactionID":"1291636025268895777","answers":["amicae"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *amica, amicae* (friend, lover)?"},"LFIFTH000960":{"interactionID":"1291636097738080377","answers":["uxores"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *uxor, uxoris* (wife)?"},"LFIFTH004939":{"interactionID":"1291639738427641948","answers":["debent"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *debeo* (to owe; to be bound)?"},"LFIFTH006751":{"interactionID":"1291767046907887721","answers":["praecipitis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *praecipio* (to advise, instruct, teach)?"},"LFIFTH002158":{"interactionID":"1291770764512464956","answers":["invitam"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine accusative singular** of *invitus* (unwilling)?"},"LFIFTH006006":{"interactionID":"1291771878276464691","answers":["educunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *educo* (to lead forth, bring away)?"},"LFIFTH005343":{"interactionID":"1291918867353960478","answers":["reddidimus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *reddo* (to give back)?"},"G002704":{"interactionID":"1291962870795604048","answers":["back, rear","a tergo: from the rear"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *tergum tergi n.*."},"G000462":{"interactionID":"1291964135948550308","answers":["V3"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the part of speech/Latin inflection category of the word *cogo cogere coegi coactum*.\n\nPlease use the following for your answer.\n**Adjective: 1st and 2nd Declension:** A12\n**Adjective: 3rd Declension:** A3\n**Adjective: Indeclinable:** AI\n**Adjective: Numeral:** AN\n**Adverb:** ADV\n**Conjunction:** CONJ\n**Noun: 1st Declension:** N1\n**Noun: 2nd Declension:** N2\n**Noun: 3rd Declension:** N3\n**Noun: 4th Declension:** N4\n**Noun: 5th Declension:** N5\n**Noun: Indeclinable:** NI\n**Preposition:** PREP\n**Pronoun:** PRO\n**Verb: 1st Conjugation:** V1\n**Verb: 2nd Conjugation:** V2\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -io:** V3i\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -o:** V3\n**Verb: 4th Conjugation:** V4\n**Verb: Deponent:** VD\n**Verb: Impersonal:** VIP\n**Verb: Irregular:** VIRR"},"P000162":{"interactionID":"1315531711509172234","answers":["JUSTIFICATION FOR WAR"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Casus Belli*?"},"LFIFTH001736":{"interactionID":"1291966738887606312","answers":["avidi"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter genitive singular** of *avidus* (eager, greedy)?"},"LFIFTH004274":{"interactionID":"1291966750711222344","answers":["conas"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *conor* (to attempt, try)?"},"LFIFTH003503":{"interactionID":"1291968776387952680","answers":["venerat"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *veneror* (to worship, venerate)?"},"L1004531":{"interactionID":"1291969110028324945","answers":["luxuriis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative plural** of *luxuria, luxuriae* (licentiousness, luxury, extravagance)?"},"L1000205":{"interactionID":"1291969119700254720","answers":["scientias"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *scientia, scientiae* (knowledge)?"},"LFIFTH003023":{"interactionID":"1291969385623191594","answers":["cuiuscumque"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter genitive singular** of *quicumque* (whoever, whatever)?"},"P000134":{"interactionID":"1339064383321673799","answers":["(SENATUS CONSULTUM ULTIMUM) FINAL DECREE OF THE SENATE (MARITAL LAW)"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *S.C.U.*?"},"P000147":{"interactionID":"1342872185731026985","answers":["YOU HIT THE NAIL ON THE HEAD"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *rem acu tetigisti*?"},"P000022":{"interactionID":"1355580499883589754","answers":["NON SIBI, SED SUIS. (\"NOT FOR HERSELF, BUT FOR HER OWN.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Tulane University*?"},"L1016493":{"interactionID":"1291973364839350336","answers":["paverit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *pasco* (to pasture, feed, nourish)?"},"P000036":{"interactionID":"1339065408678006866","answers":["DISCIPLINA PRAESIDIUM CIVITATIS (\"INSTRUCTION IS THE SAFEGUARD OF THE STATE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Texas*?"},"L1010376":{"interactionID":"1291974446260817930","answers":["properaverint"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *propero* (to hasten)?"},"L1013665":{"interactionID":"1291974556914814976","answers":["nubebo"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future active indicative** of *nubo* (to marry)?"},"L1010766":{"interactionID":"1291974650921746495","answers":["ornabant"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *orno* (to adorn, to equipe)?"},"L1014059":{"interactionID":"1291974660426170499","answers":["intuebatis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *intueor* (to look at, regard)?"},"L1021064":{"interactionID":"1291974669188206603","answers":["deficies"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future active indicative** of *deficio* (to withdraw, desert; to cease, disappear)?"},"L1006978":{"interactionID":"1291975943807569951","answers":["suis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine ablative plural** of *suus* (his, her, its, their)?"},"LFIFTH001760":{"interactionID":"1291980059669823520","answers":["benigni"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter genitive singular** of *benignus* (kind, friendly, favorable)?"},"LFIFTH001818":{"interactionID":"1291980403485184082","answers":["certi"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine genitive singular** of *certus* (determined, settled)?"},"LFIFTH002953":{"interactionID":"1291982768321986581","answers":["eodem"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter ablative singular** of *idem* (the same)?"},"LFIFTH002117":{"interactionID":"1291983212976799795","answers":["immensa"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter nominative plural** of *immensus* (boundless, immense)?"},"LFIFTH002489":{"interactionID":"1291983227950465077","answers":["sua"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter nominative plural** of *suus* (his, her, its, their)?"},"P000224":{"interactionID":"1308687117357940778","answers":["IN THIS SIGN YOU WILL CONQUER"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **In hoc signo vinces**."},"P000030":{"interactionID":"1308686638419017730","answers":["SALUS POPULI. (\"THE WELFARE OF THE PEOPLE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Missouri*?"},"P000211":{"interactionID":"1308810827637460993","answers":["AUGUSTUS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Festina lente**?"},"F001189":{"interactionID":"1292004341783334942","answers":["ASTYANAX"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who is the son of Hector?"},"F001104":{"interactionID":"1292007483639988346","answers":["TELEPHUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was healed by scrapings from Achilles spear?"},"F000954":{"interactionID":"1292008071962431528","answers":["ILUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Laomedon?"},"F001683":{"interactionID":"1292008402536501310","answers":["OENEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Deianira?"},"F002205":{"interactionID":"1292009614401077268","answers":["TELETHUSA"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the mother of Iphis and wife of Ligdus?"},"LFIFTH007056":{"interactionID":"1292121204634685491","answers":["servivit"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *servio* (to be a servant or slave, to serve)?"},"L1003847":{"interactionID":"1292122326317531257","answers":["clientium"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural** of *cliens, clientis* (client; follower)?"},"L1004246":{"interactionID":"1292123178394583061","answers":["partus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **vocative singular** of *partus, partus* (bearing, birth)?"},"L1011454":{"interactionID":"1292123387937820782","answers":["iurabimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future active indicative** of *iuro* (to swear, take an oath)?"},"L1000131":{"interactionID":"1292124058632192122","answers":["provinciarum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural** of *provincia, provinciae* (province)?"},"L1004982":{"interactionID":"1292124066626404453","answers":["apte"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine vocative singular** of *aptus* (suitable)?"},"L1019947":{"interactionID":"1292124144460103815","answers":["adducam"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future active indicative** of *adduco* (to lead, to bring to)?"},"L1000518":{"interactionID":"1292125114368000103","answers":["reginarum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural** of *regina, reginae* (queen)?"},"L1020833":{"interactionID":"1292125783451631627","answers":["fugietis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future active indicative** of *fugio* (to flee, to run away)?"},"L1004826":{"interactionID":"1292125809829482516","answers":["valido"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine dative singular** of *validus* (strong, powerful)?"},"L1006112":{"interactionID":"1292125820990783540","answers":["improbis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter ablative plural** of *improbus* (bad, dishonest)?"},"L1021844":{"interactionID":"1292125835016274012","answers":["evenis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *evenio* (to happen)?"},"A000330":{"interactionID":"1292157995572264991","answers":["live"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What does the Greek word **zao (ζαω)** mean?"},"A000022":{"interactionID":"1292158058562326668","answers":["pais (παις), child","ago (αγω), to lead, bring"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **pedagogue**?"},"L1021787":{"interactionID":"1292182423802613762","answers":["finiveritis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *finio* (to limit, to bound, to terminate)?"},"L1010877":{"interactionID":"1292183678356553768","answers":["occupabit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future active indicative** of *occupo* (to occupy, seize)?"},"L1014318":{"interactionID":"1292184201931784387","answers":["fatebunt"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future active indicative** of *fateor* (to confess, acknowledge)?"},"L1006949":{"interactionID":"1292184224505401424","answers":["superba"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter accusative plural** of *superbus* (proud, arrogant)?"},"L1006841":{"interactionID":"1292187979816767559","answers":["saevum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter accusative singular** of *saevus* (furious, ferocious)?"},"P000020":{"interactionID":"1307177039341686804","answers":["AD MAIOREM DEI GLORIAM (\"FOR THE GREATER GLORY OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *The Jesuit*?"},"P000104":{"interactionID":"1295945098424750162","answers":["(TER IN DIE) THREE TIMES A DAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *t.i.d.*?"},"P000017":{"interactionID":"1342872670944886884","answers":["CRUX SPES UNICA (\"THE CROSS IS THE ONLY HOPE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Notre Dame University*?"},"LFIFTH004160":{"interactionID":"1292193093285580891","answers":["educat"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *educo* (to bring up, educate)?"},"A000426":{"interactionID":"1292622106156339242","answers":["krypto (κρυπτω), to hide"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **crypt**?"},"LFIFTH001567":{"interactionID":"1292622446637223957","answers":["aegrae"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive singular** of *aeger* (ill, troubled)?"},"LFIFTH002861":{"interactionID":"1292626876895858688","answers":["silvestrem"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine accusative singular** of *silvester* (belonging to a forest, woody)?"},"F000504":{"interactionID":"1293050345039204395","answers":["TELEMACHUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the son of Penelope and Odysseus?"},"LFIFTH005166":{"interactionID":"1293050307776876574","answers":["advenisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *advenio* (to come to, reach, arrive at)?"},"F000516":{"interactionID":"1293050610412814407","answers":["DELPHI"],"genus":"myth","question":"What city had the early name Pytho?"},"F002108":{"interactionID":"1293050769129476127","answers":["SISYPHUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who instituted the Isthmian Games?"},"F001737":{"interactionID":"1293050800590819338","answers":["TEMENUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Which of the Heraclids took over Argos?"},"L1002208":{"interactionID":"1293051043994931272","answers":["anni"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *annus, anni* (year)?"},"L1002383":{"interactionID":"1293063370299277425","answers":["virtutes"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *virtus, virtutis* (courage, virtue)?"},"L1003850":{"interactionID":"1293064844232228968","answers":["clientibus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *cliens, clientis* (client; follower)?"},"L1020729":{"interactionID":"1293064863207395348","answers":["ingredit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *ingredior* (to go into, to enter)?"},"L1011220":{"interactionID":"1293064914927226931","answers":["mirabimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future active indicative** of *miror* (to wonder, to be amazed, to admire)?"},"L1015218":{"interactionID":"1293065061971132436","answers":["advenient"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future active indicative** of *advenio* (to come to, reach, arrive at)?"},"L1000572":{"interactionID":"1293065187699720204","answers":["patriarum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural** of *patria, patriae* (native country)?"},"P000080":{"interactionID":"1355173643318984854","answers":["AD MAIOREM DEI GLORIAM (\"FOR THE GREATER GLORY OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Society of Jesuits*?"},"F001712":{"interactionID":"1293065644090064961","answers":["LICHAS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What herald was hurled to his death into the sea after delivering a poisoned robe?"},"L1007321":{"interactionID":"1293065717255634994","answers":["fallaci"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *fallax* (deceitful)?"},"L1000413":{"interactionID":"1293066203366953122","answers":["viis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *via, viae* (way, path, street)?"},"L1001224":{"interactionID":"1293066223491354746","answers":["soceris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative plural** of *socer, soceri* (father-in-law)?"},"F000179":{"interactionID":"1293066473119682600","answers":["APHRODITE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What deity possessed a magic girdle with irresistible powers of enticement?"},"F000943":{"interactionID":"1293066495328387072","answers":["PRIAM"],"genus":"myth","question":"By what better name is the Trojan Podarces known?"},"F001481":{"interactionID":"1293066705513353246","answers":["IPHICLES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the son of Amphitryon and Alcmena, half-brother of Heracles?"},"F001194":{"interactionID":"1293077156510826528","answers":["ODYSSEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who received Hecuba as part of the spoils of Troy?"},"F001358":{"interactionID":"1293066840108699711","answers":["TIRESIAS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who had told Odysseus to carry an oar until people thought it was a winnowing fan?"},"F000499":{"interactionID":"1293066853404639315","answers":["ELPENOR"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who first addresses Odysseus in the underworld before drinking the blood?"},"F000454":{"interactionID":"1293066923562500147","answers":["ALCIBIADES"],"genus":"myth","question":"What Athenian leader supposedly desecrated the Herms?"},"F001143":{"interactionID":"1293066932999950428","answers":["BATTLE BETWEEN GODS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What does the term 'theomachy' refer to?"},"L1005247":{"interactionID":"1293067105654149191","answers":["candidae"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine dative singular** of *candidus* (white, clear)?"},"L1005183":{"interactionID":"1293067115279945829","answers":["blandi"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine genitive singular** of *blandus* (agreeable)?"},"F001816":{"interactionID":"1293067218740973578","answers":["POLYDEUCES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the best boxer among the Argonauts?"},"L1017469":{"interactionID":"1293067492931141692","answers":["gessi"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *gero* (to bear, carry)?"},"F001087":{"interactionID":"1293067549579284500","answers":["MOPSUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Whom did Calchas challenge to a seer contest after the Trojan War?"},"F002299":{"interactionID":"1293067564800409661","answers":["JASON"],"genus":"myth","question":"After forcing fire-breathing bulls into submission, who yoked them to a plow and used them to sow a field with dragon's teeth?"},"F001817":{"interactionID":"1293067669985296384","answers":["IDAS AND LYNCEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What two brothers and later enemies of the Dioscuri (Castor & Polydeuces) joined them on the Argo?"},"L1018881":{"interactionID":"1293067772124729435","answers":["consuescebat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *consuesco* (to be accustomed)?"},"F000791":{"interactionID":"1293070813074948141","answers":["TANTALUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Pelops?"},"F002324":{"interactionID":"1293071566728593488","answers":["IOBATES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who received a letter instructing him to kill its messenger because he had allegedly seduced the wife of Proetus?"},"F001335":{"interactionID":"1293071595635609601","answers":["EUMAEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What faithful swineherd of Odysseus first recognized him?"},"F000966":{"interactionID":"1293071734425260053","answers":["ASTYANAX"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the child of Hector and Andromache?"},"F000920":{"interactionID":"1293072087862218802","answers":["AESACUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who foretold that Paris would lead to Troy's destruction?"},"F000988":{"interactionID":"1293072473507627059","answers":["LYCIANS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Of what Trojan ally were Glaucus and Sarpedon the leaders?"},"F001029":{"interactionID":"1293072519628324906","answers":["PRIAM"],"genus":"myth","question":"To whom does Helen describe the Greeks as they fight in the plain?"},"F002329":{"interactionID":"1293072536174723102","answers":["ETEOCLES"],"genus":"myth","question":"What king of Thebes refused to give up power when his year to rule was up?"},"F000976":{"interactionID":"1293072545662107658","answers":["CASSANDRA"],"genus":"myth","question":"What daughter of Priam received the gift of prophecy from Apollo?"},"F002126":{"interactionID":"1293072557695565824","answers":["TIRYNS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Where was Proetus, the purifier of Bellerophon, king?"},"F000933":{"interactionID":"1293072672724619306","answers":["SEA MONSTER"],"genus":"myth","question":"What did Poseidon send to Troy to punish Laomedon?"},"F001197":{"interactionID":"1293076563704807479","answers":["POLYMESTOR"],"genus":"myth","question":"To whom did Priam send his son Polydorus for safe refuge during the war?"},"P000111":{"interactionID":"1308687312871231498","answers":["(DEO VOLENTE) GOD WILLING"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *D.V.*?"},"F002213":{"interactionID":"1293073870269579354","answers":["TEUCER"],"genus":"myth","question":"What son of Scamander was a king of the Troad?"},"F001014":{"interactionID":"1293073893724131368","answers":["ODYSSEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who travelled with Diomedes to fetch Achilles from Scyros?"},"F000936":{"interactionID":"1293073918545891369","answers":["LAOMEDON'S IMMORTAL HORSES"],"genus":"myth","question":"What payment did Heracles demand of Laomedon for saving Hesione?"},"F001790":{"interactionID":"1293076529760305182","answers":["AMYTHAON"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Melampus and Bias?"},"F001114":{"interactionID":"1293076613034151966","answers":["ILIAD"],"genus":"myth","question":"What poem is often described as 'the wrath of Achilles'?"},"F002340":{"interactionID":"1348449634980204575","answers":["PENELOPE"],"genus":"myth","question":"Agenor, Leodes, Amphimedon, Eurymachus, and Antinous were all suitors of what Ithacan queen?"},"F000964":{"interactionID":"1293076958275436605","answers":["EETION"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Andromache?"},"F001103":{"interactionID":"1293938428110573589","answers":["HERACLES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Telephus, wounded by Achilles?"},"F000325":{"interactionID":"1293077143785574472","answers":["SENECA THE YOUNGER"],"genus":"myth","question":"What Roman playwright wrote a tragedy called Phaedra?"},"F001052":{"interactionID":"1293077357661261906","answers":["ZEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who rejected Thetis upon learning her son would be greater than his father?"},"F000428":{"interactionID":"1385694414646677645","answers":["PLEIADES"],"genus":"myth","question":"To what group did Maia belong?"},"F000196":{"interactionID":"1293077476213260348","answers":["MYRRHA"],"genus":"myth","question":"What daughter of Cinyras fell desperately in love with her own father?"},"F000631":{"interactionID":"1293077555271831585","answers":["ARES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Whom did Cadmus have to serve after killing a serpent?"},"F002209":{"interactionID":"1293077566336532530","answers":["ISIS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who turned Iphis into a boy the day before her wedding to Ianthe?"},"F000303":{"interactionID":"1293077578956931123","answers":["ORION"],"genus":"myth","question":"What giant pursued the Pleiades in life and afterwards as a constellation?"},"F000941":{"interactionID":"1293077589052755979","answers":["HERACLES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who killed Laomedon?"},"F002001":{"interactionID":"1293077595499397161","answers":["ACHILLES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the son of Peleus and Thetis?"},"F002143":{"interactionID":"1293077603531358279","answers":["ARTEMIS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who killed Laodamia, daughter of Bellerophon?"},"F001124":{"interactionID":"1293077611488219169","answers":["SARPEDON"],"genus":"myth","question":"What son of Zeus is killed by Patroclus?"},"P000133":{"interactionID":"1313893974028587059","answers":["(SCILICET) ACTUALLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *sc.*?"},"LFIFTH003953":{"interactionID":"1293083000636178515","answers":["memoramus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *memoro* (to remind of, to mention)?"},"L1002894":{"interactionID":"1293212485582717009","answers":["virginem"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative singular** of *virgo, virginis* (maiden, virgin)?"},"L1004490":{"interactionID":"1293212430763294741","answers":["diebus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *dies, diei* (day)?"},"L1012056":{"interactionID":"1293212632324505671","answers":["dignant"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *dignor* (to deem worthy)?"},"L1002119":{"interactionID":"1293260931245281360","answers":["capillorum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural** of *capillus, capilli* (hair)?"},"L1008844":{"interactionID":"1293261030176329760","answers":["offeret"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future active indicative** of *offero* (to bring before, offer, show)?"},"L1012251":{"interactionID":"1293261848682172459","answers":["constat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *consto* (to stand firm, endure; to be evident)?"},"L1012764":{"interactionID":"1293261862749737082","answers":["accusaverant"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *accuso* (to accuse, blame)?"},"L1009259":{"interactionID":"1293262548543475712","answers":["deferetis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future active indicative** of *defero* (to bear or bring away; to report)?"},"L1017770":{"interactionID":"1293262559696261174","answers":["explebis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future active indicative** of *expleo* (to fill, complete)?"},"L1018406":{"interactionID":"1293262572111527936","answers":["deponis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *depono* (to put down)?"},"L1003361":{"interactionID":"1293262580395147366","answers":["pastori"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *pastor, pastoris* (shepherd)?"},"LFIFTH002105":{"interactionID":"1293266360591323186","answers":["ignota"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter nominative plural** of *ignotus* (unknown)?"},"LFIFTH002027":{"interactionID":"1293268289123913891","answers":["formosum"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter accusative singular** of *formosus* (beautiful, handsome)?"},"LFIFTH006488":{"interactionID":"1293268355263762492","answers":["caeditis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *caedo* (to cut, cut off, strike, kill)?"},"LFIFTH004527":{"interactionID":"1293323375359426701","answers":["studuimus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *studeo* (to be eager, to desire; to study)?"},"L1009803":{"interactionID":"1293324840953970810","answers":["turbat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *turbo* (to disturb, agitate)?"},"LFIFTH002888":{"interactionID":"1293326866505011260","answers":[" nostrum"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive singular** of *nos* (we, us, ourselves; emph. I, me, myself)?,nostri"},"LFIFTH001233":{"interactionID":"1293343629150261340","answers":["errores"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *error, erroris* (wandering; mistake)?"},"LFIFTH002026":{"interactionID":"1293343610539868253","answers":["formosam"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine accusative singular** of *formosus* (beautiful, handsome)?"},"LFIFTH003370":{"interactionID":"1293343591279755285","answers":["aufers"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *aufero* (to take off, remove)?"},"LFIFTH004415":{"interactionID":"1293344712110899251","answers":["accusavi"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *accuso* (to accuse, blame)?"},"LFIFTH001092":{"interactionID":"1293361136678338643","answers":["potestates"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *potestas, potestatis* (power, authority)?"},"LFIFTH003515":{"interactionID":"1293365566110699641","answers":["vacavimus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *vaco* (to be empty, vacant, free, idle)?"},"L1003193":{"interactionID":"1293369930879733832","answers":["scelere"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *scelus, sceleris* (crime)?"},"L1020661":{"interactionID":"1293369892761763904","answers":["pepereram"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *pario* (to bring forth, bear, produce)?"},"L1019983":{"interactionID":"1293370666761977856","answers":["addam"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future active indicative** of *addo* (to add)?"},"F000282":{"interactionID":"1293370996706770987","answers":["ARCADIA"],"genus":"myth","question":"Where did Callisto live?"},"F001711":{"interactionID":"1293371004684603422","answers":["LICHAS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who carried the poisoned robe of Deianira to Heracles?"},"LFIFTH001939":{"interactionID":"1293371411808915518","answers":["dubiae"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive singular** of *dubius* (uncertain)?"},"LFIFTH005685":{"interactionID":"1293371521103822932","answers":["loquis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *loquor* (to speak, talk, say)?"},"LFIFTH004442":{"interactionID":"1293432014040727572","answers":["viderunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *video* (to see)?"},"LFIFTH005292":{"interactionID":"1293431995069759530","answers":["requisivisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *requiro* (to ask, demand, inquire)?"},"LFIFTH006454":{"interactionID":"1293431975092158464","answers":["carpimus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *carpo* (to pick, pluck, crop)?"},"LFIFTH002036":{"interactionID":"1293437275115360288","answers":["frigidi"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter genitive singular** of *frigidus* (cold)?"},"LFIFTH001579":{"interactionID":"1293437292375179294","answers":["aequae"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive singular** of *aequus* (plain, favourable, fair)?"},"P000203":{"interactionID":"1339065078028308645","answers":["A CLEAN SLATE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *tabula rasa*?"},"LHALF011658":{"interactionID":"1293438007365468222","answers":["moriebatis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *morior* (to die)?"},"LHALF001377":{"interactionID":"1293438125716144199","answers":["damno"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *damnum, damni* (damage, loss)?"},"F001762":{"interactionID":"1293438655612063776","answers":["PHYXIUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What epithet was applied to Zeus as the god of escape?"},"F001003":{"interactionID":"1293438672737140758","answers":["WHITE HORSES"],"genus":"myth","question":"What possession of Rhesus became a prize of Odysseus and Diomedes?"},"F000197":{"interactionID":"1293438754823995482","answers":["MYRRH"],"genus":"myth","question":"Into what kind of tree was Myrrha transformed to escape the wrath of her father Cinyras?"},"F000290":{"interactionID":"1293438776827183115","answers":["ZEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who prevented Arcas from killing his mother, the bear, while hunting?"},"F001465":{"interactionID":"1293803639600709653","answers":["PTERELAUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What king of the Teleboans fought Electryon of Mycenae?"},"F000758":{"interactionID":"1293438808301502474","answers":["EVADNE"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the wife of Capaneus?"},"F001487":{"interactionID":"1293438820498538517","answers":["LICYMNIUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What son of Electryon and Anaxo was the brother of Alcmena?"},"F001176":{"interactionID":"1293438827452432445","answers":["DEMODOCUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What bard sings of Troy in the Odyssey?"},"LHALF002936":{"interactionID":"1293664474347081819","answers":["habitus"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *habitus, habitus* (appearance, dress)?"},"LHALF006453":{"interactionID":"1293718040206381096","answers":["turbavit"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *turbo* (to disturb, agitate)?"},"LHALF006068":{"interactionID":"1293718716575387678","answers":["interfuit"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *intersum* (to be between; to differ; to take part in)?"},"LHALF011162":{"interactionID":"1293723584488804454","answers":["bibi"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *bibo* (to drink)?"},"P000206":{"interactionID":"1309750222611812382","answers":["A CONSTANT COMPANION (GO WITH ME)"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *vade mecum*?"},"P000120":{"interactionID":"1308810920083980359","answers":["(FOLIO VERSO) ON THE LEFT HAND PAGE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *f.v.*?"},"P000118":{"interactionID":"1308815185951330435","answers":["(FLORUIT) PERIOD OF TIME DURING WHICH A PERSON OR THING FLOURISHED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *fl.*?"},"P000135":{"interactionID":"1313763703128199250","answers":["(SINE GRATIA) WITHOUT EXAMPLE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *s.g.*?"},"P000122":{"interactionID":"1355177145890111678","answers":["(IBIDEM) IN THE SAME PLACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *ibid.*?"},"P000117":{"interactionID":"1294498817051459604","answers":["(FOLIIS) ON THE [FOLLOWING] PAGES"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *ff.*?"},"P000094":{"interactionID":"1313762284857856040","answers":["(OCULUS DEXTER) RIGHT EYE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *o.d.*?"},"P000148":{"interactionID":"1339065101117952031","answers":["ON THE RIGHT"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *a dextra*?"},"P000009":{"interactionID":"1308687122789564426","answers":["DEUS NOBIS FIDUCIA (\"GOD IS OUR TRUST\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *George Washington University*?"},"P000176":{"interactionID":"1315530308447375441","answers":["IN THE MIDDLE OF THINGS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *in medias res*?"},"P000236":{"interactionID":"1339056133846859806","answers":["ALL THAT WORK AND NOTHING TO SHOW FOR IT"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **parturient montes, nasceture ridiculus mus**."},"P000180":{"interactionID":"1341082631378440322","answers":["A SLIP OF THE TONGUE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *lapsus linguae*?"},"P000175":{"interactionID":"1339065398989033593","answers":["IN THE PLACE OF A PARENT"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *in loco parentis*?"},"P000102":{"interactionID":"1294855485375254629","answers":["(SEMEL IN DIE) ONCE A DAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *s.i.d.*?"},"P000182":{"interactionID":"1308810540944199732","answers":["WITH THE NECESSARY CHANGES HAVING BEEN MADE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *mutatis mutandis*?"},"F000613":{"interactionID":"1293800587330322493","answers":["THEBES"],"genus":"myth","question":"What was the leading city of Boeotia?"},"F001376":{"interactionID":"1293800599862902856","answers":["IO"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the sister of Phoroneus?"},"F000864":{"interactionID":"1293800664291475486","answers":["ATHENA"],"genus":"myth","question":"What goddess appears to help expedite Orestes and Iphigenia's escape from Tauris?"},"F002308":{"interactionID":"1293801302668738652","answers":["LABYRINTH"],"genus":"myth","question":"The inhabitants of Delos, commemorating the visit of Theseus danced in intricate patterns in order to imitate the windings of what Cretan structure?"},"F001441":{"interactionID":"1295978425290592266","answers":["ARGUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was sent to guard Io?"},"F001266":{"interactionID":"1293802362636603464","answers":["MARON"],"genus":"myth","question":"What priest of Apollo was spared in Odysseus' attack of Ismarus?"},"F001058":{"interactionID":"1293802410581688360","answers":["ACHILLES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was fated to live long and die ingloriously, or die young and gloriously?"},"F001996":{"interactionID":"1293802430831661077","answers":["ACASTUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who hid the sword of Peleus on Mt. Pelion?"},"F000346":{"interactionID":"1293802455880044545","answers":["MT. PARNASSUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"On the slopes of what mountain was the Delphic sanctuary?"},"F000781":{"interactionID":"1293802462557507654","answers":["TIRESIAS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Whom did Jupiter and Juno consult to find out whether women or men had more fun?"},"F000309":{"interactionID":"1293802602844127273","answers":["SISTERS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What was the relationship of Asterie to Leto?"},"P000091":{"interactionID":"1294467033634705490","answers":["(BIS IN DIE) TWICE A DAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *b.i.d.*?"},"P000116":{"interactionID":"1313761800856014910","answers":["(FIDEI DEFENSOR) DEFENDER OF THE FAITH (A TITLE OF THE BRITISH MONARCHS)"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *F.D.*?"},"F000080":{"interactionID":"1293802912861917245","answers":["PONTUS AND GE"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who were the parents of Charybdis?"},"F001920":{"interactionID":"1293802921380544523","answers":["3","THREE"],"genus":"myth","question":"How many times did Talus walk around Crete each day?"},"F000940":{"interactionID":"1293938422594928711","answers":["TEUCER"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the child of Hesione and Laomedon?"},"F001163":{"interactionID":"1293803389192503296","answers":["ACHILLES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Whose ghost appears to the Greeks after Troy's fall to demand sacrifice?"},"F000345":{"interactionID":"1293803401573830733","answers":["DELPHINIUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What epithet of Apollo associates him with dolphins?"},"F001242":{"interactionID":"1293803412156059698","answers":["MEDA"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the wife of Idomeneus?"},"F001268":{"interactionID":"1293803419987083326","answers":["LAND OF THE LOTUS-EATERS"],"genus":"myth","question":"To whose land did Odysseus go after the Cicones?"},"F002061":{"interactionID":"1293803427578777640","answers":["TROPHONIUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the brother of Agamedes?"},"F000173":{"interactionID":"1293803649205796954","answers":["APHRODITE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What deity did the city of Paphos honor above all others?"},"F000662":{"interactionID":"1293805927211991040","answers":["THEBE"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the wife of Zethus?"},"F001121":{"interactionID":"1293805935709519946","answers":["THROWN FROM WALLS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What happened to Astyanax when Troy was sacked?"},"LHALF005385":{"interactionID":"1293806004739506196","answers":["silvestris"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive singular** of *silvester* (belonging to a forest, woody)?"},"LHALF003629":{"interactionID":"1293806034426794044","answers":["commodi"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter genitive singular** of *commodus* (proper, suitable)?"},"LHALF005421":{"interactionID":"1293806196666531870","answers":["pedestres"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine accusative plural** of *pedester* (on foot, pedestrian)?"},"LHALF002854":{"interactionID":"1293806389554053181","answers":["magistratui"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *magistratus, magistratus* (magistracy)?"},"LHALF005689":{"interactionID":"1293806411578343424","answers":["quodquam"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter accusative singular** of *quisquam* (any one, any thing)?"},"LHALF004913":{"interactionID":"1293806425860083764","answers":["commune"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter accusative singular** of *communis* (common, public)?"},"LHALF004491":{"interactionID":"1293806624217239552","answers":["pleno"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine dative singular** of *plenus* (full)?"},"F002182":{"interactionID":"1293807277958107157","answers":["OVID"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who wrote the Heroides?"},"F002124":{"interactionID":"1293807296136347742","answers":["ROLL BOULDER UPHILL"],"genus":"myth","question":"What was Sisyphus' punishment for telling on Zeus?"},"F001066":{"interactionID":"1293807650827407412","answers":["TRUMPET BLAST"],"genus":"myth","question":"What led Achilles to take off his disguise as a girl and put on armor?"},"F001076":{"interactionID":"1293807662537900062","answers":["AGAMEMNON KILLED SACRED STAG"],"genus":"myth","question":"Why did Artemis cause unfavorable winds for the Greeks at Aulis?"},"F001347":{"interactionID":"1293807669899038832","answers":["PENELOPE"],"genus":"myth","question":"Whom does Homer describe as \"periphron\"?"},"F001379":{"interactionID":"1293807696658825290","answers":["BELUS AND AGENOR"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who were the two sons of Libya?"},"F002301":{"interactionID":"1293807732771782748","answers":["ARGUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What son of Arestor built the ship which allowed Jason to sail to Colchis?"},"F001743":{"interactionID":"1293807740514209876","answers":["BLACK SEA"],"genus":"myth","question":"What is the Euxine Sea now called?"},"F001045":{"interactionID":"1293807746260406375","answers":["ODYSSEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who vengefully contrived the death of Palamedes?"},"F000416":{"interactionID":"1293807755777540096","answers":["DONKEY EARS"],"genus":"myth","question":"How did Apollo punish Midas for challenging his victory?"},"F001111":{"interactionID":"1293807890066571399","answers":["CHRYSEIS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What priestess of Apollo was originally awarded to Agamemnon?"},"F001366":{"interactionID":"1293807901000859648","answers":["INACHUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What river was the father of Phoroneus?"},"F001904":{"interactionID":"1293807996551430174","answers":["OVID"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who wrote the Metamorphoses?"},"F001090":{"interactionID":"1293808004327538688","answers":["PHILOCTETES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who first guided the Greek fleet to the island of Chryse?"},"F000636":{"interactionID":"1293808010455552054","answers":["ROBE"],"genus":"myth","question":"Besides a necklace, what other famous gift did Harmonia receive?"},"F002231":{"interactionID":"1293808045134184487","answers":["BABYLON"],"genus":"myth","question":"In what city did Pyramus and Thisbe live?"},"F000210":{"interactionID":"1293937711903801424","answers":["CYBELE"],"genus":"myth","question":"From whose severed organ had the almond tree grown?"},"F001410":{"interactionID":"1293938166486798378","answers":["CHRYSAOR"],"genus":"myth","question":"What creatures name meant \"he of the golden sword\"?"},"F001997":{"interactionID":"1293938182626349176","answers":["CHIRON"],"genus":"myth","question":"What centaur protected Peleus when his sword was hidden?"},"F001146":{"interactionID":"1293938371021766669","answers":["PENTHESILEA"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who led the Amazons at Troy?"},"F000740":{"interactionID":"1293938387677483069","answers":["MENOECEUS II"],"genus":"myth","question":"Which of the Spartoi sacrificed himself to save Thebes?"},"F002008":{"interactionID":"1293938393591316590","answers":["LUCIFER"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the Roman equivalent of Eosphoros?"},"F000900":{"interactionID":"1293938411496800317","answers":["APHAREUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Idas and Lynceus?"},"F000677":{"interactionID":"1293938418564337664","answers":["EURYDICE (DIFFERENT FROM OPRHEUS')"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the wife of Creon?"},"F000081":{"interactionID":"1293938486692413470","answers":["ZEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who cast Charybdis into the sea with a thunderbolt?"},"A000344":{"interactionID":"1293945056641810533","answers":["god"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What does the Greek word **theos (θεος)** mean?"},"LHALF011567":{"interactionID":"1293950470183714948","answers":["perficitis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *perficio* (to achieve, complete, accomplish)?"},"LFIFTH000734":{"interactionID":"1293955400902770729","answers":["aevo"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *aevum, aevi* (age, generation, period)?"},"LFIFTH002801":{"interactionID":"1293955462613700670","answers":["utile"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter accusative singular** of *utilis* (useful)?"},"LFIFTH006435":{"interactionID":"1293958302107041832","answers":["cessi"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *cedo* (to move; to happen, result)?"},"LHALF001645":{"interactionID":"1293983196937064498","answers":["legem"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative singular** of *lex, legis* (law)?"},"LHALF005284":{"interactionID":"1293983226536263894","answers":["utile"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter accusative singular** of *utilis* (useful)?"},"LHALF011234":{"interactionID":"1293983161646186648","answers":["alunt"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *alo* (to feed, nourish)?"},"LHALF000472":{"interactionID":"1293983360665784512","answers":["iuventas"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *iuventa, iuventae* (youth)?"},"LHALF000616":{"interactionID":"1293993544687681648","answers":["aulam"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative singular** of *aula, aulae* (hall, palace)?"},"LHALF002979":{"interactionID":"1293993506867642420","answers":["aestibus"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *aestus, aestus* (agitation, heat, tide)?"},"LHALF009820":{"interactionID":"1293993525884620873","answers":["metuebant"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *metuo* (to fear, to be afraid of)?"},"LFIFTH005802":{"interactionID":"1293993794718666824","answers":["imponitis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *impono* (to lay upon, impose)?"},"LFIFTH003077":{"interactionID":"1294002062451015852","answers":["neutrius"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine genitive singular** of *neuter* (neither of two)?"},"LFIFTH003678":{"interactionID":"1294002040611279010","answers":["pugnavisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *pugno* (to fight)?"},"LFIFTH006845":{"interactionID":"1294002014358999091","answers":["ingrediunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *ingredior* (to go into, to enter)?"},"LFIFTH004536":{"interactionID":"1294014419147423905","answers":["silet"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *sileo* (to keep silent, to be quiet)?"},"LFIFTH001173":{"interactionID":"1294018777620549735","answers":["montes"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *mons, montis* (mountain)?"},"LFIFTH002279":{"interactionID":"1294022431005999205","answers":["nimium"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter accusative singular** of *nimius* (excessive)?"},"LFIFTH002339":{"interactionID":"1294022914844131379","answers":["pium"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter accusative singular** of *pius* (dutiful, pious, honest)?"},"LHALF000627":{"interactionID":"1294056699979759726","answers":["animae"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *anima, animae* (breeze, breath, soul)?"},"LHALF001083":{"interactionID":"1294056682011234420","answers":["otio"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *otium, otii* (leisure time)?"},"LHALF006789":{"interactionID":"1294056726202683392","answers":["potavistis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *poto* (to drink)?"},"LHALF009007":{"interactionID":"1294057378207236187","answers":["tetigi"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *tango* (to touch)?"},"LHALF011262":{"interactionID":"1294057411912536125","answers":["egistis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *ago* (to lead, to drive, to do)?"},"LHALF011425":{"interactionID":"1294057418065576057","answers":["sufficiebamus"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *sufficio* (to be sufficient)?"},"LHALF005522":{"interactionID":"1294057721133273109","answers":["eae"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine nominative plural** of *is* (he, she, it; this, that)?"},"LHALF011956":{"interactionID":"1294057913668862024","answers":["accipimus"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *accipio* (to receive)?"},"P000129":{"interactionID":"1339065095212503111","answers":["(PASSIM) EVERYWHERE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *pass.*?"},"P000123":{"interactionID":"1339064391127269419","answers":["(INFRA DIGNITATEM) BENEATH ONE'S DIGNITY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *Infra. dig.*?"},"P000002":{"interactionID":"1355299725925945395","answers":["NIL SINE MAGNO LABORE. (\"NOTHING WITHOUT GREAT EFFORT.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Brooklyn College*?"},"P000181":{"interactionID":"1295943162212122636","answers":["A METHOD OF WORKING"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *modus operandi*?"},"P000005":{"interactionID":"1313764455586205726","answers":["RESPICE, ADSPICE, PROSPICE. (\"LOOK BACK, LOOK TO THE PRESENT, LOOK TO THE FUTURE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *City College of NY*?"},"F000882":{"interactionID":"1294097835100344410","answers":["CILISSA"],"genus":"myth","question":"What nurse of Orestes safely secured his escape after Agamemnon's murder?"},"F002202":{"interactionID":"1294097879270428693","answers":["IPHIS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who hanged himself in sorrow at the door of Anaxarete?"},"F002337":{"interactionID":"1294098101321072750","answers":["EUMAEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What Ithacan swineherd remained faithful to Odysseus?"},"F002114":{"interactionID":"1294098251292868731","answers":["HERMES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Autolycus?"},"F001252":{"interactionID":"1294099947058233364","answers":["ANDROMACHE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What Trojan widow accompanied Neoptolemus home from Troy?"},"F001561":{"interactionID":"1294099965479747614","answers":["NETS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What did Heracles use to catch the Erymanthian Boar?"},"A000272":{"interactionID":"1294118181559865384","answers":["demos (δημος), the people"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **epidemic**?"},"A000612":{"interactionID":"1294118215236190299","answers":["phagein (φαγειν), to eat"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **esophagus**?"},"LFIFTH002977":{"interactionID":"1294128392697937920","answers":["quo"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter ablative singular** of *qui* (who, which, what; who? which? what?)?"},"LHALF009108":{"interactionID":"1294156484325937163","answers":["serebant"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *sero* (to sow, plant)?"},"LHALF006863":{"interactionID":"1294157105594499156","answers":["parant"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *paro* (to prepare, provide)?"},"LHALF009402":{"interactionID":"1294157218832322560","answers":["proposuerunt"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *propono* (to put forth, declare, propose)?"},"LHALF008019":{"interactionID":"1294157431785525248","answers":["sustinuit"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *sustineo* (to support, sustain)?"},"LHALF007991":{"interactionID":"1294157632604733452","answers":["tacemus"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *taceo* (to be silent)?"},"LHALF007830":{"interactionID":"1294157650979979274","answers":["amaverunt"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *amo* (to love)?"},"LHALF006807":{"interactionID":"1294157659234107403","answers":["postulaverunt"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *postulo* (to ask, demand, summon)?"},"LHALF009389":{"interactionID":"1294157843804459009","answers":["proponitis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *propono* (to put forth, declare, propose)?"},"LHALF011255":{"interactionID":"1294157857503318157","answers":["agebamus"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *ago* (to lead, to drive, to do)?"},"LHALF010241":{"interactionID":"1294157878642475088","answers":["favit"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *faveo* (to be favorable or inclined towards)?"},"LHALF009806":{"interactionID":"1294157892118908978","answers":["misit"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *mitto* (to send, throw)?"},"LHALF009903":{"interactionID":"1294157932623171584","answers":["laesimus"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *laedo* (to hurt, wound, annoy)?"},"LHALF006321":{"interactionID":"1294157948905459743","answers":["vulgavi"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *vulgo* (to spread, to make known)?"},"LHALF011273":{"interactionID":"1294158051590275182","answers":["agnoscebatis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *agnosco* (to recognize; to admit)?"},"LHALF007793":{"interactionID":"1294158108154921040","answers":["arbitrabat"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *arbitror* (to believe, to make a decision)?"},"LHALF011506":{"interactionID":"1294158117713612800","answers":["rapiebant"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *rapio* (to seize, rob, snatch)?"},"LHALF008871":{"interactionID":"1294158180393160766","answers":["ussi"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *uro* (to burn)?"},"LHALF007378":{"interactionID":"1294158344948289536","answers":["firmaverunt"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *firmo* (to make firm, strengthen fortify)?"},"LHALF008703":{"interactionID":"1294158716777795634","answers":["censebat"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *censeo* (to assess, estimate; to propose, vote)?"},"LHALF009985":{"interactionID":"1294158765481918475","answers":["instruebas"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *instruo* (to set in order, equip; to teach, instruct)?"},"LHALF006235":{"interactionID":"1294158773669068892","answers":["afferebant"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *affero* (to bring to; to allege, assert)?"},"LHALF007573":{"interactionID":"1294158781915074571","answers":["damnavit"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *damno* (to condemn)?"},"LHALF008128":{"interactionID":"1294158869689536562","answers":["respondebatis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *respondeo* (to answer)?"},"LHALF011071":{"interactionID":"1294158879667654716","answers":["carpebam"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *carpo* (to pick, pluck, crop)?"},"LHALF006575":{"interactionID":"1294158887938691165","answers":["significaverunt"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *significo* (to show; to mean, signify)?"},"LHALF006630":{"interactionID":"1294159002418020382","answers":["revocatis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *revoco* (to call back)?"},"LHALF010256":{"interactionID":"1294159011792293939","answers":["fefelli"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *fallo* (to deceive, cheat, disappoint)?"},"LHALF010402":{"interactionID":"1294159023507247135","answers":["ducunt"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *duco* (to lead, conduct)?"},"LHALF011225":{"interactionID":"1294159065747951696","answers":["amisisti"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *amitto* (to lose)?"},"LHALF007296":{"interactionID":"1294159074279030815","answers":["imperabat"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *impero* (to command, order)?"},"LHALF006307":{"interactionID":"1294159657748922474","answers":["abivimus"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *abeo* (to go away, depart)?"},"LHALF008896":{"interactionID":"1294159774069559389","answers":["trahimus"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *traho* (to draw, drag)?"},"LHALF006262":{"interactionID":"1294159787784667168","answers":["aditis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *adeo* (to go to, approach)?"},"LHALF006911":{"interactionID":"1294160015149498390","answers":["optat"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *opto* (to choose, to wish)?"},"LHALF007953":{"interactionID":"1294160030475485194","answers":["torsistis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *torqueo* (to twist, turn, torture)?"},"LHALF008456":{"interactionID":"1294160121521377382","answers":["iussimus"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *iubeo* (to command, order)?"},"LHALF011516":{"interactionID":"1294160159387422771","answers":["proficitis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *proficio* (to go on, to make progress)?"},"LHALF008634":{"interactionID":"1294160324835934240","answers":["egebas"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *egeo* (to need, lack)?"},"LHALF005094":{"interactionID":"1294160333870596137","answers":["ingentes"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *ingens* (huge)?"},"A000705":{"interactionID":"1294345845659009054","answers":["water... hydor (ὑδωρ)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **formaldehyde**?"},"LHALF008186":{"interactionID":"1294346822499700838","answers":["praebuerunt"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *praebeo* (to give, offer)?"},"LHALF007795":{"interactionID":"1294347413414346845","answers":["arbitrabatis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *arbitror* (to believe, to make a decision)?"},"LHALF011880":{"interactionID":"1294347449971904572","answers":["cupivi"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *cupio* (to desire, to wish)?"},"LHALF008594":{"interactionID":"1294347849907179541","answers":["flevi"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *fleo* (to weep, cry)?"},"LHALF001261":{"interactionID":"1294348003364306965","answers":["incendia"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *incendium, incendii* (fire)?"},"LHALF006469":{"interactionID":"1294348365282414653","answers":["temptavisti"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *tempto* (to handle, touch; to attempt)?"},"A000158":{"interactionID":"1294349672529399868","answers":["ballo (βαλλω), throw"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **parable**?"},"A000210":{"interactionID":"1294352939552477185","answers":["homos (ὁμος), one and the same, like","genos (γενος), race, offspring, kind"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **homogeneous**?"},"A000198":{"interactionID":"1313341989881647154","answers":["monos (μονος), alone","gamos (γαμος), wedding, marriage"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **monogamous**?"},"A000177":{"interactionID":"1294376113136734401","answers":["biblos (βιβλος)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What Greek word means **book**?"},"A000473":{"interactionID":"1294376405710405652","answers":["little, small... micros (μικρος)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **microcosm**?"},"A000268":{"interactionID":"1294400731633156096","answers":["grapho (γραφω), to draw, write, describe"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **telegram**?"},"A000423":{"interactionID":"1294400773253234820","answers":["krypto (κρυπτω)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What Greek word means **to hide**?"},"A000626":{"interactionID":"1294427400376946780","answers":["micros (μικρος), little, small","skopeo (σκοπεω), behold, examine, inspect, consider, see"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **microscope**?"},"LHALF011596":{"interactionID":"1294451718263930911","answers":["percussistis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *percutio* (to strike; to kill)?"},"P000073":{"interactionID":"1308687111704018977","answers":["SPERAMUS MELIORA, RESURGET CINERIBUS (\"WE HOPE FOR BETTER THINGS, IT WILL RISE FROM THE ASHES\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Detroit*?"},"A000457":{"interactionID":"1294465624898273280","answers":["word, speech, reasoning... logos (λογος)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **analogy**?"},"LHALF003872":{"interactionID":"1294468028146258002","answers":["fera"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter nominative plural** of *ferus* (wild)?"},"LHALF010959":{"interactionID":"1294522659861827647","answers":["cognoscit"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *cognosco* (to examine, to know)?"},"LFIFTH001601":{"interactionID":"1294743905312706641","answers":["alba"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter nominative plural** of *albus* (white)?"},"LFIFTH003917":{"interactionID":"1294743876589850645","answers":["negavistis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *nego* (to say no, to deny)?"},"LFIFTH006108":{"interactionID":"1294743930537246740","answers":["desiit"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *desino* (to cease, desist)?"},"LFIFTH007167":{"interactionID":"1294750175054532759","answers":["feritis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *ferio* (to strike; to kill)?"},"LHALF001904":{"interactionID":"1294791771649474612","answers":["iudici"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *iudex, iudicis* (judge)?"},"LHALF001243":{"interactionID":"1294810054888919130","answers":["iocos"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *iocus, ioci* (joke)?"},"LHALF001250":{"interactionID":"1294811886017056845","answers":["initiis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *initium, initii* (beginning)?"},"LFIFTH000086":{"interactionID":"1294835798230695987","answers":["fortunae"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *fortuna, fortunae* (luck)?"},"LHALF006434":{"interactionID":"1294855060878266430","answers":["vacavi"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *vaco* (to be empty, vacant, free, idle)?"},"LHALF012018":{"interactionID":"1294855133829660732","answers":["servivit"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *servio* (to be a servant or slave, to serve)?"},"P000064":{"interactionID":"1355177418930917437","answers":["JOANNES EST NOMAN EIUS (\"JOHN IS HIS NAME.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Puerto Rico*?"},"LHALF008454":{"interactionID":"1295125427152748564","answers":["iussisti"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *iubeo* (to command, order)?"},"LFIFTH000238":{"interactionID":"1295130252850499585","answers":["invidia"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *invidia, invidiae* (envy, hostility)?"},"LFIFTH002773":{"interactionID":"1295130275206004776","answers":["simplices"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *simplex* (simple, ingenuous)?"},"LFIFTH004514":{"interactionID":"1295130294113796127","answers":["sustinuisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *sustineo* (to support, sustain)?"},"LFIFTH001050":{"interactionID":"1295130636641767525","answers":["solitudines"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *solitudo, solitudinis* (loneliness, lonely place)?"},"LHALF011513":{"interactionID":"1295139372752044133","answers":["proficis"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *proficio* (to go on, to make progress)?"},"LFIFTH000097":{"interactionID":"1295153282947481691","answers":["magistra"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *magistra, magistrae* (instructress)?"},"LFIFTH001094":{"interactionID":"1295159228415348757","answers":["ponte"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *pons, pontis* (bridge)?"},"LHALF010051":{"interactionID":"1295174307974221924","answers":["imponunt"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *impono* (to lay upon, impose)?"},"LHALF007629":{"interactionID":"1295174359622877284","answers":["conat"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *conor* (to attempt, try)?"},"LHALF010474":{"interactionID":"1295174372822351903","answers":["dimittebamus"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *dimitto* (to send out, dismiss)?"},"A000179":{"interactionID":"1313341966250938378","answers":["book... biblos (βιβλος)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **Bible**?"},"A000718":{"interactionID":"1295196524782813212","answers":["cheir (χειρ), hand"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **surgery**?"},"F001577":{"interactionID":"1295217609532248125","answers":["PHYLEUS (AUGEAS' SON)"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who did Heracles put on the throne of Elis to replace king Augeas?"},"G002851":{"interactionID":"1295219703588851752","answers":["old"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *vetus veteris*."},"G000908":{"interactionID":"1295219798896148480","answers":["facies faciei f."],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find all 3 principal parts of the noun that matches the definition *form, appearance*. Do not include macrons."},"G002823":{"interactionID":"1295219879259148300","answers":["ADV"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the part of speech/Latin inflection category of the word *vere*.\n\nPlease use the following for your answer.\n**Adjective: 1st and 2nd Declension:** A12\n**Adjective: 3rd Declension:** A3\n**Adjective: Indeclinable:** AI\n**Adjective: Numeral:** AN\n**Adverb:** ADV\n**Conjunction:** CONJ\n**Noun: 1st Declension:** N1\n**Noun: 2nd Declension:** N2\n**Noun: 3rd Declension:** N3\n**Noun: 4th Declension:** N4\n**Noun: 5th Declension:** N5\n**Noun: Indeclinable:** NI\n**Preposition:** PREP\n**Pronoun:** PRO\n**Verb: 1st Conjugation:** V1\n**Verb: 2nd Conjugation:** V2\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -io:** V3i\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -o:** V3\n**Verb: 4th Conjugation:** V4\n**Verb: Deponent:** VD\n**Verb: Impersonal:** VIP\n**Verb: Irregular:** VIRR"},"G000009":{"interactionID":"1295220356424142919","answers":["CONJ"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the part of speech/Latin inflection category of the word *ac*.\n\nPlease use the following for your answer.\n**Adjective: 1st and 2nd Declension:** A12\n**Adjective: 3rd Declension:** A3\n**Adjective: Indeclinable:** AI\n**Adjective: Numeral:** AN\n**Adverb:** ADV\n**Conjunction:** CONJ\n**Noun: 1st Declension:** N1\n**Noun: 2nd Declension:** N2\n**Noun: 3rd Declension:** N3\n**Noun: 4th Declension:** N4\n**Noun: 5th Declension:** N5\n**Noun: Indeclinable:** NI\n**Preposition:** PREP\n**Pronoun:** PRO\n**Verb: 1st Conjugation:** V1\n**Verb: 2nd Conjugation:** V2\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -io:** V3i\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -o:** V3\n**Verb: 4th Conjugation:** V4\n**Verb: Deponent:** VD\n**Verb: Impersonal:** VIP\n**Verb: Irregular:** VIRR"},"F000349":{"interactionID":"1295261446573391944","answers":["DORIC, IONIC, CORINTHIAN"],"genus":"myth","question":"What were the three major orders of Greek architecture?"},"F000682":{"interactionID":"1295570433885606012","answers":["CHRYSIPPUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What son of Pelops was kidnapped by Laius?"},"F000302":{"interactionID":"1295261489556619294","answers":["ATLAS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of the Pleiades?"},"F000040":{"interactionID":"1295263464297725954","answers":["LITYERSES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the son of Midas?"},"F000445":{"interactionID":"1295483752935329924","answers":["PETASUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What was a traveling hat called?"},"F001793":{"interactionID":"1295483733042008106","answers":["ACASTUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the son of Pelias?"},"F001055":{"interactionID":"1295483703723819029","answers":["STYX"],"genus":"myth","question":"Into what river did Thetis dip Achilles to make him immortal?"},"F002038":{"interactionID":"1295484301370069052","answers":["WORMS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who warned Melampus that his jail cell was about to cave in?"},"I003114":{"interactionID":"1295557749538557962","answers":["legioni"],"genus":"inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *legio, legionis* (army, legion)?"},"I021244":{"interactionID":"1295557702319214722","answers":["occupantis"],"genus":"inflection","question":"What is the **genitive singular masculine present participle** of *occupo* (to occupy, seize)?"},"I072883":{"interactionID":"1295557724398157894","answers":["deiecturum"],"genus":"inflection","question":"What is the **nominative singular neuter future participle** of *deicio* (to throw or cast down)?"},"LADV104598":{"interactionID":"1295560780540022880","answers":["additus sum"],"genus":"LADV_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect passive indicative** of *addo* (to add)?"},"F000400":{"interactionID":"1295570375786364999","answers":["MOIRAI (FATES)"],"genus":"myth","question":"Whom did Apollo convince with wine to allow Admetus to live?"},"F002279":{"interactionID":"1295570413631438988","answers":["MEGARA"],"genus":"myth","question":"What daughter of Creon did Heracles inadvertently kill in a fit of madness enduced by Hera?"},"F001013":{"interactionID":"1295571419815739402","answers":["ARES AND APHRODITE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What two deities were wounded by Diomedes?"},"F001455":{"interactionID":"1295622853219192852","answers":["DANAUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the uncle of Lynceus, husband of Hypermnestra?"},"F002042":{"interactionID":"1295625256521830482","answers":["10TH (CATTLE OF GERYON)"],"genus":"myth","question":"To which of Heracles' labor can Melampus adventure be likened?"},"LFIFTH000409":{"interactionID":"1295932872435175475","answers":["vitio"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *vitium, vitii* (fault, error, vice)?"},"LFIFTH001338":{"interactionID":"1295932931684040704","answers":["pisces"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *piscis, piscis* (fish)?"},"LFIFTH003598":{"interactionID":"1295932892001730570","answers":["significatis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *significo* (to show; to mean, signify)?"},"P000248":{"interactionID":"1295943320337387530","answers":["FOOLS LAUGH AT THE LATIN LANGUAGE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Rident stolidi verba Latina**."},"P000124":{"interactionID":"1339059005733081108","answers":["(LOCO CITATO) IN A PREVIOUSLY CITED PLACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *loc. cit.*?"},"LHALF010606":{"interactionID":"1295947477182185512","answers":["deducunt"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *deduco* (to lead away)?"},"P000240":{"interactionID":"1355296882158731405","answers":["A SOUND MIND IN A SOUND BODY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Mens sana in corpore sano**."},"LHALF006161":{"interactionID":"1295965969285386261","answers":["desunt"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *desum* (to be away, to be absent; to fail)?"},"LHALF010851":{"interactionID":"1295966350795079700","answers":["condebas"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *condo* (to found, establish)?"},"G001905":{"interactionID":"1377005175251795978","answers":["N1"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the part of speech/Latin inflection category of the word *pecunia pecuniae f.*.\n\nPlease use the following for your answer.\n**Adjective: 1st and 2nd Declension:** A12\n**Adjective: 3rd Declension:** A3\n**Adjective: Indeclinable:** AI\n**Adjective: Numeral:** AN\n**Adverb:** ADV\n**Conjunction:** CONJ\n**Noun: 1st Declension:** N1\n**Noun: 2nd Declension:** N2\n**Noun: 3rd Declension:** N3\n**Noun: 4th Declension:** N4\n**Noun: 5th Declension:** N5\n**Noun: Indeclinable:** NI\n**Preposition:** PREP\n**Pronoun:** PRO\n**Verb: 1st Conjugation:** V1\n**Verb: 2nd Conjugation:** V2\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -io:** V3i\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -o:** V3\n**Verb: 4th Conjugation:** V4\n**Verb: Deponent:** VD\n**Verb: Impersonal:** VIP\n**Verb: Irregular:** VIRR"},"LFIFTH002443":{"interactionID":"1295969584611987487","answers":["stultae"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive singular** of *stultus* (silly)?"},"LHALF005713":{"interactionID":"1295973807907143753","answers":["unoquoque"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter ablative singular** of *unusquisque* (every one)?"},"LHALF010774":{"interactionID":"1295973842623135805","answers":["consulimus"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *consulo* (to consider, advise, deliberate)?"},"LHALF011834":{"interactionID":"1295974054448070747","answers":["deiecerunt"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *deicio* (to throw or cast down)?"},"LHALF011360":{"interactionID":"1295977557900132362","answers":["accendi"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *accendo* (to kindle, set on fire; to incite)?"},"LFIFTH005551":{"interactionID":"1295977608470859798","answers":["pavimus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *pasco* (to pasture, feed, nourish)?"},"LFIFTH006697":{"interactionID":"1295977640733179906","answers":["subiecistis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *subicio* (to place under)?"},"LFIFTH000354":{"interactionID":"1295977671943258194","answers":["templa"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative plural** of *templum, templi* (temple)?"},"LFIFTH003782":{"interactionID":"1295978028350046219","answers":["peccavisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *pecco* (to commit a fault, to sin)?"},"C000268":{"interactionID":"1295978223766601759","answers":["lanista"],"genus":"culture_daily_life","question":"Find a Latin term that matches the following description: **trainer of gladiators**"},"T000266":{"interactionID":"1295978327584014367","answers":["CAESAR HAS NO AUTHORITY OVER THE GRAMMARIANS"],"genus":"translation","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Caesar non supra grammaticos*?"},"D000105":{"interactionID":"1295978498330071091","answers":["campus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *champion* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"L000535":{"interactionID":"1295978560510758943","answers":["SUETONIUS"],"genus":"literature","question":"What authorr's father fought on the losing side at the Battle of Bedriacum in 69 AD?"},"C000364":{"interactionID":"1295978921459978250","answers":["Salii Collini"],"genus":"culture_daily_life","question":"Find a Latin term that matches the following description: **dancing priests of Quirinus**"},"C000007":{"interactionID":"1295978987503222837","answers":["people who were related by marriage only"],"genus":"culture_daily_life","question":"Write a description for the Latin term **adfines**."},"C000053":{"interactionID":"1295979010194407485","answers":["ribbons which held six locks of carefully braided hair divided by a spear"],"genus":"culture_daily_life","question":"Write a description for the Latin term **vittae**."},"C000243":{"interactionID":"1295979016250982422","answers":["four tali all with different numbers"],"genus":"culture_daily_life","question":"Write a description for the Latin term **Vulture throw**."},"C000496":{"interactionID":"1295979025000435732","answers":["Publius"],"genus":"culture_daily_life","question":"What Roman praenomen has the abbreviation of **P**?"},"G000645":{"interactionID":"1295979065299435621","answers":["V3"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the part of speech/Latin inflection category of the word *decerno decernere decrevi decretum*.\n\nPlease use the following for your answer.\n**Adjective: 1st and 2nd Declension:** A12\n**Adjective: 3rd Declension:** A3\n**Adjective: Indeclinable:** AI\n**Adjective: Numeral:** AN\n**Adverb:** ADV\n**Conjunction:** CONJ\n**Noun: 1st Declension:** N1\n**Noun: 2nd Declension:** N2\n**Noun: 3rd Declension:** N3\n**Noun: 4th Declension:** N4\n**Noun: 5th Declension:** N5\n**Noun: Indeclinable:** NI\n**Preposition:** PREP\n**Pronoun:** PRO\n**Verb: 1st Conjugation:** V1\n**Verb: 2nd Conjugation:** V2\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -io:** V3i\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -o:** V3\n**Verb: 4th Conjugation:** V4\n**Verb: Deponent:** VD\n**Verb: Impersonal:** VIP\n**Verb: Irregular:** VIRR"},"G001237":{"interactionID":"1295979933553918042","answers":["bring upon, against","bellum inferre: make war on"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *infero inferre intuli illatum*."},"G002081":{"interactionID":"1295979989384302672","answers":["prior prius"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find all 2 principal parts of the adjective that matches the definition *earlier, preceding*. Do not include macrons."},"G000995":{"interactionID":"1295980131881324604","answers":["flos floris m."],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find all 3 principal parts of the noun that matches the definition *flower, bloom*. Do not include macrons."},"G000199":{"interactionID":"1295980155210043443","answers":["fit, suitable"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *aptus apta aptum*."},"G000532":{"interactionID":"1295980165041623093","answers":["agree","constat, it is established that (+ acc. and infin.)"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *consto constare constiti*."},"G002395":{"interactionID":"1295980182749970464","answers":["enough, sufficient, sufficiently"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *satis sat*."},"G002279":{"interactionID":"1295980204971528194","answers":["recipio recipere recepi receptum"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find all 4 principal parts of the verb that matches the definition *take back, receive; se recipere, betake oneself, go*. Do not include macrons."},"G000641":{"interactionID":"1295980252886994975","answers":["debeo debere debui debitum"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find all 4 principal parts of the verb that matches the definition *owe, be obliged*. Do not include macrons."},"G002905":{"interactionID":"1295980484546924574","answers":["any, anyone"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *ullus ulla ullum*."},"G000191":{"interactionID":"1295980503329013760","answers":["aperio aperire aperui apertum"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find all 4 principal parts of the verb that matches the definition *open*. Do not include macrons."},"G002464":{"interactionID":"1295980513278038098","answers":["save, watch over"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *servo servare*."},"G002713":{"interactionID":"1295980787199381514","answers":["third"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *tertius tertia tertium*."},"G000883":{"interactionID":"1295981298883493981","answers":["army"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *exercitus exercitus m.*."},"G000304":{"interactionID":"1295981322744893450","answers":["war"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *bellum belli n.*."},"G001102":{"interactionID":"1295981407755309067","answers":["glory, fame"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *gloria gloriae f.*."},"L1013602":{"interactionID":"1295982304715477002","answers":["obtinuimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *obtineo* (to hold, occupy, possess)?"},"LFIFTH005228":{"interactionID":"1296885627018547222","answers":["scripsimus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *scribo* (to write)?"},"LFIFTH002774":{"interactionID":"1296886886417039441","answers":["tenuis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine/feminine genitive singular** of *tenuis* (thin, fine, slender, weak)?"},"LHALF000797":{"interactionID":"1297374049432899656","answers":["viris"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *virus, viri* (poison)?"},"LFIFTH002201":{"interactionID":"1297381598983094314","answers":["laeta"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter nominative plural** of *laetus* (joyful)?"},"LFIFTH004136":{"interactionID":"1297381631283433603","answers":["existimaverunt"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *existimo* (to value, estimate, consider, think)?"},"LFIFTH006978":{"interactionID":"1297381571304886344","answers":["corripuisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *corripio* (to seize, snatch; to blame)?"},"D000085":{"interactionID":"1298517866131357766","answers":["calo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *nomenclature* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"LFIFTH002986":{"interactionID":"1298517885400121396","answers":["quo"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter ablative singular** of *quis* (who? which? what?; somebody)?"},"D000440":{"interactionID":"1298518606212239371","answers":["longus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *lunge* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"LHALF007048":{"interactionID":"1298802569422049301","answers":["negamus"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *nego* (to say no, to deny)?"},"D000327":{"interactionID":"1298884090296274985","answers":["frango"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *frail* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000168":{"interactionID":"1298884115571019776","answers":["clamo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *chiaroscuro* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000715":{"interactionID":"1298884066879340574","answers":["rota"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *rowel* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"LHALF001178":{"interactionID":"1298884930700574753","answers":["magistris"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *magister, magistri* (teacher, master)?"},"LHALF004189":{"interactionID":"1298884952318021713","answers":["iucundas"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine accusative plural** of *iucundus* (delightful)?"},"LFIFTH004837":{"interactionID":"1298898230595162183","answers":["horres"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *horreo* (to be frightened at)?"},"LFIFTH007045":{"interactionID":"1298898464419086417","answers":["venit"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *venio* (to come)?"},"LFIFTH002209":{"interactionID":"1299006549133496440","answers":["longa"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine ablative singular** of *longus* (long)?"},"LFIFTH005083":{"interactionID":"1299006491033862215","answers":["tradis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *trado* (to deliver, betray, report)?"},"LFIFTH005511":{"interactionID":"1299006527599804479","answers":["perdit"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *perdo* (to destroy, ruin; to lose)?"},"LFIFTH006773":{"interactionID":"1299006509732200508","answers":["perficitis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *perficio* (to achieve, complete, accomplish)?"},"LFIFTH003117":{"interactionID":"1299006936372613150","answers":["transivisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *transeo* (to go over or across)?"},"D000249":{"interactionID":"1299197360458694656","answers":["domus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *damsel* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"LFIFTH001843":{"interactionID":"1299197334911062048","answers":["clarae"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **feminine genitive singular** of *clarus* (clear, famous)?"},"A000031":{"interactionID":"1299516050710200347","answers":["to lead, bring... ago (αγω)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **strategic**?"},"LADV060001":{"interactionID":"1299540222064721992","answers":["coniuncturum"],"genus":"LADV_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative singular neuter future participle** of *coniungo* (to join)?"},"LADV065789":{"interactionID":"1299540150774136912","answers":["traiecerit"],"genus":"LADV_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *traicio* (to throw across, transport across, cross )?"},"LADV095488":{"interactionID":"1299540499849543790","answers":["pulsorum"],"genus":"LADV_inflection","question":"What is the **genitive plural masculine perfect participle** of *pello* (to push, expel)?"},"LFIFTH007134":{"interactionID":"1299572119532994583","answers":["munitis"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *munio* (to fortify, defend)?"},"D000350":{"interactionID":"1304678393903714325_7","answers":["glacies"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *glance* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000210":{"interactionID":"1299766554875138190","answers":["culina"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *kiln* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000579":{"interactionID":"1299944871246827632","answers":["pars"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *parcel* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000854":{"interactionID":"1299945391411691562","answers":["utor"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *utensil* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000573":{"interactionID":"1304678510610223125_2","answers":["pario"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *repertoire* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000782":{"interactionID":"1301030913244659795","answers":["sto"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *rest* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000798":{"interactionID":"1301030943993368638","answers":["taceo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *reticent* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"LHALF010951":{"interactionID":"1301045657158549564","answers":["cogebant"],"genus":"LHALF_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *cogo* (to urge, force, compel)?"},"LADV090292":{"interactionID":"1301255996496416818","answers":["fassuris"],"genus":"LADV_inflection","question":"What is the **dative plural masculine future participle** of *fateor* (to confess, acknowledge)?"},"LADV042858":{"interactionID":"1301256820576227399","answers":["restitueratis"],"genus":"LADV_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *restituo* (to give back, restore)?"},"D000620":{"interactionID":"1301261233491673088","answers":["plango"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *plaintiff* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000530":{"interactionID":"1301261288869073028","answers":["odi"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *annoy* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000653":{"interactionID":"1301261526203633716","answers":["premo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *print* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"F000570":{"interactionID":"1301305279740121088","answers":["HERMES"],"genus":"myth","question":"What god had the epithet Psychopompus?"},"F002195":{"interactionID":"1301305404998815744","answers":["CANACE"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the sister of Macareus, with whom he fell in love?"},"F001870":{"interactionID":"1301306462777249924","answers":["SNATCHERS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What does the name of the Harpies mean?"},"D000438":{"interactionID":"1301359354238206086","answers":["locus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *lieu* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000815":{"interactionID":"1301359335305252895","answers":["texo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *subtle* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000064":{"interactionID":"1301359800717934593","answers":["bulla"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *boil* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000060":{"interactionID":"1301363963107475456","answers":["bos"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *beef* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000623":{"interactionID":"1301364000121950208","answers":["planus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *plan* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000668":{"interactionID":"1301363943721406464","answers":["puto"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *count* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000513":{"interactionID":"1301369560246779974","answers":["noceo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *nuisance* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"L1002304":{"interactionID":"1301763223585816626","answers":["regioni"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **dative singular** of *regio, regionis* (region)?"},"L1003243":{"interactionID":"1301769969624940577","answers":["radicibus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *radix, radicis* (root)?"},"L1017330":{"interactionID":"1301957715756716052","answers":["imposuerunt"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural perfect active indicative** of *impono* (to lay upon, impose)?"},"L1011753":{"interactionID":"1301959108844589097","answers":["firmaverat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *firmo* (to make firm, strengthen fortify)?"},"A000229":{"interactionID":"1302062703937847327","answers":["gignosko (γιγνωσκω)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What Greek word means **to come to know, recognize**?"},"A000043":{"interactionID":"1302062743591063563","answers":["algos (αλγος)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What Greek word means **pain**?"},"D000378":{"interactionID":"1302066869980762143","answers":["iocus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *jewel* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"A000728":{"interactionID":"1302066881364234270","answers":["chronos (χρονος), time"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **crony**?"},"D000627":{"interactionID":"1313891688862846996","answers":["plecto"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *pleat* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"L1021517":{"interactionID":"1302299971223293964","answers":["senseritis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *sentio* (to perceive, notice, feel; to think)?"},"L1015895":{"interactionID":"1302302802382688266","answers":["querebatis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *queror* (to complain, lament)?"},"L1012349":{"interactionID":"1302337780399210666","answers":["comparabatis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *comparo* (to prepare, provide)?"},"L1012894":{"interactionID":"1302337817007099945","answers":["valuerimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *valeo* (to be strong, powerful, capable of)?"},"L1010409":{"interactionID":"1302337850838356039","answers":["probaverit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *probo* (to test, approve)?"},"D000662":{"interactionID":"1355361555385946163","answers":["pulvis"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *powder* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"A000574":{"interactionID":"1302442599516471336","answers":["every, entire, all"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What does the Greek word **pas (πας)** mean?"},"H001264":{"interactionID":"1302693101948895286","answers":["TRIED TO RESTORE PAGAN WORSHIP"],"genus":"history","question":"Why was Julian known as the \"apostate\"?"},"H000427":{"interactionID":"1302693546855501854","answers":["BLIND"],"genus":"history","question":"What does the cognomen \"Caecus\" mean?"},"LFIFTH000787":{"interactionID":"1302847699485327471","answers":["virtute"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *virtus, virtutis* (courage, virtue)?"},"LFIFTH004161":{"interactionID":"1302847798294872064","answers":["educamus"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *educo* (to bring up, educate)?"},"D000289":{"interactionID":"1303826834877579375","answers":["facio"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *feat* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"L1019512":{"interactionID":"1303827358125658112","answers":["carueramus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *careo* (to be without)?"},"H000229":{"interactionID":"1303910600295976990","answers":["ROMULUS & REMUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What infants were saved by a she-wolf when they were exposed in the wilderness by Amulius?"},"H001215":{"interactionID":"1303910641844748348","answers":["AURELIAN"],"genus":"history","question":"Who defeated Tetricus the ruler of the Gallic Empire?"},"H001171":{"interactionID":"1303920904987873330","answers":["238–244 AD"],"genus":"history","question":"What were the years of Gordian III's reign?"},"H001024":{"interactionID":"1303933839500116059","answers":["BEDRIACUM"],"genus":"history","question":"What is another name for the battle of Cremona?"},"L1021026":{"interactionID":"1303945634302394409","answers":["deiciebant"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *deicio* (to throw or cast down)?"},"L1000030":{"interactionID":"1303950462768255037","answers":["nauta"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *nauta, nautae* (sailor)?"},"D000765":{"interactionID":"1303976737079820328","answers":["sibilus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *persiflage* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000358":{"interactionID":"1304678393903714325_0","answers":["herba"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *arbor* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000793":{"interactionID":"1304678393903714325_2","answers":["sum"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *entity* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000357":{"interactionID":"1304678393903714325_3","answers":["habeo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *provender* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000792":{"interactionID":"1304678393903714325_5","answers":["suavis"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *suave* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000676":{"interactionID":"1304678393903714325_6","answers":["quattor"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *quarantine* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000606":{"interactionID":"1304678393903714325_8","answers":["pes"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *vamp* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000721":{"interactionID":"1304678393903714325_9","answers":["sacer"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *execration* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000803":{"interactionID":"1304678510610223125_3","answers":["tango"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *taste* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000451":{"interactionID":"1304678510610223125_4","answers":["maneo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *menial* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000691":{"interactionID":"1304678510610223125_5","answers":["rapio"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *usurp* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000575":{"interactionID":"1355362999560568923","answers":["paro"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *emperor* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000411":{"interactionID":"1304678510610223125_7","answers":["latus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *elate* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000245":{"interactionID":"1304678510610223125_8","answers":["do"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *traitor* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000621":{"interactionID":"1304678510610223125_9","answers":["planus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *explain* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"L1010652":{"interactionID":"1304938846378655804","answers":["peccant"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *pecco* (to commit a fault, to sin)?"},"L1020573":{"interactionID":"1304938823519834159","answers":["percipiebat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *percipio* (to occupy; to perceive, observe)?"},"L1011264":{"interactionID":"1304938908240318464","answers":["mandant"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural present active indicative** of *mando* (to order, command)?"},"H000876":{"interactionID":"1305612147794903092","answers":["BONONIA"],"genus":"history","question":"Where did Marc Antony, Octavian, and Lepidus meet in 43 BC to form the Second Triumvirate?"},"H000656":{"interactionID":"1305612274811011153","answers":["133 BC"],"genus":"history","question":"In what year did Attalus III bequeathe Pergamum to the Romans in his will?"},"H000561":{"interactionID":"1305617057500495983","answers":["HASDRUBAL"],"genus":"history","question":"What brother of Hannibal defended Spain while Hannibal invaded Italy?"},"H000318":{"interactionID":"1305617098940092426","answers":["TEMPLE OF JUPITER CAPITOLINUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What is the alternate name of the Temple of Jupiter Optimus Maximus?"},"H000057":{"interactionID":"1305622269229404191","answers":["APPIUS CLAUDIUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What man, the only member of both decemviri councils, is infamous for his tyrannical actions?"},"H000511":{"interactionID":"1305625257423536270","answers":["HAMILCAR BARCA"],"genus":"history","question":"What Carthaginian made his young son Hannibal swear eternal hatred for Rome in return for the opportunity to join his father's military exploits?"},"H000526":{"interactionID":"1305628427310596167","answers":["TREBIA RIVER"],"genus":"history","question":"After his victory at the Ticinus River, where did Hannibal defeat the forces of Sempronius Longus?"},"H000243":{"interactionID":"1305670717433450527","answers":["753–509 BC"],"genus":"history","question":"What were the beginning and ending years of the Monarchy?"},"H001027":{"interactionID":"1305670760857206894","answers":["VITELLIUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Which emperor was defeated at the Second Battle of Bedriacum in 69 AD"},"H000633":{"interactionID":"1305673586916331561","answers":["MASSINISSA"],"genus":"history","question":"Who caused Third Punic War by making raids into Carthaginian territory which forced them to retaliate and violate their treaty with the Romans?"},"H000425":{"interactionID":"1305681153327628368","answers":["FABIUS RULLIANUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What Roman commander was defeated by the Samnites at Lautulae in 315 BC?"},"H001167":{"interactionID":"1305681122834776116","answers":["MAXIMINUS THRAX, GORDIAN I, GORDIAN II, BALBINUS, PUPIENUS, GORDIAN III"],"genus":"history","question":"Name the 6 emperors of 238 AD."},"H001134":{"interactionID":"1305681328389226637","answers":["SEVERANS"],"genus":"history","question":"Which dynasty reigned from 193–235 AD?"},"H000481":{"interactionID":"1305697688154538024","answers":["DUILIUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What Roman admiral won Rome's first major naval battle at Mylae in 260 BC?"},"H001228":{"interactionID":"1305697654155513876","answers":["RULE BY 4 (FOUR)"],"genus":"history","question":"What does \"tetrarchy\" mean?"},"H000413":{"interactionID":"1305700589413335090","answers":["298–290 BC"],"genus":"history","question":"What were the years of the Third Samnite War?"},"H000034":{"interactionID":"1305740737870037053","answers":["TARQUINNIUS SUPERBUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Who took refuge at Caere in Etruria after he and his sons were banished from Rome in 509 BC?"},"H000598":{"interactionID":"1305750462334500878","answers":["168 BC"],"genus":"history","question":"In what year did Aemilius Paullus defeat Perseus of Macedon at Pydna?"},"H000749":{"interactionID":"1305750496471941134","answers":["CRASSUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Which triumvir was killed fighting the the Parthians at Carrhae in 53 BC?"},"H000367":{"interactionID":"1305759192468029440","answers":["6 MONTHS","SIX MONTHS"],"genus":"history","question":"How long did a dictator serve?"},"H000816":{"interactionID":"1305791177722691674","answers":["59 BC"],"genus":"history","question":"In what year was Julius Caesar elected consul for the first time?"},"H000622":{"interactionID":"1305791314612453406","answers":["188 BC"],"genus":"history","question":"In what year did the Treaty of Apamea officially end the war against Antiochus III?"},"F000278":{"interactionID":"1306454574059622422","answers":["DIANA"],"genus":"myth","question":"What was the Roman name of Artemis?"},"F000467":{"interactionID":"1306454630879723530","answers":["HECATE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What deity was known for bearing a torch?"},"F000793":{"interactionID":"1306456781484200017","answers":["OENOMAUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Hippodamia?"},"H000197":{"interactionID":"1306884932169240646","answers":["COMMODUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What son of Marcus Aurelius ruled from 180–192 AD?"},"H000999":{"interactionID":"1306884989736190004","answers":["SENECA THE YOUNGER"],"genus":"history","question":"What teacher of Nero was forced to commit suicide in 65 AD because of his involvement in the Pisonian Conspiracy?"},"L1015557":{"interactionID":"1307131993095536731","answers":["restituet"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future active indicative** of *restituo* (to give back, restore)?"},"L1019086":{"interactionID":"1307132040402964621","answers":["committemus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future active indicative** of *committo* (to connect; to engage in)?"},"H000607":{"interactionID":"1307137359095271536","answers":["192–188 BC"],"genus":"history","question":"What were the years of the War with Antiochus?"},"L1000017":{"interactionID":"1307151941851418684","answers":["puellis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative plural** of *puella, puellae* (girl)?"},"L1010155":{"interactionID":"1307151959689662615","answers":["salutavero"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *saluto* (to greet, salute)?"},"L1019111":{"interactionID":"1307151923203411989","answers":["colitis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural present active indicative** of *colo* (to cultivate; to inhabit; to care for; to honor)?"},"L1005990":{"interactionID":"1307153361568665752","answers":["humanis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine ablative plural** of *humanus* (human, gentle)?"},"H000457":{"interactionID":"1307205920601804892","answers":["275 BC"],"genus":"history","question":"In what year did the Romans defeat Pyrrhus at Beneventum?"},"F000194":{"interactionID":"1307206587416445038","answers":["CINYRAS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the son of Paphos?"},"H000552":{"interactionID":"1307213504650154048","answers":["ROMULUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Who won the first Spolia Opima by defeating Acron?"},"LFIFTH000795":{"interactionID":"1307374874569998427","answers":["lacunar"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative singular** of *lacunar, lacunaris* (ceiling)?"},"LFIFTH000971":{"interactionID":"1307374914701103218","answers":["clade"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *clades, cladis* (disaster, defeat)?"},"LFIFTH004772":{"interactionID":"1307375069458206750","answers":["maeruisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *maereo* (to be sad, mournful)?"},"H000408":{"interactionID":"1307463067478790204","answers":["BRENNUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Who said \"Vae Victis\" when the Romans complained about false weights on the scale used to weigh his ransom money?"},"H001084":{"interactionID":"1307463103822172231","answers":["117–138 AD"],"genus":"history","question":"What were the years of Hadrian's reign?"},"H001052":{"interactionID":"1307465472618401802","answers":["COLOSSUS STATUE OF NERO IN FRONT"],"genus":"history","question":"How did the Colosseum receive its name?"},"H000878":{"interactionID":"1307472526871625848","answers":["PERUSIA"],"genus":"history","question":"At what battle of 40 BC did Octavian capture Fulvia and Lucius Antony?"},"H000593":{"interactionID":"1307487565439565856","answers":["196 BC"],"genus":"history","question":"In what year did Flamininus declare freedom and independence for all the Greek states at the Isthmian Games?"},"H000292":{"interactionID":"1307487604597325866","answers":["ANCUS MARCIUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Which king started a settlement at Ostia where the Tiber meets the Mediterranean?"},"H000539":{"interactionID":"1307487768330506250","answers":["QUINTUS FABIUS MAXIMUS CUNCTATOR"],"genus":"history","question":"Who adopted a delaying strategy and avoided all out battle with Hannibal when he was appointed dictator?"},"H000329":{"interactionID":"1307896898350354512","answers":["SEXTUS TARQUINIUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What son of Tarquinius Superbus abused royal power by taking advantage of Lucretia, the wife of Collatinus?"},"H001119":{"interactionID":"1307896936849870949","answers":["COLONIA COMMODIANA"],"genus":"history","question":"What did Commodus change Rome's name to?"},"H000793":{"interactionID":"1307897086368415754","answers":["CATO THE YOUNGER"],"genus":"history","question":"What statesman routinely opposed Julius Caesar and fought for the death penalty for Catiline and his co-conspirators?"},"H001026":{"interactionID":"1307913857184043058","answers":["CAECINA & VALENS"],"genus":"history","question":"Who were the two star generals of Vitellius?"},"H001036":{"interactionID":"1307913841417388055","answers":["VESPASIAN"],"genus":"history","question":"Which emperor was the father of Titus & Domitian?"},"H000861":{"interactionID":"1307913885608837191","answers":["JULIA"],"genus":"history","question":"Who was the daughter of Caesar and Cornelia?"},"H000327":{"interactionID":"1307914057139093625","answers":["BURNED 3 OF THEM"],"genus":"history","question":"What did the Sibyl do each time Tarquinius Superbus refused to pay the price for the Sibylline books?"},"D000361":{"interactionID":"1308271866326286359","answers":["hospes"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *hotel* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000624":{"interactionID":"1308271917677019177","answers":["plecto"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *apply* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"L1009275":{"interactionID":"1308683071436099665","answers":["detulerit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *defero* (to bear or bring away; to report)?"},"L1017072":{"interactionID":"1308683131494334514","answers":["iunxerint"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *iungo* (to join)?"},"L1021324":{"interactionID":"1308683392656740353","answers":["accepimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active indicative** of *accipio* (to receive)?"},"L1011105":{"interactionID":"1308683409895460885","answers":["negaverat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *nego* (to say no, to deny)?"},"L1014693":{"interactionID":"1308683417088692254","answers":["vincet"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future active indicative** of *vinco* (to win, to prevail)?"},"L1015929":{"interactionID":"1308683566938325002","answers":["quaesiverat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *quaero* (to seek, ask, inquire, desire)?"},"L1011147":{"interactionID":"1308683576379969547","answers":["narraverit"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *narro* (to tell, narrate)?"},"L1013381":{"interactionID":"1308683744902905978","answers":["prohibebitis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future active indicative** of *prohibeo* (to forbid, prohibit)?"},"L1019988":{"interactionID":"1308683805023797259","answers":["addent"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural future active indicative** of *addo* (to add)?"},"D000325":{"interactionID":"1308684039418282044","answers":["foro"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *perforate* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000732":{"interactionID":"1308684069755682816","answers":["scamnum"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *shambles* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000698":{"interactionID":"1308684078094225439","answers":["rego"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *rail* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"P000059":{"interactionID":"1308684184977674250","answers":["SALUS POPULI SUPREMA LEX ESTO. (\"LET THE WELFARE OF THE PEOPLE BE THE SUPREME LAW.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Missouri*?"},"P000234":{"interactionID":"1355579700952568149","answers":["I HAVE RAISED A MONUMENT MORE LASTING THAN BRONZE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Exegi monumentum aere perennius**."},"P000056":{"interactionID":"1308686476145590312","answers":["SI QUAERIS PENINSULAM AMOENAM, CIRCUMSPICE (\"IF YOU SEEK A PLEASANT PENINSULA, LOOK AROUND\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Michigan*?"},"P000038":{"interactionID":"1308687698587942933","answers":["STUDIIS ET REBUS HONESTIS (\"BY HONORABLE PURSUITS AND DEEDS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Vermont*?"},"P000013":{"interactionID":"1308687819069460490","answers":["VERITAS VOS LIBERABIT. (\"TRUTH WILL FREE YOU.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Johns Hopkins University*?"},"P000177":{"interactionID":"1308810592055857172","answers":["IN MEMORY OF"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *in memoriam*?"},"P000113":{"interactionID":"1308813667881451612","answers":["(ET ALIA) AND OTHERS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *et al.*?"},"H000985":{"interactionID":"1309006501154783232","answers":["MUSHROOMS"],"genus":"history","question":"What poisonous food was said to have killed Claudius?"},"H000347":{"interactionID":"1309006596600238080","answers":["HELD HIS RIGHT HAND IN A FIRE TO SHOW LARS PORSENNA THE ROMANS WOULD NOT SURRENDER"],"genus":"history","question":"How did Mucius Scaevola earn his cognomen?"},"H001244":{"interactionID":"1309013409551089736","answers":["CHRISTIANITY"],"genus":"history","question":"What religion did Constantine make the official religion of the empire?"},"H000837":{"interactionID":"1309013821024894976","answers":["ALEA IACTA EST"],"genus":"history","question":"What did Caesar reportedly say before crossing the Rubicon in 49 BC?"},"L1002018":{"interactionID":"1309697701352570880","answers":["facto"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **ablative singular** of *factum, facti* (deed, act)?"},"L1021584":{"interactionID":"1309697750585180225","answers":["reppererant"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *reperio* (to find)?"},"D000146":{"interactionID":"1311843886293061683","answers":["cauda"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *cue* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"P000231":{"interactionID":"1310033562673741955","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Eheu fugaces labuntur anni**?"},"P000239":{"interactionID":"1309752871268519936","answers":["JUVENAL"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Mens sana in corpore sano**?"},"P000190":{"interactionID":"1310031525177331822","answers":["AUTOPSY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *post mortem*?"},"D000564":{"interactionID":"1310314848822886431","answers":["panis"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *appanage* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"GMDR001640":{"interactionID":"1310439898171445329","answers":["small brain cells (with **micr-** meaning __millionth","denoting something as small, relating to smallness__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **microglia**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *micr-*."},"GMDR001274":{"interactionID":"1310354206796025896","answers":["chlor- (h) meaning denoting a green color"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Identify a Greek medical root of **chloroma** (*rare type of tumor containing green pigment*)."},"GMDR003783":{"interactionID":"1310362670461091900","answers":["sigmoido-"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots appears in **sigmoiditis** (*inflammation of the sigmoid colon*)? The choices are *schisto-*, *schizo-*, *sclero-*, and *sigmoido-*."},"GMDR002168":{"interactionID":"1310365856739364975","answers":["rod-like structures in some invertebrates (with **rhabdo-** meaning __rod shaped, striated__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **rhabdite**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *rhabd(o)-*."},"H000420":{"interactionID":"1310409922906685480","answers":["CAUDINE FORKS"],"genus":"history","question":"At what battle in 321 BC did the Samnite force a Roman army to walk under the yoke?"},"H000841":{"interactionID":"1310409943429419098","answers":["PHARSALUS"],"genus":"history","question":"At what battle in 48 BC did Caesar defeat Pompey and put him to flight?"},"H000879":{"interactionID":"1310409964904255569","answers":["FULVIA AND LUCIUS ANTONY"],"genus":"history","question":"What wife and brother of Marc Antony did Octavian capture at Perusia?"},"H000901":{"interactionID":"1310411102135521425","answers":["27 BC–14 AD"],"genus":"history","question":"What were the years of Augustus' reign?"},"GMDR000719":{"interactionID":"1310431378160091166","answers":["blepharo-"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots implies **of or pertaining to the eyelid**? The choices are *blast-*, *blepharo-*, *brachy-*, and *brady-*."},"GMDR001837":{"interactionID":"1310431332362489971","answers":["membrane around heart (with **peri-** meaning __denoting something with a position 'surrounding' or 'around' another__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **pericardium**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *peri-*."},"GMDR002335":{"interactionID":"1310437796132946041","answers":["recording uterine contractions during labor (with **toco-** meaning __childbirth__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **tocography**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *toco-*."},"GMDR002165":{"interactionID":"1310437911132377138","answers":["a condition involving the breakdown of muscle tissue, releasing harmful proteins into the bloodstream (with **rhabdo-** meaning __rod shaped, striated__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **rhabdomyolysis**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *rhabd(o)-*."},"GMDR001884":{"interactionID":"1310438056599486547","answers":["canal carrying urine (with **ur-** meaning __of or pertaining to urine, the urinary system__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **urethra**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *ur-*."},"GMDR001955":{"interactionID":"1310438633773465600","answers":["a performance or expression involving gestures and no speech (with **pan-** meaning __denoting something as 'complete' or containing 'everything'","\"all\"__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **pantomime**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *pan-, pant(o)-*."},"GMDR000360":{"interactionID":"1310439088926625873","answers":["odyn- (meaning **pain**)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What Greek medical root comes from the Greek **ὀδύνη (odúnē)**?"},"GMDR002069":{"interactionID":"1310439104672043048","answers":["a term used historically for seizures induced by electrical shock (with **-plexy** meaning __stroke or seizure__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **electroplexy**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *-plexy*."},"GMDR002157":{"interactionID":"1310439307143807018","answers":["having a thick, stocky body build (with **pykno-** meaning __to thicken (as the nucleus does in early stages of cell death)__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **pyknic**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *pykno-*."},"GMDR000940":{"interactionID":"1310497592051765330","answers":["myelo-"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots implies **of or relating to bone marrow or the spinal cord**? The choices are *myri-*, *myo-*, *myelo-*, and *myco-*."},"GMDR001269":{"interactionID":"1310497631553982485","answers":["brachy-"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots appears in **brachygnathia** (*abnormal shortness of jaw*)? The choices are *blast-*, *blepharo-*, *brachy-*, and *brady-*."},"GMDR002282":{"interactionID":"1310497614008946779","answers":["combined action or cooperation (with **sy-** meaning __indicates similarity, likeness, or being together","assimilates before some consonants: before l to syl-, s to sys-, before a labial consonant to sym-__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **synergy**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *sy-, syl-, sym-, syn-, sys-*."},"GMDR002098":{"interactionID":"1310497650637803581","answers":["a pigment involved in forming heme, a component of hemoglobin (with **porphyr-** meaning __denotes a purple color__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **porphyrin**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *porphyr-*."},"D000614":{"interactionID":"1310498681316704287","answers":["piscis"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *porpoise* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"GMDR000633":{"interactionID":"1310500451405402142","answers":["turned toward, with an orientation toward, having an affinity for, affecting"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What does the Greek medical root **-trop** mean?"},"GMDR002362":{"interactionID":"1310500964607983627","answers":["congenital fissure of the neck (with **trachelo-** meaning __of or pertaining to the neck__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **tracheloschisis**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *trachel(o)-*."},"GMDR000166":{"interactionID":"1310501045063122944","answers":["encephal(o)-, encephalo- (meaning **of or pertaining to the brain","see also cerebro-**)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What Greek medical root comes from the Greek **ἐγκέφαλος (enképhalos), the brain**?"},"GMDR001990":{"interactionID":"1310502263013511188","answers":["an organism that eats wood (with **phagist-** meaning __feeder of or the act of feeding on__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **xylophagist**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *phagist-, -phagy*."},"GMDR000092":{"interactionID":"1310501394171695166","answers":["chem(o)-, chemo- (meaning **chemistry, drug**)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What Greek medical root comes from the Greek **χημεία (khēmeía)**?"},"GMDR002205":{"interactionID":"1310501458424102972","answers":["a fragmented part of a red blood cell (with **schisto-** meaning __split, cleft__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **schistocyte**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *schist(o)-*."},"GMDR001744":{"interactionID":"1310501555279106058","answers":["ear pain (with **oto-** meaning __of or pertaining to the ear__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **otalgia**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *ot(o)-*."},"GMDR001750":{"interactionID":"1310501837786447904","answers":["cutting into or drawing blood from a vein (with **phleb-** meaning __of or pertaining to the (blood) veins, a vein__","**-tomy** meaning __act of cutting","incising, incision__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **phlebotomy**, which is derived from the Greek medical roots *phleb-*; *-tomy*."},"GMDR002275":{"interactionID":"1310503761386668034","answers":["excessively strong or vigorous (with **stheno-** meaning __strength, force, power__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **hypersthenic**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *stheno-*."},"GMDR001577":{"interactionID":"1310503775491985469","answers":["white patches on mucous membranes (with **leuco-** meaning __denoting a white color__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **leukoplakia**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *leuc(o)-, leuk(o)-*."},"GMDR001691":{"interactionID":"1310711825536520304","answers":["eardrum repair (with **myri-** meaning __ten thousand__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **myringoplasty**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *myri-*."},"H000791":{"interactionID":"1310725688973594637","answers":["ANTIUM"],"genus":"history","question":"Where did the prows used for the rostra come from?"},"GMDR000483":{"interactionID":"1310786640524087376","answers":["denotes something as 'before' another (in [physical] position or time)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What does the Greek medical root **pro-** mean?"},"GMDR001949":{"interactionID":"1310788540048605215","answers":["twins joined at the chest (with **-pagus** meaning __Indicates conjoined twins, with the first part denoting the organs fused__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **thoracopagus**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *-pagus*."},"GMDR002304":{"interactionID":"1310788710408785950","answers":["pain in the nipple (with **thel-** meaning __of or pertaining to a nipple (uncommon as a prefix)__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the term **thelalgia**, which is derived from the Greek medical root *thel-*."},"GMDR000921":{"interactionID":"1310792676123344916","answers":["**-ectomy** meaning __denotes a surgical operation or removal of a body part","resection, excision__","**spleno-** meaning __spleen__ (and **splenectomy** meaning __removal of spleen__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **splenectomy**."},"D000804":{"interactionID":"1310794119395807333","answers":["tempto"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *tentacle* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000581":{"interactionID":"1310859225408213012","answers":["parvus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *paraffin* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000336":{"interactionID":"1310859263601807390","answers":["fundo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *futile* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000163":{"interactionID":"1310859244806869024","answers":["cingo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *cinch* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000374":{"interactionID":"1310859280244539512","answers":["inter"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *enter* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000795":{"interactionID":"1310861289479999590","answers":["sum"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *puissance* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000487":{"interactionID":"1310861409780760617","answers":["moneo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *muster* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"GMDR000101":{"interactionID":"1311065076580483113","answers":["cartilage, gristle, granule, granular"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What does the Greek medical root **chondr(i)o-** mean?"},"GMDR000588":{"interactionID":"1311065019638878328","answers":["-gen"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots implies **born in, from**? The choices are *-gen*, *-genic*, *galact-*, and *gastr-*."},"GMDR001090":{"interactionID":"1311065040182317086","answers":["**laryngo-** meaning __of or pertaining to the larynx, the lower throat cavity where the voice box is__ (and **laryngitis** meaning __inflammation of larynx__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **laryngitis**."},"GMDR001079":{"interactionID":"1311065059769974944","answers":["**kerat-** meaning __cornea (eye or skin)__ (and **LASIK** meaning __surgical reshaping of cornea with laser__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **LASIK**."},"D000196":{"interactionID":"1311146495852019712","answers":["costa"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *accost* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000726":{"interactionID":"1312277538810105947","answers":["sal"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *sauce* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"H000852":{"interactionID":"1311495923670585344","answers":["46 BC"],"genus":"history","question":"In what year did Caesar win the battle of Thapsus against Pompey's sons & Cato the Younger?"},"H000132":{"interactionID":"1311496475628277813","answers":["CLAUDIUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Which emperor advanced the efforts of his predecessor when he moved beyond the shores of Kent and conquered Britain in 43 AD?"},"D000562":{"interactionID":"1311523598225244200","answers":["pango"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *impinge* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000545":{"interactionID":"1311523634292068352","answers":["oro"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *orison* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000648":{"interactionID":"1311523616982040656","answers":["prehendo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *entrepreneur* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000282":{"interactionID":"1311843868840562749","answers":["exsul"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *exile* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000174":{"interactionID":"1311843849899081800","answers":["claudo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *sluice* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000780":{"interactionID":"1311843837810835466","answers":["sto"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *arrest* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000609":{"interactionID":"1311891887937818725","answers":["pila"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *platoon* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000753":{"interactionID":"1311891868757262406","answers":["sero"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *assert* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000410":{"interactionID":"1311896767998197830","answers":["side","flank"],"genus":"derivative","question":"What is the definition of the Latin root that *lateral* derives from?"},"GMDR000198":{"interactionID":"1311931244535353385","answers":["gluco- (meaning **sweet**)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What Greek medical root comes from the Greek **γλυκύς (glukús), sweet**?"},"D000670":{"interactionID":"1311952213647818755","answers":["quails"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *kickshaw* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000517":{"interactionID":"1312103448526979143","answers":["nomen"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *renown* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000810":{"interactionID":"1312103466038202378","answers":["teneo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *rein* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000023":{"interactionID":"1312110033613361293","answers":["altus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *exalt* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"H000212":{"interactionID":"1312146320684748810","answers":["LAVINIA"],"genus":"history","question":"What daughter of King Latinus did Aeneas marry in Italy?"},"H000979":{"interactionID":"1312147755908595773","answers":["BRITANNICUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Who was the son of Claudius and Messalina?"},"D000312":{"interactionID":"1313762065302687744","answers":["focus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *foyer* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000162":{"interactionID":"1312164442594873496","answers":["cilium"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *supercilious* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000547":{"interactionID":"1312164459695050774","answers":["bone"],"genus":"derivative","question":"What is the definition of the Latin root that *osprey* derives from?"},"D000200":{"interactionID":"1312164477973561445","answers":["cratis"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *grill* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000090":{"interactionID":"1312164541496430763","answers":["calx"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *cockatrice* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"H000580":{"interactionID":"1312239642099318784","answers":["PHILIP V"],"genus":"history","question":"What king of Macedon allied with Hannibal and attacked Rome in 215 BC?"},"D000302":{"interactionID":"1312277518539034625","answers":["fingo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *feign* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"GMDR000293":{"interactionID":"1312279417099128892","answers":["denotes someone who studies a certain field (the field of ------logy)","a specialist","one who treats"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What does the Greek medical root **-logist** mean?"},"D000685":{"interactionID":"1312289251597090836","answers":["racemus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *raisin* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"GMDR001068":{"interactionID":"1312636543436849242","answers":["**-ismus** meaning __spasm, contraction__ (and **vaginismus** meaning __vaginal muscle spasm__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **vaginismus**."},"GMDR000858":{"interactionID":"1312637261593972768","answers":["**cor-** meaning __of or pertaining to the eye's pupil__ (and **corectomy** meaning __excision of part of the iris__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **corectomy**."},"A000006":{"interactionID":"1313305633495453737","answers":["aeido (αειδω), to sing"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **ode**?"},"A000627":{"interactionID":"1313305679825604710","answers":["little, small... micros (μικρος)","behold, examine, inspect, consider, see... skopeo (σκοπεω)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **microscope**?"},"A000715":{"interactionID":"1313309870472171520","answers":["water... hydor (ὑδωρ)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **hydrochloric**?"},"A000342":{"interactionID":"1313394938188136459","answers":["theomai (θεαομαι), to behold"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **theory**?"},"A000166":{"interactionID":"1313394892709433344","answers":["ballo (βαλλω), throw"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the Greek root of the word **parliament**?"},"A000535":{"interactionID":"1313395301532307487","answers":["homos (ὁμος)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What Greek word means **one and the same, like**?"},"D000260":{"interactionID":"1313756790399303681","answers":["emo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *exempt* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000169":{"interactionID":"1313759614021533748","answers":["clamo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *clarity* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000658":{"interactionID":"1313759978930311198","answers":["pretium"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *price* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000434":{"interactionID":"1313760924431286302","answers":["ligo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *liaison* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000295":{"interactionID":"1313761671554007060","answers":["fido"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *federal* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000827":{"interactionID":"1313762140095647797","answers":["torqueo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *torch* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"P000235":{"interactionID":"1355299737779048488","answers":["HORACE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **parturient montes, nasceture ridiculus mus**?"},"P000228":{"interactionID":"1355168301021401128","answers":["SEIZE THE DAY, TRUSTING AS LITTLE AS POSSIBLE IN TOMORROW"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Carpe diem, quam minimum credula postero**."},"P000054":{"interactionID":"1339062623458562108","answers":["CRESCITE ET MULTIPLICAMINI (\"INCREASE AND MULTIPLY\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Maryland*?"},"D000028":{"interactionID":"1313891670852636703","answers":["ante"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *ancient* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000809":{"interactionID":"1313891653190418493","answers":["teneo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *abstain* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000807":{"interactionID":"1313891706944360510","answers":["tendo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *standard* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000506":{"interactionID":"1313892819907379200","answers":["nego"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *renegade* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"P000225":{"interactionID":"1313893997797707816","answers":["DESCARTES"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous person said **Cogito ergo sum**?"},"P000209":{"interactionID":"1313894203130122240","answers":["BY WAY OF"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *via*?"},"P000088":{"interactionID":"1313894221022892143","answers":["SIT TIBI TERRA LEVIS (\"MAY THE EARTH REST LIGHTLY ON YOU\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *S.T.T.L.*?"},"LFIFTH001803":{"interactionID":"1314132778370990130","answers":["candidi"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine nominative plural** of *candidus* (white, clear)?"},"LFIFTH001778":{"interactionID":"1314132824487493632","answers":["blando"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter ablative singular** of *blandus* (agreeable)?"},"LFIFTH004001":{"interactionID":"1314137697832665109","answers":["laceravisti"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular perfect active indicative** of *lacero* (to tear to pieces, to lacerate)?"},"P000200":{"interactionID":"1315488625659482172","answers":["SECRETLY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Sub rosa*?"},"H000426":{"interactionID":"1316988985427628082","answers":["APPIUS CLAUDIUS CAECUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Who built a road from Rome to Capua which helped the Romans win the 2nd Samnite War?"},"H000437":{"interactionID":"1316993319921782804","answers":["2","TWO"],"genus":"history","question":"How many censors served at once?"},"H000195":{"interactionID":"1318067523257897061","answers":["COMMODUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What emperor could allegedly hit an ostrich with a javelin at 50 paces and could frequently be seen in the arena dressed as Hercules?"},"H001243":{"interactionID":"1318067497114796092","answers":["CONSTANTINE"],"genus":"history","question":"Which emperor made Christianity the official religion of the empire?"},"H001140":{"interactionID":"1318067563204444201","answers":["CARACALLA & GETA"],"genus":"history","question":"Who were the two sons of Septimius Severus & Julia Domna?"},"H001234":{"interactionID":"1318067854729281586","answers":["DIOCLETIAN"],"genus":"history","question":"Who was the first emperor to abdicate from power and retire?"},"H001240":{"interactionID":"1318072044826660894","answers":["MAXIMIAN"],"genus":"history","question":"Which Tetrarch was the father of Maxentius?"},"H001037":{"interactionID":"1318072067031044156","answers":["VESPASIAN"],"genus":"history","question":"Which emperor said on his deathbed \"vae, puto, deus fio\"?"},"H001305":{"interactionID":"1318415536446640241","answers":["ODOACER"],"genus":"history","question":"What Germanic chieftain sacked Rome in 476 AD?"},"H000172":{"interactionID":"1318420201745809439","answers":["THEODOSIUS I"],"genus":"history","question":"Who was the last emperor to rule a united Roman Empire?"},"H000158":{"interactionID":"1318427641539203092","answers":["DOMITIAN"],"genus":"history","question":"What emperor first led a campaign against Decebalus and the Dacians?"},"H000635":{"interactionID":"1318433840548810752","answers":["SALTED THE FIELDS"],"genus":"history","question":"What did Scipio Aemilianus do to ensure Carthage would never be able to grow crops again?"},"H000477":{"interactionID":"1328933767292780605","answers":["TO MAKE CARTHAGE LEAVE MESSANA"],"genus":"history","question":"Why did the Mamertines appeal to Rome for help?"},"H000105":{"interactionID":"1328933814944272514","answers":["SATURNINUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Whose career as tribune began in 103 BC with legislation to provide land settlements to Marius' veterans and ended with a senatus consultum ultimum and a shower of roof tiles?"},"H001045":{"interactionID":"1328933900482777191","answers":["TITUS'"],"genus":"history","question":"During which emperor's reign did Mt. Vesuvius erupt?"},"H001096":{"interactionID":"1328934633924067471","answers":["161–180 AD"],"genus":"history","question":"What were the years of Marcus Aurelius' reign?"},"H001139":{"interactionID":"1328944788552028220","answers":["ARCH OF SEPTIMIUS SEVERUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What structure in the Forum Romanum commemorates the military accomplishments of Septimius Severus?"},"H000652":{"interactionID":"1329300051364675624","answers":["TIBERIUS GRACCHUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Who negotiated with Numantia for the release of 20,000 Roman soldiers in 137 BC?"},"H000093":{"interactionID":"1329300077294129233","answers":["LEX TITIA"],"genus":"history","question":"What law of 43 BC legalized the Second Triumvirate?"},"H000911":{"interactionID":"1329300095472111700","answers":["PANTHEON"],"genus":"history","question":"What temple did Augutus' chief leiutenant Agrippa build?"},"H000666":{"interactionID":"1329301778205904926","answers":["TIBERIUS GRACCHUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What tribune of 133 BC was killed for proposing radical legislation which favored the plebeians?"},"H000543":{"interactionID":"1336882366127276073","answers":["SYRACUSE"],"genus":"history","question":"What Sicilian city did Marcellus capture in 211 BC?"},"H000422":{"interactionID":"1336882347269685311","answers":["WALK UNDER THE YOKE"],"genus":"history","question":"What sign of complete surrender did the Samnites force upon the Romans after the Caudine Forks?"},"H000185":{"interactionID":"1336882400235622441","answers":["ADRIANOPLE"],"genus":"history","question":"At what battle of 378 AD was the emperor Valens killed in battle?"},"H000813":{"interactionID":"1336882328219287637","answers":["QUAESTOR"],"genus":"history","question":"Which officials were in charge of Rome's finances?"},"H000054":{"interactionID":"1336898219007021107","answers":["CINCINNATUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What man did the Senate chose to be dictator to save the Romans at Mt. Algidus?"},"H000785":{"interactionID":"1336898254104690769","answers":["43 BC"],"genus":"history","question":"In what year was Cicero executed at Formiae?"},"H000025":{"interactionID":"1336900669151383643","answers":["MINORES GENTES"],"genus":"history","question":"Tarquinnius Priscus enlarged the Senate by adding another 100 members, many of whom were probably Etruscan. What were these new members called?"},"L1002160":{"interactionID":"1337277996649680966","answers":["astrum"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative singular** of *astrum, astri* (star)?"},"L1011213":{"interactionID":"1337277929855389756","answers":["mirabat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *miror* (to wonder, to be amazed, to admire)?"},"LFIFTH002640":{"interactionID":"1337282960545550377","answers":["fideles"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine/feminine nominative plural** of *fidelis* (loyal, trusty, faithful)?"},"L1015079":{"interactionID":"1337480440373575780","answers":["tenuistis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural perfect active indicative** of *teneo* (to hold, keep, possess)?"},"L1020805":{"interactionID":"1337480465677815859","answers":["ieceram"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular pluperfect active indicative** of *iacio* (to throw)?"},"L1022093":{"interactionID":"1337480401299570689","answers":["aperueritis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *aperio* (to uncover)?"},"LFIFTH006300":{"interactionID":"1337481897823178772","answers":["coniunxit"],"genus":"LFIFTH_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect active indicative** of *coniungo* (to join)?"},"L1021601":{"interactionID":"1337885953410338826","answers":["oriebatis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *orior* (to rise, get up)?"},"L1009713":{"interactionID":"1337886049971470407","answers":["vetat"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular present active indicative** of *veto* (to forbid)?"},"L1011953":{"interactionID":"1337886574821769357","answers":["dubitabatis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural imperfect active indicative** of *dubito* (to be in doubt, to doubt)?"},"L1007199":{"interactionID":"1337886614633840701","answers":["civili"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter ablative singular** of *civilis* (pertaining to the citizen)?"},"GMDR000657":{"interactionID":"1339054287342538794","answers":["**aero-** meaning __air, gas__ (and **aeroembolism** meaning __air bubble in blood vessels__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **aeroembolism**."},"P000109":{"interactionID":"1339055360580911166","answers":["(CONFER) COMPARE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *cf.*?"},"L1010720":{"interactionID":"1339055530211147818","answers":["oras"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular present active indicative** of *oro* (to pray, to plead)?"},"L1011262":{"interactionID":"1339057036587040768","answers":["mandamus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural present active indicative** of *mando* (to order, command)?"},"L1010678":{"interactionID":"1339057269983150215","answers":["peccaveris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *pecco* (to commit a fault, to sin)?"},"P000014":{"interactionID":"1339059585339752469","answers":["PRODESSE QUAM CONSPICI. (\"TO THE PRODUCTIVE, RATHER THAN TO BE ORNAMENTAL.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Miami University of Ohio*?"},"L1020971":{"interactionID":"1339062485558235207","answers":["effeceratis"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural pluperfect active indicative** of *efficio* (to accomplish, make, form)?"},"P000027":{"interactionID":"1339065425023078440","answers":["ET DOCERE ET RERUM EXQUIRERE CAUSAS (\"BOTH TO TEACH & TO INQUIRE INTO THE CAUSES OF THINGS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Georgia*?"},"P000074":{"interactionID":"1355599043123871806","answers":["DOMINE, DIRIGE NOS (\"LORD, GUIDE US\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *London*?"},"P000011":{"interactionID":"1355298951254900806","answers":["MIHI CURA FUTURI. (\"MY ANXIETY IS FOR THE FUTURE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Hunter College*?"},"P000008":{"interactionID":"1339065828146020403","answers":["SAPIENTIA ET DOCTRINA. (\"WISDOM AND KNOWLEDGE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Fordham University*?"},"GMDR000068":{"interactionID":"1339100725493366815","answers":["-pepsia (meaning **denotes something relating to digestion, or the digestive tract.**)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What Greek medical root comes from the Greek **πεπτός (peptós), cooked, digested < πέσσω (péssō), I boil, cook; digest**?"},"GMDR001188":{"interactionID":"1339100688407334952","answers":["**-tony** meaning __tension__ (and **atony** meaning __lack of muscle tone__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **atony**."},"P000061":{"interactionID":"1339104609360285759","answers":["EXCELSIOR! (\"HIGHER!\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *New York*?"},"L000287":{"interactionID":"1339105916053622824","answers":["MONUMENTUM ANCYRANUM"],"genus":"literature","question":"Where was Augustus' Res Gestae found inscribed?"},"GMDR000273":{"interactionID":"1339110563703296020","answers":["place, topical"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What does the Greek medical root **top(o)-** mean?"},"GMDR000687":{"interactionID":"1339110654300127344","answers":["**-phagia** meaning __Forms terms denoting conditions relating to eating or ingestion__ (and **macrophage** meaning __a type of white blood cell that engulfs and digests pathogens__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **macrophage**."},"GMDR000002":{"interactionID":"1339110668158373888","answers":["narc(o)-, narco- (meaning **numb, sleep**)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What Greek medical root comes from the Greek **νάρκη (nárkē), numbess, torpor**?"},"GMDR000540":{"interactionID":"1339110681433083935","answers":["myo-"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots appears in **myopathy** (*muscle disease*)? The choices are *myo-*, *myco-*, *myelo-*, and *mylo-*."},"GMDR000354":{"interactionID":"1339110743341137960","answers":["pod-"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots implies **of or pertaining to the foot, -footed**? The choices are *pod-*, *polio-*, *poly-*, and *por-*."},"GMDR000440":{"interactionID":"1339110755051634708","answers":["-oid"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots implies **resemblance to**? The choices are *-oma*, *-opsy*, *-oid*, and *-osis*."},"GMDR000405":{"interactionID":"1339110771379933186","answers":["-rrhexis"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots implies **rupture**? The choices are *-rrhage*, *-rrhaphy*, *-rrhea*, and *-rrhexis*."},"GMDR000972":{"interactionID":"1339110784915079168","answers":["**psor-** meaning __Itching__ (and **psoroma** meaning __an old term for a skin condition with itching__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **psoroma**."},"GMDR000379":{"interactionID":"1339110803118358613","answers":["phot-"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots implies **of or pertaining to light**? The choices are *phos-*, *phot-*, *pan-*, and *phon-*."},"GMDR000482":{"interactionID":"1339110813352460308","answers":["hema-"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots appears in **hemophilia** (*disorder preventing blood from properly clotting*)? The choices are *hema-*, *homo-*, *homeo-*, and *hemi-*."},"GMDR001166":{"interactionID":"1339110826295951394","answers":["**-tic** meaning __pertaining to__ (and **diabetic** meaning __relating to diabetes__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **diabetic**."},"T001219":{"interactionID":"1339111567752429568","answers":["CHANGE BUT THE NAME, AND THE STORY IS TOLD OF YOURSELF"],"genus":"translation","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *mutato nomine de te fabula narratur*?"},"D000151":{"interactionID":"1339111890005135372","answers":["cavea"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *cage* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000183":{"interactionID":"1339111982749585458","answers":["coquo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *apricot* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000678":{"interactionID":"1339112061661085746","answers":["quattor"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *quire* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000367":{"interactionID":"1339112189050617906","answers":["iacio"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *jetty* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000592":{"interactionID":"1339112216670240852","answers":["pendo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *avoirdupois* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000659":{"interactionID":"1339112238832685118","answers":["pretium"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *prize* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"L1009364":{"interactionID":"1339112431280197704","answers":["afferes"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future active indicative** of *affero* (to bring to; to allege, assert)?"},"GMDR000021":{"interactionID":"1339417746227593318","answers":["shoulder"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What does the Greek medical root **om(o)-** mean?"},"L1006692":{"interactionID":"1339422438802456657","answers":["prime"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **masculine vocative singular** of *primus* (first)?"},"GMDR000066":{"interactionID":"1339470452526944266","answers":["peo- (meaning **of or pertaining to the penis**)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What Greek medical root comes from the Greek **πέος (péos)**?"},"GMDR000497":{"interactionID":"1339470503332806656","answers":["**col-** meaning __colon__","**-scope** meaning __instrument for or process of viewing__ (and **colonoscopy** meaning __examination of the colon__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **colonoscopy**."},"L1002990":{"interactionID":"1339471087947354134","answers":["matres"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **accusative plural** of *mater, matris* (mother)?"},"GMDR000148":{"interactionID":"1339617177313087498","answers":["ptero-, ptery- (meaning **pertaining to a wing","'pterygo-', wing-shaped**)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What Greek medical root comes from the Greek **πτερόν (pterón), wing, feather**?"},"GMDR000028":{"interactionID":"1339617196883836928","answers":["onych(o)-, onycho- (meaning **of or pertaining to the nail (of a finger or toe)**)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What Greek medical root comes from the Greek **ὄνυξ/ὀνυχο- (ónux/onukho-), nail; claw; talon**?"},"GMDR000318":{"interactionID":"1339617214138945568","answers":["py-"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Which of the following Greek medical roots implies **pus**? The choices are *py-*, *psych-*, *pseud-*, and *pyel-*."},"GMDR000829":{"interactionID":"1339617155615817819","answers":["**phaco-** meaning __lens-shaped__ (and **phacomalacia** meaning __softening of the lens of the eye__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **phacomalacia**."},"GMDR000918":{"interactionID":"1339621186866516018","answers":["**pne-** meaning __air, breath, lung__ (and **pneumoconiosis** meaning __lung disease caused by dust inhalation__)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"Define the medical root that appears in the term **pneumoconiosis**."},"P000093":{"interactionID":"1339659385156272230","answers":["(HORA SOMNI) AT BEDTIME"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin abbreviation *h.s.*?"},"GMDR000256":{"interactionID":"1339665980183543818","answers":["thyr(o)-, thyro- (meaning **thyroid**)"],"genus":"gmdr","question":"What Greek medical root comes from the Greek **θῠρεός (thureós), large oblong shield; + εἶδος (eîdos), a form or shape**?"},"P000127":{"interactionID":"1339723564844191765","answers":["(POST MERIDIEM) AFTER MIDDAY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the Latin phrase and English translation that correspond to the Latin abbreviation *P.M.*?"},"P000214":{"interactionID":"1340932092896215080","answers":["THE STORY IS FINISHED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Acta est fabula**."},"T000485":{"interactionID":"1341082702341996707","answers":["GOD WITH US"],"genus":"translation","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Deus nobiscum*?"},"P000023":{"interactionID":"1355298348646793409","answers":["PAX ET LUX (\"PEACE AND LIGHT\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Tufts University*?"},"L1020400":{"interactionID":"1342873274505232386","answers":["proficiemus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future active indicative** of *proficio* (to go on, to make progress)?"},"H000528":{"interactionID":"1342873881526014024","answers":["217 BC"],"genus":"history","question":"In what year did Hannibal entrap and defeat Flaminius at Lake Trasimene?"},"F000472":{"interactionID":"1348447040052531211","answers":["CELEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Callidice, Cleisidice, Demo & Callithoe?"},"F000730":{"interactionID":"1348935640980389910","answers":["TYDEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was attacked by 50 Thebans, and killed all but one?"},"H000562":{"interactionID":"1355145970089721997","answers":["CARTHAGO NOVA"],"genus":"history","question":"What city in Spain did Scipio Africanus capture in 209 BC?"},"H000466":{"interactionID":"1355145947193151539","answers":["PHOENICIA"],"genus":"history","question":"Where did the Carthaginians originate from?"},"H000468":{"interactionID":"1355146017414185170","answers":["AGRIGENTUM"],"genus":"history","question":"What Sicilian city did the Romans besiege in 262 BC?"},"H000254":{"interactionID":"1355146054978506892","answers":["TO RECOVER THEIR WIVES"],"genus":"history","question":"What did Titus Tatius lead a group of Sabines to Rome?"},"H000597":{"interactionID":"1355150451833831465","answers":["PYDNA"],"genus":"history","question":"At what battle in 168 BC did the Roman general Aemilius Paullus defeat Perseus of Macedon?"},"P000007":{"interactionID":"1355169467499282605","answers":["VOX CLAMANTIS IN DESERTO. (\"A VOICE OF ONE CRYING IN THE WILDERNESS.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Dartmouth College*?"},"P000000":{"interactionID":"1355579379308167342","answers":["TERRAS IRRADIENT. (\"LET THEM ILLUMINATE THE EARTH.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Amherst College*?"},"P000145":{"interactionID":"1355177121823199422","answers":["THERE IS NO ACCOUNTING FOR TASTE"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *De gustibus non est disputandum*?"},"P000079":{"interactionID":"1355297804981112913","answers":["ARS ARTIS GRATIA (\"ART FOR THE SAKE OF ART\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer*?"},"P000031":{"interactionID":"1355180146075762789","answers":["LITTERIS DEDICATA ET OMNIBUS ARTIBUS (\"DEDICATED TO LETTERS AND ALL THE ARTS\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Nebraska*?"},"P000230":{"interactionID":"1355180881131864136","answers":["THERE'S NO GREATER HONOR THAN TO DIE FOR ONE'S COUNTRY"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Dulce et decorum est pro patria mori**."},"P000019":{"interactionID":"1355296911342440448","answers":["DEI SUB NUMINE VIGET (\"IT FLOURISHES UNDER THE WILL OF GOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Princeton University*?"},"P000025":{"interactionID":"1355296900340908293","answers":["CRESCAT SCIENTIA, VITA EXCOLATUR (\"LET KNOWLEDGE INCREASE, LET LIFE BE PERFECTED\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of Chicago*?"},"P000216":{"interactionID":"1355296928509988904","answers":["I CAME, I SAW, I CONQUERED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Veni, vidi, vici**."},"P000024":{"interactionID":"1355580254881579230","answers":["CIVIUM IN MORIBUS REI PUBLIAE SALUS. (\"IN THE CHARACTER OF ITS CITIZENS LIES THE WELFARE OF THE STATE.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Univ. Florida*?"},"P000250":{"interactionID":"1355297545366016040","answers":["TIME, THE DEVOURER OF ALL THINGS"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Tempus edax rerum**."},"P000183":{"interactionID":"1355298551210578082","answers":["PERFECTION"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *Ne plus ultra*?"},"P000037":{"interactionID":"1355299220160253982","answers":["ECCE QUAM BONAM (\"BEHOLD HOW GOOD\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *University of the South (Sewanee)*?"},"P000081":{"interactionID":"1355299406232031242","answers":["DUM VIVIMUS VIVAMUS (\"WHILE WE LIVE LET US LIVE\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of the *Epicureans*?"},"D000593":{"interactionID":"1355302874099482865","answers":["pendo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *expend* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000345":{"interactionID":"1355361525191151696","answers":["genus"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *gent* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000600":{"interactionID":"1355361502927917168","answers":["penes"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *penetrate* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000256":{"interactionID":"1355361516660064455","answers":["duo"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *dual* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000799":{"interactionID":"1355361544409583666","answers":["tango"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *attain* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000567":{"interactionID":"1355387837830140116","answers":["par"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *pair* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"D000823":{"interactionID":"1355387813939515500","answers":["tono"],"genus":"derivative","question":"From what Latin root does the word *astound* derive from? (Give the first principal part.)"},"G000563":{"interactionID":"1355578135340646451","answers":["converto convertere converti conversum"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find all 4 principal parts of the verb that matches the definition *turn about, turn, change*. Do not include macrons."},"P000040":{"interactionID":"1355578788901163268","answers":["PRO HUMANITATE (\"FOR HUMANITY\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Wake Forest Univesity*?"},"P000021":{"interactionID":"1355580021015711784","answers":["PRO ECCLESIA ET PATRIA. (\"FOR CHURCH AND COUNTRY.\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Trinity College*?"},"L1021873":{"interactionID":"1355580848249766100","answers":["evenero"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *evenio* (to happen)?"},"L1017790":{"interactionID":"1355598541258621028","answers":["expleverimus"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *expleo* (to fill, complete)?"},"L1017859":{"interactionID":"1355598517565001848","answers":["evasero"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *evado* (to come out, escape)?"},"A000057":{"interactionID":"1355598798088569053","answers":["another... allos (αλλος)"],"genus":"greek_derivatives","question":"What is the meaning of the Greek root of the word **parallelogram**?"},"P000072":{"interactionID":"1355598961699717321","answers":["URBS IN HORTO (\"CITY IN A GARDEN\")"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What is the Latin motto of *Chicago*?"},"P000245":{"interactionID":"1355599023968489522","answers":["NERO"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"What famous Roman said **Qualis artifex pereo**?"},"P000222":{"interactionID":"1355599053135548659","answers":["CARTHAGE MUST BE DESTROYED"],"genus":"pmaq","question":"Translate **Delenda est Carthago**."},"G000156":{"interactionID":"1377005218469908480","answers":["V1"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the part of speech/Latin inflection category of the word *amo amare*.\n\nPlease use the following for your answer.\n**Adjective: 1st and 2nd Declension:** A12\n**Adjective: 3rd Declension:** A3\n**Adjective: Indeclinable:** AI\n**Adjective: Numeral:** AN\n**Adverb:** ADV\n**Conjunction:** CONJ\n**Noun: 1st Declension:** N1\n**Noun: 2nd Declension:** N2\n**Noun: 3rd Declension:** N3\n**Noun: 4th Declension:** N4\n**Noun: 5th Declension:** N5\n**Noun: Indeclinable:** NI\n**Preposition:** PREP\n**Pronoun:** PRO\n**Verb: 1st Conjugation:** V1\n**Verb: 2nd Conjugation:** V2\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -io:** V3i\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -o:** V3\n**Verb: 4th Conjugation:** V4\n**Verb: Deponent:** VD\n**Verb: Impersonal:** VIP\n**Verb: Irregular:** VIRR"},"G001333":{"interactionID":"1377005245971828837","answers":["journey, route"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *iter itineris n.*."},"G002548":{"interactionID":"1377005283695657073","answers":["aspect, appearance"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the definition of the word *species speciei f.*."},"G000858":{"interactionID":"1377005312405668034","answers":["N3"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the part of speech/Latin inflection category of the word *error erroris m.*.\n\nPlease use the following for your answer.\n**Adjective: 1st and 2nd Declension:** A12\n**Adjective: 3rd Declension:** A3\n**Adjective: Indeclinable:** AI\n**Adjective: Numeral:** AN\n**Adverb:** ADV\n**Conjunction:** CONJ\n**Noun: 1st Declension:** N1\n**Noun: 2nd Declension:** N2\n**Noun: 3rd Declension:** N3\n**Noun: 4th Declension:** N4\n**Noun: 5th Declension:** N5\n**Noun: Indeclinable:** NI\n**Preposition:** PREP\n**Pronoun:** PRO\n**Verb: 1st Conjugation:** V1\n**Verb: 2nd Conjugation:** V2\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -io:** V3i\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -o:** V3\n**Verb: 4th Conjugation:** V4\n**Verb: Deponent:** VD\n**Verb: Impersonal:** VIP\n**Verb: Irregular:** VIRR"},"G002808":{"interactionID":"1377005501795139604","answers":["CONJ"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find the part of speech/Latin inflection category of the word *vel*.\n\nPlease use the following for your answer.\n**Adjective: 1st and 2nd Declension:** A12\n**Adjective: 3rd Declension:** A3\n**Adjective: Indeclinable:** AI\n**Adjective: Numeral:** AN\n**Adverb:** ADV\n**Conjunction:** CONJ\n**Noun: 1st Declension:** N1\n**Noun: 2nd Declension:** N2\n**Noun: 3rd Declension:** N3\n**Noun: 4th Declension:** N4\n**Noun: 5th Declension:** N5\n**Noun: Indeclinable:** NI\n**Preposition:** PREP\n**Pronoun:** PRO\n**Verb: 1st Conjugation:** V1\n**Verb: 2nd Conjugation:** V2\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -io:** V3i\n**Verb: 3rd Conjugation -o:** V3\n**Verb: 4th Conjugation:** V4\n**Verb: Deponent:** VD\n**Verb: Impersonal:** VIP\n**Verb: Irregular:** VIRR"},"G002177":{"interactionID":"1377005772084478143","answers":["quamquam"],"genus":"grammar","question":"Find all 1 principal parts of the conjunction that matches the definition *however, although*. Do not include macrons."},"L2019733":{"interactionID":"1377306593166889121","answers":["laceraverimus"],"genus":"L2_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person plural perfect active subjunctive** of *lacero* (to tear to pieces, to lacerate)?"},"L2036062":{"interactionID":"1377306525353377844","answers":["restitui"],"genus":"L2_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular perfect active indicative** of *restituo* (to give back, restore)?"},"L2078670":{"interactionID":"1377306553056493638","answers":["eductus est"],"genus":"L2_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular perfect passive indicative** of *educo* (to lead forth, bring away)?"},"L2060749":{"interactionID":"1377308226030145536","answers":["inveniebam"],"genus":"L2_inflection","question":"What is the **first-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *invenio* (to find)?"},"L2085092":{"interactionID":"1377308390010786015","answers":["expertum"],"genus":"L2_inflection","question":"What is the **nominative singular neuter perfect participle** of *experior* (to try, to prove; to experience)?"},"L2073615":{"interactionID":"1377310989376295044","answers":["statutum"],"genus":"L2_inflection","question":"What is the **vocative singular neuter perfect participle** of *statuo* (to set up, establish; to decide)?"},"L2061570":{"interactionID":"1377345594296631479","answers":["conveniebat"],"genus":"L2_inflection","question":"What is the **third-person singular imperfect active indicative** of *convenio* (to come or meet together; to agree)?"},"L2063241":{"interactionID":"1377345654690414612","answers":["esus eras"],"genus":"L2_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular pluperfect passive indicative** of *edo* (to eat)?"},"F000300":{"interactionID":"1377349566848045056","answers":["SCORPION"],"genus":"myth","question":"What creature does Artemis create to defend herself from Orion?"},"L1013180":{"interactionID":"1379349941436153877","answers":["silueris"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person singular future perfect active indicative** of *sileo* (to keep silent, to be quiet)?"},"PW000062":{"interactionID":"1383304795401617469","answers":["PLAGUE"],"genus":"pw","question":"What event in 430 BC significantly weakened the Athenian military?"},"PW000069":{"interactionID":"1383304957834297364","answers":["ATHENIAN VICTORY AND CAPTURE OF SPARTAN SOLDIERS"],"genus":"pw","question":"What was the significance of the Battle of Pylos?"},"PW000108":{"interactionID":"1383305061974933555","answers":["CYRUS THE YOUNGER"],"genus":"pw","question":"What Persian prince played a significant role in supporting Sparta?"},"PW000043":{"interactionID":"1383305079624568862","answers":["ALCIBIADES"],"genus":"pw","question":"What Athenian general, despite his earlier defection to Sparta, was not re-elected after the Spartan victory at Notium in 406 BC?"},"PW000143":{"interactionID":"1383305088885329931","answers":["THE DECELEAN WAR"],"genus":"pw","question":"What term refers to the final phase of the Second Peloponnesian War?"},"PW000131":{"interactionID":"1383305097685110824","answers":["AMPHIPOLIS"],"genus":"pw","question":"What Athenian colony in Thrace was captured by the Spartan general Brasidas?"},"PW000102":{"interactionID":"1383305126894239864","answers":["RELIGIOUS STATUES WHOSE MUTILATION WAS A BAD OMEN"],"genus":"pw","question":"What were the hermai, and why were they significant?"},"PW000048":{"interactionID":"1383305139452117104","answers":["REGAIN IONIAN CONTROL AND WEAKEN ATHENS"],"genus":"pw","question":"What was the primary motivation of the Persians in supporting Sparta?"},"PW000109":{"interactionID":"1383305161337995284","answers":["SPARTAN VICTORY LEADING TO ALCIBIADES' DOWNFALL"],"genus":"pw","question":"What was the Battle of Notium?"},"PW000077":{"interactionID":"1383305170783440946","answers":["CHARISMATIC ATHENIAN GENERAL WHO SWITCHED SIDES"],"genus":"pw","question":"Who was Alcibiades?"},"LADV013532":{"interactionID":"1383312738448572516","answers":["vigilaveritis"],"genus":"LADV_inflection","question":"What is the **second-person plural future perfect active indicative** of *vigilo* (to be awake)?"},"H000986":{"interactionID":"1383312799836541018","answers":["AGRIPPINA THE YOUNGER"],"genus":"history","question":"Who reportedly served Claudius a bowl of poisoned mushrooms?"},"H001192":{"interactionID":"1383312933886628050","answers":["GOTHS"],"genus":"history","question":"What group did Gallienus and Claudius Gothicus defeat at Naissus?"},"H000970":{"interactionID":"1383313289580384266","answers":["41–54 AD"],"genus":"history","question":"What were the years of Claudius' reign?"},"H000820":{"interactionID":"1383313350242467890","answers":["VETOED A LAND REFORM BILL"],"genus":"history","question":"How did Bibulus get on Caesar's bad side?"},"H001127":{"interactionID":"1383313534750035968","answers":["PERTINAX"],"genus":"history","question":"Which emperor succeeded Commodus and ruled briefly in 193 AD?"},"T001929":{"interactionID":"1383313906122100847","answers":["MAY IT BE WORTHY OF THE NAME"],"genus":"translation","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *sit nomine digna*?"},"T002044":{"interactionID":"1383313921737359422","answers":["SPRING TIME"],"genus":"translation","question":"Give the English translation for the following Latin phrase *tempus vernum*?"},"F001823":{"interactionID":"1383315258268975185","answers":["POSEIDON"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the father of Euphemus?"},"F002039":{"interactionID":"1383315414209007678","answers":["IPHICLUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What son of Phylacus suffered from impotence?"},"F000493":{"interactionID":"1383315518752030730","answers":["HIEROPHANT"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the chief priest of the Eleusinian Mysteries?"},"F001627":{"interactionID":"1383316910086819850","answers":["SCYTHES"],"genus":"myth","question":"Which of the sons of Heracles and Echidna was able to string Heracles' bow?"},"F001681":{"interactionID":"1383317366179495987","answers":["MYSIANS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Of what people was Telephus king?"},"F001988":{"interactionID":"1383318820264869968","answers":["CALYDONIAN BOAR"],"genus":"myth","question":"On what hunt did Peleus accompany Euytion?"},"F000659":{"interactionID":"1383318874941820968","answers":["ANTIOPE"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the sister of Nycteis?"},"F000901":{"interactionID":"1383319011550560337","answers":["IDAS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Which of the Apharidae was killed by Zeus' thunderbolt?"},"F000856":{"interactionID":"1383320463144390746","answers":["ATHENIAN CITIZENS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who are the jury of the Areopagus?"},"F001527":{"interactionID":"1383637223647477834","answers":["TIRYNS"],"genus":"myth","question":"What city was the kingdom of Eurystheus?"},"F000619":{"interactionID":"1383674103323557918","answers":["BULL"],"genus":"myth","question":"In what disguise did Zeus abduct Europa?"},"H000264":{"interactionID":"1383981551334850590","answers":["TITUS TATIUS"],"genus":"history","question":"With whom did Romulus co-rule in order to appease the Sabines?"},"H000874":{"interactionID":"1383981644481826856","answers":["LEX TITIA"],"genus":"history","question":"What of 43 BC legallized the Second Triumvirate for 5 years?"},"F000780":{"interactionID":"1383993594423021568","answers":["TIRESIAS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who foretold the end of Odysseus' wanderings and the manner of his death?"},"F001329":{"interactionID":"1383993548621217842","answers":["ARETE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What queen of the Phaeacians was the wife of Alcinous and mother of Nausicaa?"},"F002237":{"interactionID":"1383993571396292721","answers":["POSEIDON"],"genus":"myth","question":"Which Greek Olympian was called the \"Earthshaker\" because he was responsible for earthquakes?"},"F000038":{"interactionID":"1383997595000635463","answers":["CYDIPPE"],"genus":"myth","question":"What priestess of Hera was the mother of Cleobis and Biton?"},"F000440":{"interactionID":"1384002180671078451","answers":["ZEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"To whom did Hermes and Apollo take their cattle dispute?"},"H000342":{"interactionID":"1385431050939011092","answers":["PONS SUBLICIUS"],"genus":"history","question":"What bridge did Horatius Cocles single-handedly defend from the assault of Lars Porsenna?"},"F000585":{"interactionID":"1385694388168167455","answers":["THE FROGS"],"genus":"myth","question":"In what play does Aristophanes write 'brekekekex koax koax'?"},"F002250":{"interactionID":"1385694355645399121","answers":["HEPHAESTUS (NOT VULCAN)"],"genus":"myth","question":"According to Homer, which god created a new shield for Achilles?"},"F002251":{"interactionID":"1387538832567828480","answers":["ATHENA"],"genus":"myth","question":"What Greek goddess of wisdom was born from Zeus' head?"},"H001254":{"interactionID":"1387539657910124544","answers":["324 AD"],"genus":"history","question":"In what year did Constantine defeat Licinius at Chrysopolis?"},"H000074":{"interactionID":"1387542562763706389","answers":["BIBULUS"],"genus":"history","question":"The year 59 BC was jokingly referred to as the year of Gaius and Caesar because of the lack of influence of what co-consular colleague of Caesar?"},"L1005959":{"interactionID":"1388930687528075456","answers":["horrida"],"genus":"L1_inflection","question":"What is the **neuter accusative plural** of *horridus* (rough, terrible)?"},"H001179":{"interactionID":"1389108322656845965","answers":["CHRISTIANS"],"genus":"history","question":"What group was Decius the first emperor to systematically persecute throughout the empire?"},"F000536":{"interactionID":"1389110387974082611","answers":["AVERNUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Where does Aeneas enter the underworld?"},"F000767":{"interactionID":"1389462885016801332","answers":["PHEGEUS"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who was the king of Arcadia whose daughter married Alcmaeon?"},"F000913":{"interactionID":"1389462839751868416","answers":["PRIAM AND HECUBA"],"genus":"myth","question":"Who were the parents of Paris?"},"H000216":{"interactionID":"1389829192727658509","answers":["ALBA LONGA"],"genus":"history","question":"What city did Iulus establish near the future site of Rome?"},"H000916":{"interactionID":"1389829239729164288","answers":["AUGUSTUS"],"genus":"history","question":"Which emperor reportedly said \"I found Rome a city of brick, and left it a city of marble\"?"},"H000416":{"interactionID":"1390531619751727114","answers":["SECOND SAMNITE WAR"],"genus":"history","question":"What war was fought over a disputue at Neapolis from 327–303 BC?"}}}}